Ebata Family Grave
Darn it all!
Well, let's get started already.
Masanori, I'm gonna make you...
Okay! The Daybreak vs. Blackout
Nagoya Castle Showdown reaches its fourth battle!
Having won twice in a row,
Blackout advances to the third floor!
Here to meet them:
the secret brains of Daybreak!
It's the corpse-controlling
King of the Dead, Masanori Iseki!
Hi there!
And opposing him is...
Blackout's protector deity!
The flawless guardian
who brings everyone together!
Dear little...
Tomari Seto!
It's showtime!
Aurora Fierce Princess
Right and Wrong
Tomari?
Aurora Fierce Princess
Right and Wrong
Would you rather exhaust
your resources at this point?
Aurora Fierce Princess
Right and Wrong
Would you rather exhaust
your resources at this point?
When you play through a serious fight,
you end up dog-tired, don't you?
Which opponent do you most want revenge on?
And besides, I'd like to give him
a liiiittle direct punishment.
Being boorish again?
"Boar"-ish?!
Well, you're all gonna get bowled over by me,
so it doesn't matter who's first.
I'm "all boar"?!
Can we wind this up super-quick?
Wind up as a super boar?!
Uh, your insult interpretation's
getting kinda strained there.
Oh, shut up!
I'll be the one to destroy the embodiment of evil!
You never left much of an impression
on me from the start, though.
Are you strong, Tomari?
I'm hecka strong!
And I can eat a hecka heap of ramen!
No one asked!
If Tomari's involved, there's no need to worry.
Zakusa?! When did you get here?!
And hang on, where have you been all this time?!
Didn't I tell you before that I'm infiltrating
Daybreak on a request from a certain person?
I've been sleuthing around, on Tomari's orders...
...to find out just who's pulling the strings
behind the chain of disputes.
He is entirely the ringleader.
The banner burning, and team wrecking...
...was started at Daybreak by that man.
Oh, and not just at Daybreak.
Haven't you done this plenty of other times?
What's your aim in doing so, anyway?
That's awfully harsh,
describing me as the "ringleader."
All I did was tell them how to do it.
Basically, I'm like... Prometheus?
And unless we threaten to do something
like banner-burning, nobody'd get serious, yeah?
Without something major at stake...
...people won't get desperate.
Down, down, in the ocean depths
where light does not reach, the abyss.
There, in the mire at the very bottom,
is the exact sparkle I wish to see.
For the sake of such a self-centered desire...
...you made our children cry,
and now I'll make sure you regret it!
Huh...
I'm gonna bowl you over on Zakusa's behalf, too.
Now, shall we begin?!
Stand up, Vanguard!
I ride! Rancor Chain's skill activates!
Nice! This is gonna be fun!
My turn! I ride Kyanite Blue!
I'm being serious here...
...so you'd better play for real, or you'll lose!
I set Galactolus.
Only, once you're playing for real, I'm gonna win.
So you say.
My turn is over!
I ride! I call Hendrina!
With its skill, I discard three cards
from the top of my deck.
The thing about me...
All I want to see is when someone...
...has sunk to the very bottom...
...revealing their true self.
Only that?
With "only that" as my reason for fighting,
no person has been able to stop me thus far.
Now!
Just try to deny my existence,
and my way of being!
Shut your mouth. You'll bite your tongue.
My turn!
I ride Risatt Pink! Its skill activates!
I imprison one card from my opponent's hand!
Furthermore, with Chevalstud's skill,
I imprison Hendrina!
Huh...
Welcome to Galaxy Central Prison...
I call Perio Turquoise! Attack!
I guard.
With no air, and no warmth,
it's a fun, fun theme park.
While in your cell, you'd better repent!
I attack!
My turn is over.
Perio Turquoise weakens cards
that have left prison.
That's fighting dirty, isn't it?
Are you really one to talk?
You sure do get me!
I ride Mysterious Rain Spiritualist, Zorga.
Soul Blast!
People try to lock away their true nature
inside a jail cell called "rationality."
However!
I call my imprisoned Hendrina.
With its skill, I discard three cards
from the top of my deck.
Oh, dear. That went poorly.
Didn't get the card you'd hoped for?
Well, it's fine.
To use its other skill, I retire Hendrina.
That removes the need to pay
a Soul Blast cost for an Alchemagic.
That's quite an interesting unit.
It gets even more interesting!
I use Cursed Souls!
And stir in the Spiritual Body Condensation
from my Drop, using Alchemagic!
Alchemagic... allows you to use
powerful Order effects in combination?
Exactly! Here I go!
With Cursed Soul's effect, I call two cards!
And with Spiritual Body Condensation's effect,
I call from the Drop!
The skill of the Roaming Prison Dragon
in my Drop
allows it to be called after using an Order!
And there's more! Since I used Alchemagic,
it gets +10,000 power and an extra critical!
Wha?!
And there's more! Since I used Alchemagic,
it gets +10,000 power and an extra critical!
Furthermore, with Zorga's skill,
I call from the Drop!
Wha-wha-wha?!
Ahh... so beautiful...
You've filled your entire field
while hardly using your hand?!
This deck is unbound
by even the concept of death.
I attack!
No guard!
Twin drive!
Critical!
You've got good luck.
I guess even someone like you
hasn't been deserted by God?
Is luck, whether good or bad,
something one should rely on?
I have no belief in luck, much less God.
And even if God did exist...
...wouldn't God's favorite be a kid like Yu-yu?
Because he's a good and honest kid?
Because he's locked himself up in a teeny cell.
Tohya's the opposite: unstable.
A wild child who can't
remain obediently inside a cell.
Don't tell me you sent Tohya after Blackout!
You need a spark to ignite something, right?
Whether it's a banner... or a soul...
I attack!
I guard!
I guard and intercept!
My turn is over.
I knew something must be done about you,
or else these battles will never end.
All right! My fighting spirit's replenished!
Yeah! It really is boring
unless I'm enjoying myself!
Coming up next:
Tomari's Great Criminal Investigation!
The curtain will rise on a lovely arrest drama!
Excellent, excellent!
Thanks to your willy-nilly calls,
the field's full of perps!
Time to flex my skills!
I ride Aurora Battle Princess, Seraph Snow!
Its skill activates! I imprison two rear-guards!
I call Agra Luge!
With its skill, I imprison a rear-guard!
I call another Agra Luge!
And with Chevalstud's skill!
I send the last one...
...to prison!
Your rear-guards have all
been tossed in the slammer!
How lenient of you!
Well, however many petty underlings
you nab, it means nothing.
You have to take out the boss
of the evil organization, y'know!
Thanks for the advice!
My seriousness is at 100%!
And Seraph Snow's in tip-top shape!
This way, it can even achieve a triple drive!
Furthermore!
I call Suppress Gleamer! Its skill activates!
When there are at least three imprisoned,
I can call one more Suppress Gleamer!
Now my seriousness is at 200%!
Not bad.
Here I come!
Bring it on!
Seraph Snow attacks!
No guard!
Triple drive!
You assume a lack of jail cells
means freedom, do you?
Glorifying freedom for selfish reasons
is just displaying selfishness.
Robbing other people of their freedom...
is the one freedom nobody would allow.
Draw trigger!
Your rational argument's boring!
I attack!
I guard!
No guard!
Mmm... yeah, you're way stronger than I assumed.
But you know, however many times
I get tossed in a cell,
I'm gonna keep surging my way out
again and again, got it?
Then I'll keep tossing you back in
however many times it takes.
I'll follow you to the ends of the Earth.
This won't end until one of us is dead, huh?
She's engaging him seriously,
trying to comprehend him.
Tomari's always like that.
But this time... he is...
...he of all people is...
Dear me?
Shouldn't we be hearing it right about now?
The melody... of death.
My turn. Persona ride!
With Zorga's skill,
I call Hendrina from the Drop.
With its skill, I discard three cards
from the top of my deck.
Aww, I didn't get it?!
How could you do this to me?!
I dig this deep into the deck,
yet you're not there?
Grief, Despair, and Rejection.
You sure did get rejected!
It won't go the way you're expecting.
That's what makes it fun, though.
An excuse for being out of luck?
I told you before,
talking about stuff like luck or fate...
...is insolent.
Besides, while Grief and Despair
haven't bothered to show up,
neither will that one.
By retiring Hendrina, I remove
the Soul Blast while using Alchemagic.
Now, the world... will turn inside out!
I use Ye Wandering Souls!
And stir in the Spiritual Body Condensation
from my Drop...
...using Alchemagic!
Zorga gets an extra drive,
and calls Rancor Chain from the Drop.
With the skill of the two
Roaming Prison Dragons in my Drop,
they get called from Drop after I use an Order.
Plus, if I use Alchemagic,
they get +10,000 power and an extra critical!
Counterblast.
I call the two imprisoned Sea Breeze Abductions.
This is... getting...
You finally hear it, don't you?
The melody of death.
Now's when the real nightmare begins.
Zorga attacks.
I guard and intercept!
Now we start chipping away at each other's life.
Well, aren't you having fun?
At this moment, with this stinging, I am now...
...fully alive!
Triple drive!
Yes, fill it up! Fill up...
...my sake cup!
At this late hour!
All that pours out is hell's resentment...
Swallowing up both the dead and the living...
The world of the living becomes
pandemonium's haunts of wicked men.
Wha?!
Over Trigger!
My Vanguard gets +100,000,000 power,
and an extra critical!
The attack...
...goes through...
Additionally, my front row gets +10,000 power,
I draw one card, and heal one damage.
The monstrous rain becomes a storm,
mowing down everything in its path!
As thanks for throwing me into prison,
I'll give you these words:
"Welcome to Hell!"
Would you look at that, she survived it.
Work harder, please!
I attack!
I guard!
Yes, that's it!
You've still got life to spare, right?
Then we can keep playing!
I attack!
Perfect guard!
You really are quite good at this, Tomari!
You bore up through all that!
However!
Hasn't the process left you rather discouraged?
My turn is over.
Now, then...
In the face of absolute defeat,
how will you make a reversal?
If you've got something to show,
then by all means, show it!
Knock through anything and everything!
Knock through the "what lies beyond"
that I don't know about!
There are no absolutes!
There's always a chance at a reversal.
That's how Cardfights are!
At this point, what do you have left, Tomari?
I still have the intention of winning!
What are you trying to do now?!
Just shut up and watch!
I am Tomari Seto.
The coolest woman in the galaxy!
Stand and draw!
I ride Aurora Fierce Princess, Seraph Purelight!
Grade 4?!
You had... a secret ace?!
Now, the great round-up begins!
With Seraph Purelight's skill,
I imprison two apiece
from your hand, your Soul, and your rear-guards!
That many?!
And with Chevalstud's skill, I imprison
one rear-guard, and draw one card!
I call Lourus Yellow and Treuse Green!
You're sending out triggers?!
Now that's desperation!
Didn't I tell you?! I've been serious
about this from the beginning!
Seraph Purelight's skill!
For every two cards imprisoned,
the front row units get +5000 power!
Since there are eleven imprisoned,
that's +25,000 power!
Also, because there are at least ten imprisoned,
the front row units get an extra critical!
What? That's entertaining!
By knowing your opponent,
you won't give in to your hatred.
Bring even more on!
Is that all you've got in reserve?
Again, don't expect me to forgive you!
Please, let me experience
what lies beyond an earnest battle!
Going all-out!
This is Tomari Seto's spirit!
Seraph Purelight attacks!
No guard!
Triple drive!
First check!
That's not enough to hit!
I'm not done yet!
Second check!
That fist doesn't look like it's moving!
Third check!
Front trigger!
Wha?!
My front row units get +10,000 power!
That still won't defeat me!
Lourus Yellow...
...attacks your Vanguard!
A victory by the skin of my teeth!
Yeah!
The iron hammer of justice
on the depraved monk!
You have lost!
Because I've succeeded in
slightly comprehending the person you are,
I'll take the liberty of saying this once again.
I refuse to forgive a jerk like you.
I'll stop you over and over again,
however many times it takes.
No, not just me.
There'll always be someone there
to stand in your way.
And then, they'll defeat you!
Uh... I feel kinda...
Thanks for your hard work, Tomari.
Let me handle the rest here.
You guys hurry on ahead.
Yeah! Take good care of Tomari!
Please do, Zakusa!
What was it... you wanted to say to me?
That... doesn't matter anymore.
Next is Danji, huh?
Yeah.
He's good.
He's strong, fighting with everything on the line.
I was concerned when he started
the whole "kind older brother" thing...
...but now, he's safely become
the monster he used to be.
I...
...no...
...I'll be going now.
People say...
...that holding out an umbrella is kindness.
Don't they?
But Tohya...
...in your case...
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
Hey, listen!
A Piece of Soul
All you ladies and gentlemen, who youth it up
with cards, and make life-or-death pacts with 'em,
A Piece of Soul
it's time to party!
This time, you get an introduction to
Aurora Fierce Princess, Seraph Purelight!
A Piece of Soul
When you ride it, you arrest two cards each
from the opponent's hand, rear-guard, and Soul!
That's not all! For every two cards imprisoned,
your front row units get +5000 power,
and they also get an extra critical
if there are at least ten!
A Piece of Soul
and they also get an extra critical
if there are at least ten!
The power of power! Amazing!
A Piece of Soul
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Bastion vs Bruce
Resolve