Bro... joined Daybreak?
Miss Mirei!
That must have been frightening.
I'm fine.
I have canceled tomorrow's prayer visit.
We can spend the day relaxing, yes?
Stop it.
I fully understand that you are suffering.
You have done nothing wrong, Miss Mirei.
Those in the wrong are
the malicious outsiders who--
Stop it!
I understand. You are feeling on edge, yes?
At a time such as this,
the best thing to do is rest.
Miss Mirei...
Your Name
Reminiscence
It is time for afternoon tea.
How long do you intend to sit in that manner?
It's hot.
Drink your tea and calm down,
and forget all that happened yesterday.
There. Is that not a lovely fragrance?
You fully understand now, do you not?
That the outside world is unkind.
The world is full of bad people.
If you stay here, by my side, all will be well.
Miss Mirei...
You should drink the tea while it is still warm.
Go on...
I'm sorry.
Tomorrow, we will bring in a new driver.
Someone reliable, who will not unsettle
your emotions in the way Mr. Momoyama does.
But why?!
Mr. Danji hasn't done anything!
Please do not refer to a servant
in such an overly-familiar manner.
He's no ordinary servant.
He has taken me to all sorts of places,
and told me about many things I never knew!
He means everything to me, so why?!
Miss Mirei, you are demonstrating
special feelings for that man.
But you heard which team
his friends belong to, did you not?
Please compose yourself, Miss Mirei.
You do realize that there are many bad teams
who ridicule and exclude vulnerable people?
The longer they exist,
the more people will have to weep.
They made you suffer as well,
did they not, Miss Mirei?
Mr. Momoyama came here to reform his life
after having lead that team, Blackout.
He is currently unworthy of trust.
But Mr. Danji isn't like the others.
He stuck up for me.
He protected me!
Shall we rest a little longer?
Listen to what I'm saying!
Clearly, you are still on edge.
As it appears that you are still
unable to speak calmly, Miss Mirei,
I will prepare something else for you to drink.
Is there anything that you would like?
Moo-Moo Hida Dairy Parfait.
You know I asked about a drink...
What will you do about this?
Sorry, I'd meant for us to leave sooner,
but I had trouble getting us away.
Why do you never change?
Like I said, you're half-hearted.
By trying to be a little kind to everyone,
you maintain a lack of responsibility.
You won't make clear distinctions.
You claim you'll quit, but don't.
And you don't do what you said you would!
Realize what matters. Be an adult, for once!
If you can't manage that,
don't do anything uncalled-for!
Mr. Danji...
Where would you like to go, miss?
I am fine.
Stop laughing...
They are guests staying at this hotel.
Shall I have them return to their room?
I told you, I'm fine!
But...
I'm fine!
I'm looking for somebody!
Mr. Danji!
Mr. Danji! Mr. Danji!
Mirei!
Mr. Danji...?
Is she with you?
Yes. I'm very sorry.
Mr. ... Danji...
I hate...
I hate people like you...
...who go away without a word!
Hey...
I know they won't be there.
Where are we going?
The front gate.
Why?
Aren't you on the verge of tears?
It's more fun with more than just two.
They knew that I was with Daybreak, didn't they?
Of course they won't show up.
Still... they made a promise, yesterday.
C'mon, let's go, already.
Just a little longer.
What's wrong with just the two of us?
If they're not there, then two is enough.
We'll just go where we go.
They definitely won't show up.
You don't know that.
So you believe in them.
Say...
...Danji...
I'm dropping the "Mr." part.
Yeah.
Danji, can I make just one request?
Walk more slowly.
Sure.
It's so noisy.
I can hear everything.
Ahh, I just can't handle things today.
I mentioned before that
I had a big brother, right?
Yeah.
When I was little, he'd put
a good-luck charm on my ears.
You see...
...at one point, I moved to Sendai.
My big brother told me...
...that there was a big festival
near the new house we'd be living in.
But Mommy said I couldn't go,
because it was dangerous.
However, my big brother snuck me out, see?
I was so happy, going to my first festival
with a bunch of pocket money.
But you know what?
The shrine we arrived at
was the wrong place entirely!
I could just barely hear the festival music.
The venue was probably close by.
But ultimately, we didn't know where it was.
My purse was heavy with coins,
and I could only barely hear the festival music,
which all left me feeling
incredibly miserable, somehow.
But when my big brother covered my ears,
the agonizing noises all went away.
Even now, I remember that light roar,
a sound belonging only to him.
Anytime I felt unhappy,
his good-luck charm would drown it out!
Know what I heard from Haruka?
She'd told me that my big brother died.
This was while I was in grade school.
I heard.
It was an accident, she said.
I want you to tell her this:
Mirei was able to make it to her first festival.
Moreover... with the person most precious to her.
I knew they'd show up.
I'm sorry...
...that I left you all startled yesterday,
with no explanation.
You must have your reasons.
All right.
You're not going to ask?
What's the sense in asking?
Today is a festival day.
I once read somewhere that festivals are for
forgetting the pain and suffering of daily life.
A day just for laughing and dancing.
So for today, it shouldn't matter
whether we're enemies or allies.
Though I'm not sure if what I read was true...
It's nice to meet you.
Do you mind us visiting the festival with you?
Are you sure?
Of course!
And Tohya said he'd treat us to candied apples!
Why'd you say that?!
Buttered Potatoes  -  Yo-Yos
Chicken Skewers - Stir Fry Noodles
Pancake Fish - Baby Cakes
So, uh... are you hungry?
Is there anything that sounds good to you?
I'm fine. Go join the others.
Oh, no, it's all right.
Would you mind if I joined you
in getting something to eat?
Uh... I'll read out the names of
the food stalls as we pass.
Stir fry noodles, candied apples...
So, how's work, lately?
I've gotten used to it.
How are the old-timers
at the construction site doing?
Tamura's been bedridden
ever since his back seized up.
What, it happened again?
Hey, Bro! Get me that bear!
You're not a kid, you know.
But you gave a bear to Yu-yu!
Oof. When you put it that way,
it's hard to say no.
They're having fun.
It was always like that at Blackout, too.
With Danji around, everyone's always laughing.
You could say that Danji's presence
is what brought everyone to Blackout.
Of course, it's still fun there now.
Is that why you're being malicious?
Don't exclude me.
Um, we didn't mean to...
Are you all right?!
I'm fine.
It's awfully crowded here.
Uh, Miss Mirei!
I told you, I'm fine.
Miss Mirei...
Miss Mirei, you can't go walking off by yourself--
If so, then give him back!
Give Danji back!
Miss Mirei!
Mirei!
Stop laughing!
In the end...
...I'm...
Big... Brother...?
How did you...?
What do you mean?
What are you saying, Danji?
Does everyone except me know?
Nobody in the Minae family knows.
Only Haruka knows about it.
That's a lie!
It's not a lie!
Everyone knows!
You've come waltzing back, intent on
taking the Minae family away from me!
That's not why!
That's not why...
Then why did you come back?!
After all I've suffered in your place,
as the successor to the Minae family!
Having to be the good girl,
enduring the adults who ignore me!
It was all because you were dead, and yet!
And yet, it was all a lie?!
Ultimately, you ran away from me!
Didn't you?!
You thought you could just keep on lying to me!
And in the end, I'm all alone! Utterly alone!
I hate this! I hate this, I hate this!
Enough! Let me go!
I have nothing!
No great past like yours, no fun memories,
no place where I belong,
no people I can believe in, nothing!
It was all a lie!
I can't believe anyone!
Please believe me!
Let me go!
I won't let you go again!
I'll always be by your side!
I won't lie to you ever again!
I'll never betray you!
I can't believe you!
Please believe me!
Please believe me! Please!
Please... believe... me...
Let me go.
I won't let you go.
Never ever?
Yeah.
Even if it kills you?
Yeah!
Then, never let me go...
...even if it kills you.
And throw away everything
belonging to Danji Momoyama.
Blackout... friends... teammates...
Danji has an awful lot, doesn't he?
Throw it all away.
And choose me.
Nadatsugu, my brother...
Miss Mirei!
Bro!
Stop calling him that.
He's my brother.
Your... brother?
Danji is Miss Mirei's... older brother?
His name isn't Danji.
My brother was lying to you all along.
Lying, and playing at being a "big bro".
My brother's real name... is Nadatsugu Minae.
And because I am Arthur, I must be decisive.
First, I will state my name.
I am Mirei Minae, from Daybreak.
What is your name?
Answer me.
I am Yu-yu Kondo, from Blackout.
I am going to... destroy you, and Blackout.
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
I'm Danji!
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'm gonna introduce
my deck's awesome card, Diabolos Striker, Lyle!
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'm gonna introduce
my deck's awesome card, Diabolos Striker, Lyle!
First and most importantly,
you've gotta check out its flavor text!
"I won't let anyone stop this strike of mine--!"
Whoa, burning hot!
This dude's totally intense!
Huh?
What's its crucial skill?
Well, of course it's a cool and hot skill
that brings across Lyle's relentless manliness!
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Megumi vs Haruka
Recollection