Yu-yu!
Your father says he's coming home!
Really? Is it that time of year already?
Jeez! You've sure been cold-hearted lately!
Anyway, you need to stay home this Saturday!
Sure, got it.
I'll be back later!
Hey! You all right?!
Hey, you!
I have to... protect the banner...
For now, come inside!
Fluttering Banner
Tomari!
There was nobody suspicious!
Keep constantly on guard!
Yes, ma'am!
There's a team hunter around.
Huh? A team hunter?
Um, Shinobu, your team, Blue Monday,
hailed from near Komatsu, didn't it?
Yeah.
People from an unknown team
suddenly approached our gathering spot.
They told us to choose: either
submit to them, or fight with them.
And if you lost the fight?
They said they'd... burn the team banner.
It's not unusual for us
to get challengers, though.
But...
...that opponent was really strong...
...and our leader was no match for them.
But, I thought I should
at least protect our banner,
so I took it and ran.
I understand.
You had it rough, huh?
Yeah.
Thank you.
It's finished.
Yes! Their sleeves had that design on them.
Lemme see.
What's wrong?
Uh... you're sure good at drawing!
You never noticed before?
I guess not!
And you'd never seen that design before?
Uh uh.
Other teams are also talking about
there having been a team hunt.
And one of the hunted teams
did get their banner taken and burnt.
Don't worry.
Hmm.
Now they're talking about having a meeting of
team leaders to discuss countermeasures.
Your punk info network?
I just heard it from an old friend.
It's this weekend, Danji.
Yeah, I'd better go to that.
An "old friend," huh?
From once upon a time.
"Once upon a time," huh?
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
That doesn't have the electricity
turned on right now.
I'm sorry I forced my way in here.
What are you talking about?
Anybody's welcome here.
And with Bro here, we'll be
just fine against some team hunt!
You're worried about your teammates, aren't you?
Oh, sorry.
They wouldn't be just fine...
Please look at this. It's our team banner.
We were proud of it.
We put our all into coming up with it...
...and on the weekends, of course we met up.
Danji seems strong.
You see? He's crazy strong!
Though he's not fighting lately.
Huh... you're lucky.
If our leader had been strong, too,
this wouldn't have happened.
If only I'd been strong enough to protect it!
Say, wanna stay here until things calm down?
Huh? But...
I told you, anybody's welcome here. Right?
Yeah.
My first time here, it was also like
I'd shown up out of the blue.
Oh, was it?
And so, I think it's fine for you to stay here.
What's wrong?
I was just thinking, you two are
kinda like a big sister and big brother.
R-Really?
Sorry... for being a nuisance.
Oh, no, not at all!
Megumi, Yu-yu, promise me one thing.
What is it?
Do something to protect Blackout's banner.
I don't want you to go through
what I'm going through right now.
Sure. I promise.
Yeah!
You need to hide the banner someplace safe.
Where is it right now?
Tomari said she hid it in
the fishing-pond shed, just in case.
I see...
Then... that's a relief.
Heya! What's wrong?
Huh? Um...
Oh, my father's coming home this weekend!
Is that so?
And, uh...
I'll be leaving on minor business
for two or three days.
Sure. Oh, what about the meeting of leaders?
I'll be back by then.
Got it.
Guess I’d better tell the others, too.
I’ll leave the rest in your hands.
I'm counting on you.
And so, I'll be away for a while.
You planning to work on a fishing boat
to earn a huge load of cash?
Well...
You could ride a fishing boat, or even a balloon?
Yeah... that's true.
Okay! You can leave the rest to us! Right?
Yes, ma'am!
You guys...
If the team hunters show up,
we'll drive them away!
Yeah, yeah!
Thanks, you guys.
Don't forget souvenirs, okay?
If I return.
Say what?!
Everyone, attack!
You'd better bring souvenirs!
And you'd better buy enough for everyone!
You got that?!
Father says he's at the station!
What, already?!
Yuki!
What should I wear?
Which one do you think is better?
Don't they both look nice?
Jeez, Aki!
Megumi
Today
Has Danji... come back yet...?
Y: Has Danji... come back yet...?
Not yet ;;
And today's the meeting of leaders! >_<
This number cannot be reached at this t--
Well?
I wonder if he's turned into fish food...
Don't say something that'll tempt fate!
So, that was still around.
Where's Danji?
On urgent business. Got a problem with me?
I don't mind.
You're also famous, and you have Zakusa along.
Go on in.
I had no idea there were
this many teams besides Blackout!
We simply don't usually associate with them.
The great thing about Vanguard is that
people from any walk of life
can fight in the same arena.
Hey, hey!
Did Blackout just send over their underlings?
That's treating this with quite a lot of contempt.
Oh, sorry. Unlike you, our leader is very busy!
What?!
Oh, no!
I'm scared!
Don't make fun of me!
Hey, chill out!
Quit playing around!
I'm starting the meeting.
I've gathered you all here for one reason:
To discuss what to do about
those jokers doing this team hunt stuff.
We just want to have fun playing, and yet...
I swear, it's a real nuisance.
Ashura
You and your challengers can do
whatever you like about winning or losing.
Ashura
However...
We will not allow any banner burning!
Our banner is a piece of team history and pride,
passed down by the members who came before us.
The act of burning a banner...
...crosses a line that should never be crossed!
Welcome home, dear!
Good to be back!
Here you go, dear!
Thank you!
Yu-yu, have you changed in some way?
I... I guess?
He's made a slightly offbeat friend!
Yes! One a bit rough around the edges,
but pretty good-looking!
Right?
Oh, really?
What do you know about those banner burners?
The kid who ran to us last week with a banner
saw the custom sleeves they used.
This is the design that was on their sleeves.
Who was this kid who ran to you?
He was from a team called Blue Monday.
Did you say, "Blue Monday"?!
Wh-What's the matter?
They were wiped out two weeks ago!
And their banner got taken away.
What did you say?!
Well, that's weird.
How would he have that banner?
Then, that kid must be...
Where is he right now?
Megumi!
We'd better rush back!
Well, this is strange.
Where did everybody go?
Over there!
Why are these scattered around here?
That was by the merry-go-round.
Guys!
You all right?!
They... they...
Who's "they"?
Oh, Megumi!
Shinobu! Thank goodness you're okay!
Shinobu?
Just fooling!
Hey, Masanori, they're back!
That's "Mister" Masanori to you.
Masanori?!
What's the meaning of this?!
This prank you're playing isn't funny!
The funny part starts now...
In that case, we don't need this anymore, right?
Ta-dah!
That's Blue Monday's?!
Yep!
That's right.
Let's dispose of it.
About time we get to burn it!
You can't...
So you're the ones who've been
going around burning team banners?!
Hmm, I dunno, maybe?
What the?!
There's a new banner, in a place like this?!
That's...!
I found it right where you said it was, big sis!
Megumi, you're so nice!
You won't get away with this!
Just what is your goal here?!
That reminds me, where's Yu-yu?
I told you, he's not coming today!
Oh, did you?
Answer my question!
Are you done playing, Masanori?
Tohya Ebata!
Masanori, quit the silly pranks.
Win first, then take the banner.
Wha?!
Now, now... we've got the scene all laid out here.
If you don't want the banner to burn, fight us.
If you lose, we'll take custody of the banner,
and I'll activate this switch.
Huh?! But what will activating that switch do?!
You get to look forward to finding that out!
Wait... let me play.
I'm fine with either one.
Then I'll leave Megumi to you, Tohya.
I want a revenge match with Zakusa!
Stand up, Vanguard!
I ride Fort.
My turn is over.
My turn! I ride Charis!
Yu-yu won against you, so I can, too!
I'll take another win against you this time,
using the full power of my deck!
You're in good spirits.
That's just fine, step on in...
I'll make it hotter than last time.
I attack!
That's a straightforward way of fighting.
Can't say I hate it.
Huh?! I'm not gonna forgive you so easily!
I misjudged you, you unfair jerk!
So I'm unfair? Big deal.
I'll teach you fools a lesson
for your peace-loving complacency.
I ride Bastion.
I call four units.
Furthermore, with Dark Strain's skill,
grade 3s gain the Boost ability!
Phanuel attacks!
Its skill activates: an extra critical!
Perfect guard!
Bastion attacks!
No guard!
Twin drive!
You need to realize that this is a battleground.
Bastion's skill activates!
Because a grade 3 was triggered, I restand Phanuel!
Plus, it gets +10,000 power!
World Order.
Abyssal Dark Night.
Great play, there. I’ve got chills.
I attack your Vanguard.
Oh, I'll do no guard against that.
What?
Since my calculations aren't panning out...
...I'd better work harder!
Alchemagic!
You can't do Vanguard all alone.
Let's go together...
...to the dark, dark abyss.
I'm not kidding here.
Your opponent chooses where you end up going.
Orfist attacks your Vanguard.
You're so unfriendly...
...however...
...you've already begun sinking.
Deeper, and deeper...
Blitz Order! I play Sealed Path!
My opponent's Vanguard gets -1 critical!
Wha?!
Twin drive!
Critical...
You made a huge mistake by assuming
that the darkness was entirely on your side.
There are also evildoers
who prefer to dwell in the darkness.
Magnolia attacks!
No guard.
I won't stand for you... for the likes of
you guys... stealing it away from us!
If I don't protect it...
then there's no coming back!
First check!
Front trigger!
Second check!
Magnolia!
Don't let your guard down.
Smiling during a fight reveals too much.
You can't protect anything
with that level of preparedness.
You're wrong!
Alchemagic!
Alchemagic again?
Of two people sinking into darkness,
the one approaching closer to death...
What are you doing?
...will be swallowed by fear before drowning.
Persona Ride.
It can't be!
That wasn't a bad fight.
While the darkness may feel welcoming...
...you should take better care next time.
It's over.
Shall I help out?
I'm fine. It's really not that many.
Oh, okay.
It sounds like you've made some good friends.
Yeah.
Isn't today when you go out?
To see them?
Yeah, but I do that every week.
Go to them.
When I was around your age,
friends felt more important than family.
So if you'd rather go...
I mean, you should just go.
Go on. I'll take care of the rest.
Sure! I'll be back later!
That was easy-peasy!
You should've done more to be certain
that you'd finish me off on your previous turn.
You made a paltry attack,
as a result of naively assuming
that there'd be a next turn.
I...
Don't worry.
It'll be fine, really.
Dang it, Danji... just what are you doing...
...at such a crucial time?!
Isn't it about time for this one's turn?
Hurry up already!
I'm gonna activate it!
C'mon, tell me! Tell me!
What's it gonna do?! What?!
Check Out My Card!
I'm Masanori.
This time, I'll introduce my card:
Mysterious Rain Spiritualist, Zorga!
Zorga is a genius at handling the Drop Zone.
It can resurrect any unit from there!
And of course this goes beyond regular units:
Order cards are also Zorga's playthings.
After playing a Normal Order,
by using Alchemagic on
an Order card in the Drop Zone,
you can go on to produce its effect, as well!
It basically makes the Drop Zone a second hand!
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Fire Dragon's Ceremony