Igaiga, we'll be arriving
in Kagoshima soon.
-I'm getting nervous.
-Yeah.
What is it?
I was just remembering.
The first time I took this ferry
to Hinoshima, your hometown.
Were you nervous?
Nervous? More like anxious, I’d say.
What a place.
Nothing but mountains and sea.
I've sure traveled far.
When we first met, you were so startled
that you fell down!
When I first saw you,
I thought you were a boy!
That’s so mean!
I was really looking forward
to your arrival!
Just like yourself, the people on this
island are full of personality.
At first, your grandpa seemed scary.
I didn't like him very much.
But Grandpa Gon
was always looking out for you.
My tea is murky.
His eyes are a dull grey.
Ichiga Igarashi!
Iga-Iga!
Yes, over here!
That’s me!
By the way, it’s Kazuyoshi Igarashi!
Oh, so you’re Igaiga.
Aunt Setsu was kind from the start, right?
She was. Come to think of it,
Aunt Setsu was the first person
to call me Igaiga.
And the breakfast she made me was so good!
Here you are.
I've brought the museum director.
Oh.
The director is technically my superior,
but I was so relieved
by how approachable he was.
-What’s his name again?
-It's Kento Hidaka, of course!
-Oh, right.
-Do you remember Bunpei's full name?
Bunpei... Bunpei... Tarou!
Osamu Fumihira! Don't forget!
What did you think
when you first met Yoko?
Her? Oh, well, I...
-Hi Yoko.
-Keep driving, Bunpei!
-Takuma, too.
-I'll stop the bleeding.
Let’s play soccer!
The police officer,
the teacher, Wataru, and Yuma.
You got along with everyone right away.
-Even though you have a scary face!
-You were the fastest to fit in!
Don't forget the island's wildlife!
Those beautiful sunset-red feathers.
And goats were just walking around!
And that insect!
You got stung on the butt!
It was so unbelievably itchy!
The creatures on the island are amazing!
Red fur, Tokara horses, goats,
giant eels, Bunpei, and that insect!
Wait. Did you include Bunpei in that list?
Bunpei?
But the most surprising thing
was the island's incredible golf course!
What?
What the heck is this?
Amazing!
They used the natural coastal terrain
to create a full-on links course!
The islanders built it
for their own enjoyment!
There's a headwind today.
I'm taking the shot!
She grips the club like a baseball bat.
This really is just for fun.
She has an extreme open stance,
facing directly towards the sea.
For a shot like this,
you need to hit a low, strong draw.
But she uses a thin three iron for it.
For a girl, it's quite a long, stiff club.
I guess she's expecting a big slice.
Go!
Like a swallow before the rain,
slipping under the wind!
What was that follow-through?
There it goes!
I did it!
I'd never seen a kid play like you did.
I thought you must be a monster!
A monster? That's so mean!
No, it's a compliment!
-It means you left a big impression!
-Don't call me a monster!
What was your first impression
of me, Tonbo?
Well, you’ve got a scary face.
A really scary face.
Your face is really scary, Igaiga.
Okay, next topic.
At first, I didn't understand
anything about you.
You refused to leave the island.
I’m staying.
I'm staying on this island forever!
I’m not going anywhere!
Look!
This is the pride of the island.
It feels like time has stopped here.
I wonder which ones are my mom and dad?
They say people
turn into stars when they die.
I understood the reason you learned
to play golf with a three iron.
I remember you cried then.
It was just the starlight
stinging my eyes.
-Is that so?
-Of course!
Sorry, I got carried away.
What will you do about high school?
There’s only a middle school
on the island.
I’m not going to high school.
I’m staying on the island.
I tried all kinds of ways
to show you a new world.
Yeah!
You gave me a wedge!
It was my first club
besides the three iron!
The grip contained your father’s memories.
I bet you'd like to try it, right?
Yeah!
Since you have the wedge,
I’ll teach you something
that you can’t do with a three iron.
I wanna try too!
Amazing.
Isn’t it beautiful?
It's like the sun is melting into the sea.
Putting a bench here was a great idea.
Playing golf with you and watching the
sunset from that bench was wonderful.
Right?
It reminded me how fun golf can be,
as obvious as it may be.
But you said something
really harsh after that.
Tonbo, what you’re doing isn’t golf.
It's not golf?
I wanted to challenge
you and your play style.
Challenge?
That's right! And boy did you ever!
Tsubura!
-Yoko’s niece.
-Tsubura Adaniya!
Tsubura was completely different
from anyone I had played golf with before.
She was so good that for the first time,
I felt all jittery about playing.
Yes. She really gave you
the challenge you needed.
A three-quarter shot with a driver?
I did it!
Nice.
Tsubura only swings from here to here.
And you still send it!
I always use a three-quarter swing.
That's how I'll become Japan's best.
Japan?
Yeah.
The coach told me
that if I master the three-quarter shot,
I can be the best in Japan.
After that, I can learn a full shot
when I aim to conquer the world.
Amazing.
She's Tonbo's age
and already taking on the world.
I... I don't want to lose!
Tsubura seemed half impressed
and half astonished by your golf.
Maybe the one-legged stance was too much.
What was that?!
I don't get it!
She opened the club face!
What are you going to do next, Tonbo?
Tsubura seemed truly
shocked by the way you played.
She was holding her head.
I was just doing things like I always do.
Tsubura will be your rival someday.
I’m convinced of that.
I wonder what Tsubura thought?
Same as me.
She wanted you to keep playing golf.
That’s why she said
some harsh things to you, too.
Yeah!
Let’s keep going!
What’s your dream, Tonbo?
Dream?
What do you want to become?
What are you aiming for?
I want to stay on the island.
Forever?
What will you do?
What do you mean?
You're just going to stay here?
Is that your dream, Tonbo?
That sounds kind of boring.
Your life will be empty.
This island has everything I need.
Flying fish and red-bearded deer!
It’s not boring at all.
I’m fine here.
I’m going to live here
for the rest of my life.
Are you sure you’re not just
convincing yourself of that?
Maybe you’re just avoiding the fact
that there’s a whole world out there?
There may be even more beautiful sights.
I was shocked at first when she said that,
but after that,
I learned about Tsubura's
true passion for golf.
He's been driving
the same old truck for years.
My father, that is.
It's all rusted.
And the bed is full of holes.
Letting your kid
play golf can be expensive.
I'm going to get really good at golf.
I'm going to buy my dad a new truck.
And there's something
I want you to have, Tonbo.
I was so surprised
when she gave me that club.
I was convinced.
-That Tsubura would be your rival--
-You already said that.
Take care of it and use it all up.
This was the idea of the person
who designed the course.
He figured it would
create a six-hole course.
Didn’t everyone on the island
design that course together?
They built it, yes.
But the design was done by Mr. Kuta alone.
Let’s go see him.
The person who designed the course.
Let’s go together, Tonbo.
Me too?
At first, I was really scared.
I promised to never leave the island,
but you took me to Akureki Island.
Scarier than my face?
You're hesitating?
But you know,
I was surprised when
you talked about yourself.
Yes.
I knew I had to tell you.
I used to be a professional golfer.
Used to be?
I lost golf, my family,
and most of all my pride as a pro.
But still, humans need to eat, you know.
It’s kind of funny.
I want you to learn
more about golf, Tonbo.
I was surprised by your tears.
I’m sure it took a lot of courage
for you to talk about that.
That's when I realized I had to be
courageous, too.
Tonbo, you're...
We went to meet
Mr. Kuta on Akureki Island.
He lived in such an incredible place.
The path to his front door
was like an animal's trail!
Is this really Mr. Kuta's house?
Looks like it.
St. Andrews at sunset.
Or maybe it was sunrise.
I've seen it countless times on TV, but
this leaves a different impression.
Who's there?
I heard you built
a small course on this island.
Is that true?
-Yes, I think so.
-Please!
Would you let Tonbo play there?
What a beautiful course!
It’s totally different from Hinoshima!
You had told me, Igaiga.
You said the course was...
What was it?
"Supper difficult!"
No! Super difficult!
"Supper" doesn't make any sense!
Go! Flying fish ball!
Flying fish, turn!
Climb, climb!
I did it!
Mr. Kuta's single-hole course
was so much fun.
And supper difficult.
Super!
You’re saying that on purpose!
Alright!
What did you think of the island?
Playing a new hole,
and the fastest green you've ever seen!
How was it?
It was fun.
It was so fun.
Taking you to Akureki Island
was the right decision.
I truly believe so.
You know,
I think I finally understand all the
things you’ve been telling me, Igaiga.
Oh? And what did I tell you?
Um...
Okay, let's move on then!
Hey!
Now I’ve got four clubs.
Igaiga, Tsubura.
Mr. Kuta, too!
And of course...
Mom and Dad.
I've made a big decision.
I’ve made my choice.
Next spring, I’m leaving the island.
Here's your diploma, Tonbo.
You grew so much from
the end of summer to graduation.
Next thing I knew you were in uniform.
What’s wrong, Igaiga?
It was such a joy to watch you grow up.
They say you get more
emotional as you get older.
You may have gotten bigger, but I don't
like a kid like you telling me that!
Stop making that scary face while crying!
Don’t oversleep tomorrow.
Right.
On this last night,
I didn't know what to say.
Even though there were
so many things I wanted to talk about.
It was Grandpa Gon who always
pushed me forward and supported me.
That’s right.
No one in the world cares
about you more than Grandpa Gon.
You've all made me who I am today!
Thank you!
I’m off!
I won’t forget you!
I'm your grandpa
and you're my granddaughter!
-Grandpa Gon.
-Anytime!
You can come back anytime!
If things get tough,
come back to your old gramps!
You can always return to this island!
Grandpa Gon. Grandpa Gon!
I’m off!
Grandpa Gon!
Take a good look, Tonbo.
That island is your hometown.
It’s where your story began.
It's a home you should be proud of.
Take a good look.
Tonbo, this is just the beginning.
Yeah.
It’s finally happening.
Look! You can see Kagoshima!
Wow, the lights are incredible!
-How about we get some good food?
-Yay!
You can treat me to
an all-you-can-eat meal!
What? Wait just a minute, Tonbo.
Go!
So those are the eyes of someone
raised only looking at the horizon?
Here comes Tonbo.
On the next Oi! Tonbo!
Tonbo's Course Debut!