Wonder Child
Tohya Ebata...
As you are top of the medical school class,
Wonder Child
I'd like you to give the congratulatory address
at next year's matriculation ceremony.
Will you accept?
It'd be an honor.
I am pleased to accept.
Go on, talk to him!
Aww, he left!
Oh! Look, it's Tohya!
He's so cool!
Brilliant as always, Tohya!
Thanks to you, we should be
in the black this month!
Glad to hear it!
So by strongly highlighting scarcity
through a focus on out-of-print goods,
it's increased demand, even in niche products?
Paradise Drive
Brilliant as expected, Tohya!
I never expected a membership system
to bring this many people here.
Nah, Pops, it's not a membership system,
it's a subscription model service!
A what?
You don't need to worry about the difference.
I'm gonna play a fighting game!
Tomita Baths       Coin Laundry
I do appreciate you driving me
to my part-time jobs.
Tomita Baths       Coin Laundry
However...
Don't worry about me!
A public bath really is best
after business hours.
Check it out, I get to
boldly soak in the women's bath!
Hey!
I can't clean if you're in here!
Here's this month's pay!
You're going to Kaga again?
Yes.
Well, you're a student.
It's important to have fun, too.
Once you become a doctor,
you'll be busy every day!
I'll bring back souvenirs.
Then I'll kindly accept your offer,
and request the usual Kaga treat, "kintsuba."
Everyone at the senior center
will be thrilled with that, too!
As you wish!
You're taking a while to heal.
Excellent, this is a true badge of honor!
Ouch!
You really didn't need to fight
until you were beat up this badly, did you?
I mean, if you don't fight,
you won't be able to win.
Was that "winning"?
You'll never know unless you try!
A-Are you all right?!
I can't... lift my arm.
Hit my chest!
Yes, that's the spot!
It's a matter of heart!
You fight in order to win, right?!
What's that look for?!
You've gotta have an adventurous spirit!
Ouch!
We're riding in a car.
Why do we need to have the wind blowing at us?
That's throwing away the greatest advantage.
You don't get it.
Isn't it great to let your hair
just trail in the wind as we race along?
You have no hair, Masanori.
You're so unromantic.
You've gotta have an adventurous spirit!
Quit talking like this guy here.
Saying that means I win, yeah?
Since you've never once won against Danji.
Did my quip tick you off?
Not really.
Nah, you're totally mad.
No, I'm not.
Don't get so worked up about it.
That tendency is how you get tripped up.
I was not tripped up.
My assumptions were naive, is all.
I won't lose next time.
How many times have you watched that thing?
At least look at me for now.
Good boy.
What are you trying to tell me?
That at some point, you'll feel that
casual moments like this were the happiest ones.
What do you think about
Danji announcing his retirement?
He'll be back soon enough.
That kid who led him to retire, what is he like?
Nothing to worry about.
He's just some poor kid
who got caught up in Danji's whims.
Really something, for the top med-school student
at Teito University to get this frantic about it.
Yeah.
That's why I'll bring it to an end this time.
I don't like quitting before ever beating him.
You're gonna quit?
It's high time for me to graduate
from playing games.
Each person's life has
a form that it's meant to take.
A form it's meant to take...?
And which form would this be, hm?
Sorry!
It's 'cause the rice cooker's broken.
Get some bread for tomorrow, okay?
All right.
Whoops!
That's unsafe, you know!
S-Sorry about that!
Oh! You're from Danji's place!
Who?
You know, the cute girl who was
really cheering on Danji from the audience?
There were two of them, remember?
This is the one who was in girls' clothes.
Makeup is incredible...
Out shopping at this hour?
Uh, yes.
You like Salisbury steak with a fried egg?
Yeah, ever since I was little.
You too, Yu-yu?
Yes!
A fried egg on top makes it feel special, y'know?
Yeah, really!
Let's eat while it's still warm!
Right!
Thanks for the food!
Why do they seem so in-synch?
So that's why you were in girls' clothes.
Yes, that's right.
It's not a hobby of mine or anything.
You could start that hobby, though.
It really didn't feel weird on you at all.
Didn't you have more important things
to pay attention to at the time, Tohya?
Shut up.
But you really impressed me in that match!
I impressed you?
Yes!
The way you kept attacking
over and over was just so cool!
I wonder if that's the purpose of
"fighting in order to win."
Oh, that was something Danji told me today.
"You fight in order to win, right?!"
Fight in order to win, huh...
Gah! I lost!
Okay, who'll fight me next?
There's nobody left.
Yeah, you're just too strong, Tohya.
Uh, say!
If you had this deck,
how would you make it even stronger?
You're okay with me looking?
Of course!
But isn't that basically
showing your hand to an opponent?
Oh, no, no!
I'd be glad if I could fight you someday,
but at my current level...
Gotcha. Okay, I'll take a look.
Huh! Wow, this isn't bad at all.
It's put together very well.
Is it really?
Isn't this rather remixed via substitutions?
Yes, it is!
I got advice from Danji and the others.
If I combine this with this,
it'll be even stronger!
What's up? You look happy.
Tohya, you've loved Vanguard
since you were a kid, right?
Oh... I just assumed that for some reason.
Well, you're right.
Yeah, even Tohya was a kid at one point.
Still, why are you so fixated on Danji, Tohya?
That's cutting to the chase.
Oh, sorry about that!
It's just, while Danji is pretty amazing,
to come this deep into the countryside...
I wanted to fight this deep in the countryside.
To me, Danji is just a bit special.
Twenty wins in a row, remember?
I'd never met such a devil-may-care guy before.
That's why I want to fight him, and win.
I'd travel anywhere in order to
experience a moment like that.
I'll fight him, and win, and then...
And then?
...get back to the life I was meant to lead.
Do your best!
What, ya can't fight seriously
unless in girls' clothes?
I'll start doing my best now!
With his indomitable spirit
and refreshing card handling,
Oh, shut up.
With his indomitable spirit
and refreshing card handling,
Yu-yu's showing himself to be a fine young--
H-Hey!
It's Tohya!
Is he making another challenge?!
But didn't Danji retire?
Danji!
I'm here to keep that promise to fight you!
I don't care about your flag
or the rights to the amusement park.
I just want to have a serious Cardfight.
He's come a very long way just for this.
Not fighting him would kinda
go against basic human morality.
The two of you chose a bad time for this.
Danji is in poor condition.
In the remote region of Kaga dwelled a man...
...who continued to accept the challenges
of powerful enemies, to protect a flag.
No matter the time, or the challenger,
the man faced them, never once running away.
And the flag still flies
behind that man to this very day.
He's seen fighters from
throughout this country of Japan.
That man is the only one I acknowledge.
I came this far expecting to fight him.
And he would never turn his back on a fight!
Now you're talking!
Yeah!
You can't right now, Danji!
Aren't you unable to lift your arm?
When he's selling that earnest an argument,
I can't not buy into it!
But still!
What are you...?
All right, I'll leave it to you.
Danji, don't get a newbie
wrapped up in your whims!
Th-That's not what this is.
I...
I want to fight!
Oh really?
Very well.
Hey, guys!
Descending once again
to this field on this night!
It's the Solitary Fighter, Tohya Ebata!
And accepting his challenge,
is our New Hope, Yu-yu Kondo!
Could we just get this over with?
Stand up, Vanguard!
It's my turn! I draw!
I ride Rino!
My turn! I draw!
I ride Fort.
I call Painkiller.
Fort attacks.
No guard.
Painkiller attacks.
I'm not nice enough
to hold back against a newbie.
And I'm not nice enough to hand anyone a win!
OverDress!
That is how it'd go, knowing your deck.
Reiyu attacks your Vanguard!
Arcs attacks your Vanguard!
No guard.
Phanuel attacks your Vanguard!
Arcs intercepts!
Rooks attacks your Vanguard!
I guard!
Fort attacks your Vanguard!
No guard!
My turn is over.
Yu-yu endured Tohya's full-force attack
and is still at only 2 damage!
Who knows how this will turn out?!
It's nothing. You just aren't
in the right frame of mind yet.
Calm down, calm down!
Remember, this is a game!
It's my turn.
I ride Nirvana!
Its skill activates!
I call Trickstar from the Drop Zone!
OverDress!
Nirvana attacks your Vanguard!
No guard.
Darn it! What am I doing here?!
I'm gonna do it!
I'm gonna win, and then...
...quit playing card games?
After this?
They say special children
show differences even from a young age,
but a child like him could be a doctor someday!
You got the top score again! That's amazing!
I'd better splurge on
a nice birthday present for you.
I can't think of anything.
It's your birthday present.
Don't just study.
Play is also important.
I'll be sure to tell your mother and father
that these cards will make you smarter.
Thank you.
My turn is over.
I can't let things end here.
I'm gonna beat Danji,
and then quit playing card games!
You're quitting?
A greenhorn like you shouldn't be
standing there, blocking my way!
I ride Bastion!
I move Fort to the back row!
I call! I call! I call! I call!
Calls to fill it all!
Is he trying to finish the match on this turn?!
I'll strike you with my greatest firepower!
Boosted by Fort, Rooks attacks...
...your Vanguard!
I loved the throb of my heartbeat
that I could only hear while fighting.
His scores haven't dropped, right?
But couldn't they be even higher
if he wasn't playing cards?!
He comes home late every day!
And you're still asking me
to let him do as he likes?!
Tohya...
I was wrong.
You'd never been one
to play with toys before, right?
So you got too engrossed.
I completely understand that
playing games is more fun than studying.
But--
It's not a game.
It's not a game!
I indulged myself with darkness.
I started to frequent Cardfighting spaces,
keeping away from home.
Reiyu intercepts!
Um...
Are you quitting Vanguard?
Didn't I tell you? I'm going back to
the life I was meant to lead.
I wanna quit this game already!
Do you really--
Shut up!
Shut up. Shut up.
Shut up, shut up.
Shut up!
You should do what you want to do.
I'll do the right thing.
I'll be sure to become a doctor.
So please!
Say...
You play cards, right?
How did you...?
I remember your eyes.
You used to hang around at
that Cardfighting spot every day, yeah?
Why haven't you been by lately?
Incredibly, Yu-yu has withstood
that bombardment, taking only 1 damage!
This fight is far from over!
Now it's my turn!
Stand and draw!
OverDress!
Vairina Valiente!
There it is!
When this unit's attack hits,
it can stand and attack one more time!
Yu-yu has progressed to his strongest card!
Boosted by Velocihazard,
Nirvana attacks your Vanguard!
No guard!
Twin drive!
Over Trigger!
Valiente gets +100 million power!
That ambition compares favorably
to a warrior of long military service!
Then, I too will take that challenge,
with all my body and soul!
Your tusk won't get through.
This Sword of the Ruler
will be the only one to do any slaying!
I don't know anything about you, Tohya.
I don't know why you're thinking of quitting.
And so, all I can do is beat you up!
With everything I've got!
Then I, too, will risk everything I've got!
I'll get that tusk of yours to fracture!
Pierce through!
This guy...
So you had yet another tusk!
Let's go!
Mom! I won!
I won the Vanguard tournament!
Hurry up and get ready.
You'll be late for cram school.
I have to quit.
I have to, and yet...
Sorry, Grandmother.
This really...
...isn't a game to me.
Check Out My Card!
I'm Yu-yu!
This time, I'll introduce Vairina Valiente!
Valiente is a unit that you can
further overDress onto Vairina!
It has a skill that gives it
+5000 power for each original Dress,
and another that lets it attack again
after a successful attack!
Valiente gets stronger with each layer it wears,
meaning... that's it!
I'll go out and buy some new clothes!
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Runny Porridge