Welcome to Wonder Hill
Let's Have Lots of Fun
Maiden Mannerism
Reconciliation
Uh, are all of you okay,
coming here during the day?
I'm off-duty today.
I'm free until university second period.
And I have the day off of work.
I see.
Ow ow ow ow...
Ishida, what sort of work do you do?
You know, you don't have to be so tense.
We're all good people here.
I'm not tense at all.
Oh! Here they come!
Good to see you!
The merry-go-round!
We worked with Tohya to fix it.
Oh. I see.
Uh, say...
Yu-yu!
I thought that was you, Koide!
And Mai and Akane!
It's good to see you!
Yeah, great to see you!
Looking good!
Tohya!
Please have a look at this!
Will things be all right?
"Magnolia"...
That's Meg's!
How did you get it?
I picked it up on the viewing platform.
Goodness, then she's been by the amusement park.
She could've actually said hello, though!
It's so like Meg to be nearby,
yet unable to come any closer.
L-Listen...
To Megumi's home?!
Yeah... so, uh...
If you know where it is, shall I go by there?
My, that'd be great!
Go out to meet her!
We're counting on you, New Leader!
So... if possible, please leave this to me.
I'll bring Miss Okura back, without fail.
I promise.
I'll go with you.
I'm pretty sure that Megumi wants to come back.
I want to help, too.
The young miss would be at school presently.
True, she would be.
Around what time will she return home?
Well... I am afraid the young miss
has been rather agitated of late...
I dare say that, even if you waited for her,
you likely would not be able to meet her.
Is that so?
I have... a card that Megumi dropped.
Couldn't I at least hand this back to her?
Pardon my rudeness, but might you be
two of the young miss's card-playing friends?
Uh, yes.
In my role as caretaker,
I cannot allow you through.
In point of fact, I am also in charge of
transporting her to and from school,
so you would not be able to meet her here.
Consider: the only time I do not watch over her
is while she is inside the school building.
This is the first time that
she has had friends such as yourselves.
At present, the young miss
appears to be having difficulties,
in matters where I am unable to be of help.
Raika Academy High-School Division
If at all possible, could I trouble you
to visit her at her school?
Raika Academy High-School Division
What the?
It's actually gone.
I see her!
So lovely!
Her dignified posture!
Her mystical gaze!
Sublime... she truly is
the pride of Raika Academy!
Raika Academy, huh...
That's a super-prestigious school.
Will we be okay, against their security?
You know about it, Tohya?
Yeah.
Teito University has a bunch of
Raika graduates, too.
Huh...
On that note... are you okay,
not being at school today?
Yes... well...
Sure.
But anyway, I thought of a way
we could get into Raika Academy!
Huh? What is it?
I'm home!
You're home late, Akiko.
What?! Another hot guy?!
That's right!
Yu-yu says he's a friend!
Well done, Yu-yu!
S-Stop it...
Thank you for always looking after Yu-yu!
N-No problem.
Sorry to drop by suddenly.
He said he has business with you!
Oh, dear! And here I am,
having taken a break from love!
Then, what about me?!
I'm currently accepting applications!
Stop it, I mean it!
Ah! That's impossible.
Huh? But didn't you graduate from there, Akiko?
I thought we could go in with you.
I could get inside, sure.
But Raika Academy has never
allowed in men from outside.
That does sound like a rich girl's school.
How Akiko managed to get into a school
like that is a mystery to me even now.
Hold on, what business do you have at Raika?
I just... want to go see a friend.
Goodness, you've got a friend who's a girl?!
Y-Yeah, she's a friend, I suppose.
I have a bit of business with that girl.
Hey, now! You already have a girlfriend?!
Uh, that's not what I mean!
There was... a bit of a mess...
...and it turned into something like a fight.
I want to make up with her, so Yu-yu and I
were talking about visiting her at school.
Yu-yu, you're wanting to
mediate in your friends' fight?
Yes, that's basically it.
Yu-yu is truly kind.
He's always helping me out.
You sure have grown up!
I'll definitely collaborate with you on this!
And so will I!
That said...
...if men aren't allowed inside,
there's no sense in visiting the school.
I've got a great idea!
Good thing you held onto that uniform!
The key point today is the makeup job!
It looks like there isn't any, right?
But this sort of natural look
is the hardest to manage!
So this was an option...
However many times I see it, it's incredible.
You're able to do makeup?
After being forced to umpteen times,
you start getting the hang of it.
No, no, it's amazing.
That's not something you could normally--
No talking.
Awesome!
With good raw material,
you've really outdone yourself!
Lovely!
Is this... me?
Yu-yu! You really are incredible!
Yu-yu Kondo!
Tohko Ebata!
Now, it's time to head into battle!
Good day to you.
G-Good day to you!
Wh-Where are we heading to?
Beats me!
For now, let's keep walking!
My heart is pounding...
I shall broach the subject.
It is "go" time!
Pardon me! Will you not be leaving early today?
Correct.
If at all possible,
would you care to join us for tea?
She even looks lovely
when giving a curt rejection!
Sublime!
Good day to you!
Good day to you.
Are... they acquaintances of yours, Meg Gloria?
Yeah... er, yes, acquaintances, I suppose
you could say they are acquaintances.
What is the matter, Meg Gloria?
There is sweat upon
the sculptural beauty of your brow.
I'm gonna report you!
No, don't!
What's "Meg Gloria"?
I swear I will report you!
Please don't!!
Forget it!!!
What a state Miss Meg Gloria is in...
Just who are you two?
Could you be... suspicious individuals?
She is a transfer student!
This girl is a transfer student
and an acquaintance of Miss Megumi!
Right?
Yes! Yes, I am!
And, um, this person here is, uh...
...my... mother!
Goodness! In that case,
you ought to have said so sooner!
Well, then. I shall promptly
escort them to the front door.
Good day to you.
Oh! Meg Gloria!
These two are a transfer student and her mother.
And being your acquaintances,
they are all the more important.
Should we perhaps offer them a tour of the school?
My, how wonderful!
Let us do so!
That is a lovely idea. Shall I join you?
Goodness, Madame Tohko and Miss Yu-yu,
you even knew Meg Gloria as a small child?
I envy you both.
What was Meg Gloria like as a child?
Ahh, let me see... she was very energetic,
and often prone to smiling.
Goodness, is that so?
Eh? I-Is that not the case now?
In fact, Meg Gloria is very quiet and dignified.
Quiet?
Dignified?
Miss Yu-yu, how did you become
acquaintanced with Meg Gloria?
Oh, um, I met Miss Megumi at Vanga--
V-Violin lessons!
Goodness! Meg Gloria plays the violin?!
How sublime!
Pardon me, but what is this "Meg Gloria" about?
"Gloria" is a hymn of glory from the Latin Mass.
Meg Gloria has told us of this herself,
that she is not accustomed to
showing her emotions outwardly.
Desiring to sing the praises of her cool beauty,
we originally addressed her as Lady Meg,
but when we added "Gloria"
and addressed her as Meg Gloria instead,
she had one of her rare moments
of displaying great joy, and--
Stop it!
What are you two doing?!
How dare you two barge into
my private affairs disguised as women?!
Get out!
Get out, now!
D-Disguised as women?!
H-Hold on!
What did you two come here for?!
We came to see you, Megumi!
This is dreadful!
Our Meg Gloria!
She's been kidnapped by hooligans!
Nobody's gonna come in here, see?
Meg Gloria!
Meg... Gloria...?
So, what do you want?
Where was that?
On the viewing platform.
Listen... I know I'm in no position
to be requesting anything.
But...
Could you please come back?
Where are you?!
Meg Gloria?!
Why?
Why did you wreck Wonder Hill?
I highly doubt that you'd understand this...
But...
In order to become strong...
...I discarded absolutely everything else.
I had to win, and in order to win, I had to fight.
That was the only route I could see.
So I activated that switch,
assuming that it would force a fight.
I'm one who goes to extremes.
I'm a fool.
Though I chose one thing
and discarded everything else,
I'm still not sure whether or not
that was truly for the best.
But because I did so,
I wound up truly hurting you all.
I'm sorry.
I can't forgive you.
But... I understand that feeling, just a little.
I've had times where I wondered if
I'd be better off just discarding everything.
You see, I went to meet with Bro.
For just one moment...
for one single moment...
...I thought that I didn't need anything:
not my home, not my school, not even Blackout.
But then...
...Bro said to me...
"You shouldn't just throw it all away."
I couldn't throw any of it away.
And that was for the best.
But you threw it all away, huh?
Yeah.
So there are people like that.
For the rest of my life,
I'll never be able to forgive you.
But I understand a bit of
how you feel, so that's okay.
Meg Gloria!
And hang on, just how long
do we need to stay crammed in here?
Meg Gloria!
Did they hurt you?!
Hooligans! Let Meg Gloria go!
Hooligans?
Well, you're certainly not wrong about that.
Because these people are my friends!
Meg... Gloria...?
So that's what you're like at school, Okura?
Got a problem with that?
No, I don't.
Someone unsmiling...
Someone super-cool...
I suppose I wanted myself to be a bit like that.
What's wrong with trying to look good?!
If you want me to stay with Blackout,
then remember one thing:
You shouldn't pry too much
into members' life situations.
Blackout welcomes all comers. That's why.
Oh, Yu-yu!
She really did come back!
Meg!
It's good to see you.
Thank you, Yu-yu!
And Tohya!
Thank you for keeping your promise.
Camera test, camera test!
Okay!
Starting video feed!
Hello-break, Daybreak!
I am your leader: Mirei!
I've got a friendly match today!
Word on the street says they're a famous team,
so my heart's going pitter-pat!
I'll do my very best, for the sake of
all of you cheering me on!
There were many others, besides me,
who were asked to cooperate in the plot.
I want to make amends for upsetting all of you.
I want to go and stop them.
I want to go with you.
Me, too.
Not because I want to cooperate.
So long as I'm with you...
...I won't let you do anything
weird like that again.
Thank you.
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
I'm Yu-yu!
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'll introduce Vairina Exspecta!
Exspecta is an additional overDress to put
on a unit that already has an overDress!
Accordingly, its skill is super-powerful!
When attacking, it gets
+15,000 power and an extra critical!
However, once the battle ends,
you discard all the originalDress units.
But don't worry!
On your next turn, you can immediately
reuse Trickstar from the Drop Zone!
A Piece of Soul
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Nordlinger
Infiltration