Nooo!
Calm down. It's fine.
Are you hurt?
What have you done?!
Somebody grab him!
Don't shout.
Don't shout!
Sealed Blaze Maiden
Face Off
Ms. Haruka, here are the documents for those
who will be conducting prayers this weekend.
Please have Miss Mirei validate them.
Thank you.
The owners of the land I purified the other day
wish to give Miss Mirei something as thanks.
What would she like?
Miss Mirei likes black tea.
Understood.
Ms. Haruka, a new client wishes for both of you
to come and visit them in the Ezo region.
Miss Mirei does not travel by plane.
We must decline.
Now, now. Shall we be on our way?
Haruka, you don't understand anything!
I've been wanting to go to Ezo!
My! For what reason?
I told you already!
I want to try guarana soda!
6 damage. Just as I'd expect.
That was educational for all of you, wasn't it?
Miss Mirei is so strong!
But, the lesson was that we shouldn't talk
about other things in the middle of a fight!
Precisely.
Our leader shouldn't need a warning, surely.
Miss Mirei?
It's just, you constantly misrepresent me, Haruka!
I want guarana soda!
What's "guarana"?
I know what it is!
What is it?
You heard her.
It's a yellow fruit...
What?
Isn't this your chance to get closer?
Listen, that's not what I'm doing here.
After considering the matter in my own way,
I suspect you came here in order
to get closer to that girl, didn't you?
Hey, come on! Shut up about that!
There's a place where you can get guarana soda.
You don't say.
This says they're holding an Ezo Fair,
at the Nagoya Station building.
Huh?!
Oh, um... I was just wondering if that thing
about the Ezo Fair was true or not...
Oh, uh... lemme see that!
It seems to be true.
But...
Hmm!
Maybe make it a date?
The wind!
Hey!
Make it a date!
Hang on a minute!
W-Wait, please!
Make it a date!
I must get Ms. Haruka's permission first!
Why?
Make it a date!
Why? Because...
It's okay, right, Ms. Haruka?
See how happy Miss Mirei looks?
That's not why!
It's because you're talking about dates!
Yes, of course.
Of course you have permission to go.
All I wish for is Miss Mirei's happiness.
I'll even lend you the car.
Go enjoy yourselves!
Um... Mr. Momoyama, would you like
to open your window, too?
Oh, no, I...
Let's take a short flight, Miss Mirei.
Mr. Momoyama?
Ahh, that was so much fun!
I am glad to hear that.
The station building
appears to be across the way.
Shall we get the soda, then return home at once?
Why? We just got here!
Ms. Haruka will worry.
Something smells great!
Pancake Fish
This is what I live for!
Do you... like sweets?
I love them!
But you know what? Haruka scolds me,
telling me that I eat too many sweets.
She's so annoying about it.
Is that not merely a sign she is
thinking of your well-being, Miss Mirei?
Aha! Even you parrot the same things
that those adults say, Mr. Momoyama.
Thank you!
Hooray, it's the tail!
You know what? Not even Haruka
knows this secret of mine...
I like the pancake fish's tail best!
Well, I guess either end is good!
Prefers tail of pancake fish
Honestly, lending out someone else's car...
I did get that person's permission.
Had that person known who you were
lending it to, you wouldn't have gotten it.
I have another secret!
What is it?
Well, you see...
I love, love, LOVE the smell of nail polish!
But you know what?
Haruka scolds me with, "Don't sniff that!"
And also, the precious charm Haruka gave me
and said I should never, ever lose? I lost it.
Isn't it in your pocket?
No way! It couldn't be in my pocket...
There it is!
That's good, isn't it?
How?! How did you know?!
I suspected you were a person with a tendency
to put all sorts of things into your pocket.
Yes! Yes, that's correct!
Sold Out, Thank You!
We took too many side trips first...
I guess not even a magician
could predict they would sell out.
A magician?
Yeah!
I'd swear you know everything
about me, Mr. Momoyama!
I'm fine without the soda.
Um... but if you don't mind...
...could we have fun... for a little longer?
If it's a little longer...
Sorry about that!
Sorry! That just startled me!
Okay, let's go!
Let's go back.
Ezo Fair
Let's go back...
Mr. Momoyama, um, I'm sorry that
I grabbed you like that. Were you startled?
No, I am fine.
Your heart is beating incredibly fast, too...
Could it be that
you have trouble with loud noises?
Well...
I knew it!
So do I!
I know a good method for times like this!
Take me to the plush toys section?
Now hug it!
Doing this lets you share your feelings.
My big brother taught me that.
I guess this is another secret.
Even at my age, I still sleep with a teddy bear.
Oh, but it's no ordinary bear!
It's really, really important to me.
You see, when I was sick in bed with a cold,
my brother saved his allowance to buy it for me.
When I hugged it the way
he told me to, I felt more at ease.
But you know, because of that,
now I'm unable to sleep without the bear!
Your big brother...
Do you not... hate him?
Why do you ask?
I just...
...had a feeling.
I love him!
I love my big brother!
While he's a bit strange,
and people at the house always used to scold him,
he's really funny, see?
He joined me in my pranks,
and did stuff like make holes
in the walls of the house,
which got him a big, big scolding from Haruka!
Oh, I did it again!
Mr. Danji, you go quiet so suddenly!
Does my conversation bore you?
N-No, that's not the case.
But you've been super-polite with me all day.
That is because...
...I am your servant, Miss Mirei.
Aha!
Okay, since you're my servant,
then you'll do what I ask, right?
Is here okay?
Yes.
Are you all set up?
If I win, you'll quit being so polite to me!
Okay...
Stand up, Vanguard!
My turn. I draw!
I discard a Jake from my hand, and ride Steve.
With its skill, I call Matt from the Soul
to the middle of the back row.
I Soul Charge with Deryck.
My turn is over.
My turn.
I ride Namorkahr.
Its skill activates.
I take a Swayanbuh from my deck
and add it to my hand.
Namorkahr attacks your Vanguard.
I don't guard.
Drive check.
No trigger.
Damage check.
It is a Recusal Hate.
My turn's over.
My turn. I draw!
I discard a Brothers' Soul from my hand,
and ride Richard.
With its skill, I put Matt
in the Soul, and draw one card.
Richard attacks.
My turn is over.
My turn.
I ride Halibadra.
Halibadra attacks.
What is she thinking about?
My turn!
I ride Bruce!
Bruce attacks!
Yes!
Critical trigger--
You made a fist pump, didn't you?
That's a breach of etiquette.
Etiquette?
"Don't behave in a way
that will bewilder your opponent."
Is that one of Daybreak's principles?
Yes.
Haruka and I decided that.
What do you think, Miss Mirei?
Huh? Me?
Yes.
Miss Mirei, what is
your opinion of that etiquette?
Are you trying to disturb my emotions
with irrelevant conversation?
No.
My turn has ended.
Right now, it is nobody's turn.
I simply wanted to know
your feelings about it, Miss Mirei.
Nobody has asked me such a question...
...other than my brother!
What would he ask?
He'd often say...
"To hell with manners!"
Do you feel that way, too, Miss Mirei?
I feel...
It's hard to say!
But still, while poses like fist pumps are bad...
...occasionally, there are times
when I feel like laughing gently, like this.
Then, let's laugh.
If we can laugh together,
that will let us be a little closer as friends.
You'll be closer friends, with me?
That depends on who wins!
If I win, you really will
quit being so polite with me?
I will.
But only if you win.
Got it!
Okay...
I'll win!
My turn.
I ride Bavsargra!
I arm Bavsargra with Swayanbuh
as Left Deity Arms.
There it is.
Bavsargra attacks your Vanguard.
No guard.
I feel a change... in the air around her...
Don't get swallowed up by it!
With a boost from Ihsita,
Sikshanya attacks your Vanguard.
My turn's over.
My turn!
Final Rush!
Eden attacks Sikshanya!
I guard.
No guard.
Its skill activates! I retire Ihsita!
"No guard," without any hesitation.
What is this sensation?
Her face is unreadable!
Bruce attacks your Vanguard!
With its skill, I restand
all rear-guards in the front row!
No guard.
Twin drive!
Double front trigger!
The unease hasn't vanished... but!
I'll keep this up to force my way through!
I attack!
I guard.
With Swayanbuh's skill,
Bavsargra gets +10,000 power!
My turn is over.
Absolutely nothing got through...
I arm Bavsargra with Prithivih
as Right Deity Arms.
With Bavsargra's skill when armed with both cards,
I retire all my opponent's front row rear-guards.
Furthermore, it gets an extra critical!
Wha?!
I call!
So that was why!
She protected that rear-guard earlier,
in order to reserve the back row unit
that's boosting it here.
With a boost from Ihsita,
Bavsargra attacks your Vanguard!
Mirei... were you...
With a boost from Ihsita,
Bavsargra attacks your Vanguard!
With the armed Prithivih's skill,
it gains +10,000 power!
...always like this?!
With the armed Prithivih's skill,
it gains +10,000 power!
I guard!
Twin drive. Front trigger!
It still won't go through!
Wrong.
Using Prithivih's other skill,
by discarding this card,
I deal 1 damage!
That was so much fun!
You're a fun person, Mr. Danji.
I suppose I might be, Miss Mirei.
I... I mean, I suppose so, Mirei.
Well done!
You had a leaf stuck to you.
What's that?
Boy, this turned into a real bother.
Our assassins came scurrying back.
Since they had such a horrible time,
I tried following up on the places they'd fought,
and it appears that something is headed our way.
What is it?
A Blackout.
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
I am your leader: Mirei!
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'll introduce my card,
Sealed Blaze Maiden, Bavsargra.
A Piece of Soul
With Bavsargra, you can arm
two dedicated Order cards!
Here they are: Sealed Blaze Sword, Prithivih,
and Sealed Blaze Shield, Swayanbuh!
By arming them, not only can you retire
all of your opponent's rear-guards,
you can even get an extra critical!
With those two weapons,
you'll knock down all the bad guys!
A Piece of Soul
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Greedon
Gluttony