Tomari: So, let's see what you can spin this year
Zakusa: When the waxing moon has waned twice more
Zakusa: Comes 'the day' you'd spun my wheels before
Zakusa: And so I ask of the Rose Witch tonight
Tell this servant...
Danji: Isn't there anything fun to do...?
like?
What would you like?
P-p-p-p-p-
That's CardFight Pro-Wrestling!!
Pro-wrestling?!
Not so loud!
On top of retiring as a Cardfighter...
Now you say you're gonna be a pro wrestler?!
I told you, not so loud!
I swear, something's the matter with you lately!
Something being the matter is
very much his usual mode of operation.
Hey.
So again, why pro-wrestling?
Hm?
I was asked to do it.
Pro-Wrestling Association
Assembly Hall
By the old man from the
Neighborhood Pro-Wrestling Association.
Pro-Wrestling Association
Assembly Hall
As you can see,
professional wrestling is currently
on the verge of extinction in this town.
We need a man to inherit this mask
and resurrect the Pro-Wrestling Association.
I have long searched for such a man.
You will help me, won't you?
Leave it to me!
Danji the man will be a pro-wrestler!
And well, that's the story in a nutshell.
Right, second?
Right!
And you should have second thoughts about this!
Now, now!
So anyway, that's why I need to
build up my body by next week!
C'mon, Yu-yu!
Right!
That filled me up good!
Thanks!
You okay?
Yeah... but wondering
if we can really win this.
Don't worry.
Whoever comes, I won't run or hide.
I'll defeat 'em fair and square!
I swear it on my big thumb here!
That's our Danji!
Well, yeah!
Besides...
...the Neighborhood Pro-Wrestling Association
couldn't bring in that big a deal of a wrestler!
Where's Zakusa?
Isn't he still asleep?
A signing ceremony? It's like a title match.
Isn't this kinda large-scale?
You are Danji Momoyama?
I am, why?
Enthusiastic about this match?
Huh? W-Well, yeah...
I'm gonna beat him to a pulp!
I don't know who's coming,
but now's his brief chance to run away!
But there are some calling this
an ill-advised challenge.
It's just a town revitalization event...
Hey, he's here!
What's going on?
Why did you accept a challenge from an unknown?
Tell us about your enthusiasm for this match!
Give us a statement please, Mr. Tanahashi!
What the? It's Zakusa,
and... Hiroshi Tanahashi?!
Who's that?
You don't know?!
Bro, step down!
I won't make fun of you, so just quit, okay?!
Uh...
Hey, Zakusa, what's going on here?!
You didn't know?
This guy's no third-string,
he's a super big-league wrestler!
Hey, Zakusa! Just what are you pulling?
I could've sworn...
What if I take a Skyrocketing Elbow,
or something like that?! Tell me!
Exciting, isn't it?
Say what?!
You there, do you play cards?
You a strong player?
Y-Yeah...
Danji's the strongest Cardfighter around!
He's called the Tiger of Kaga!
Right?
Here, Danji.
Hiroshi Tanahashi!
This is gonna be you tomorrow!
What superhuman strength!
They're last-week's and last-last-week's issues,
so I had no problem with tearing them!
Bravo.
Fight... Fight me!
If you could lend me an ear, Mr. Tanahashi...
Got it.
I'm gonna beat you senseless!
Bring it on!
Wait, Zakusa, what did you tell him?!
I've decided how the two of us will fight:
CardFight Pro-Wrestling!
What?
CardFight Pro-Wrestling?!
Cards are another strong point of mine.
How 'bout you and me duke it out in both arenas?
Bro's gonna Cardfight?!
Excellent! Let's do this!
Once they trade their written oaths,
these two will be mutual enemies!
Now is the moment when this
unprecedented title match becomes reality!
No regrets, now!
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Why didn't you call me?!
I never heard that Tanahashi was coming!
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Well, neither did I.
Blasted Zakusa, pitting me against Tanahashi.
Despite his usual manner,
Zakky can be unexpectedly dynamic at times.
But you looked really cool there, Bro!
Saying, "Fight me!" to THE Hiroshi Tanahashi!
W-Well, yeah...
So, what's this "CardFight Pro-Wrestling" thing?
It seems you do a round of Cardfighting,
then a round of pro-wrestling, and repeat.
Sounds like Chess Boxing, where you
alternate between chess and boxing!
Great! That's just your kinda fight, Bro!
Are you perhaps having regrets?
Not at all.
Why would I have any?
After all, this is a fight.
And going up against someone
overwhelmingly strong is what makes fights fun.
Danji...
It's just, this is Tanahashi here.
Hard to stay calm, y'know?
How do I go about fighting him?
If you win the Cardfighting in the first round,
then you won't have to do any wrestling, right?
That's it! Great idea, Megumi!
What was I worried for?!
Aww, that's no fun!
So you'd rather see me get killed by Tanahashi?!
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Forget I asked!
Don't worry, Bro! You can beat him in Round 1!
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Yeah, it'll be an easy win!
CardFight Pro-Wrestling Deathmatch - 12 Rounds
Tanahashi vs Momoyama
It's right before the match,
you don't need to eat it all!
I know that!
Bro, is your deck--
Don't worry, I'm all set!
No matter what, I'm the Tiger!
Sheesh...
That's 'cause you didn't chew.
I'll go buy some more water bottles.
No, I'll go!
Cigarettes/Alcohol          Coffee 100 yen
But I'm his second!
Will this be enough water?
Isn't this more than enough?
The young lady seems to be
greatly enjoying herself.
Thank you, Zakusa.
No, thank you.
Town residents!
It's time to start the insane deathmatch!
Getting to see Tanahashi
up this close... it's making me giddy!
Oops! Gotta do my job!
In the blue corner,
the nightmare born of Kaga:
Danji Mo-- huh?
With the essence inherited from
Kaga's delicate specialty, Kobako snow crab,
Snow-Crab Mask is on the scene!
Snow-Crab Mask?
Wait, what are you doing?!
This mask was entrusted to me
by the head of the Pro-Wrestling Association.
We're on your side, Snow-Crab Mask!
He's a hit...
Ahem...
In the red corner!
The Once-in-a-Century Talent descends to Kaga!
Hiroshi Tanahashi enters the arena!
Oooh! Tanahashi!
Both players are presented with bouquets!
But I'm his second...
No complaining!
Zakusa told us there's a labor shortage.
The girl in the green dress is so cute!
Yeah, that girl's my type by a long shot!
Do your best, please!
Sure!
Ow ow ow! It's sliding!
Okay, let's break it up, now...
Round 1!
Stand up, Vanguard!
Vanguard!
It's Once in a Century Talent
Hiroshi Tanahashi,
versus local hero Snow-Crab Mask,
in the first ever CardFight
Pro-Wrestling Deathmatch!
The first round is a Cardfight round!
Good luck, Bro!
Hang in there, Snow-Crab Mask!
You can win this!
Fight hard, Danji!
Uh oh! Snow-Crab Mask is making his move!
I won't let it get to a pro-wrestling round!
Let's end this before it starts!
What?! ...I see!
Tanahashi's just that brilliant!
Bro, what are you doing?!
The round's gonna end!
Wow, to think I'd get to
Cardfight against Tanahashi...
I'm gonna take a moment,
and unleash the coolest move, ever!
Oh, shoot! I got too into it and lost track!
Round 2: Pro-Wrestling
Oh, jeez...
Plan A, right?
Yeah, leave it to me.
The second round is pro-wrestling!
The arena where Tanahashi is unrivaled!
Oooh, Tanahashi!
Slipping out...
What?
I'm a crab! I'm a crab!
Snow-Crab Mask makes a crab-run
to escape beneath the ring!
Snow-Crab Mask's back out!
Tanahashi's after him!
It's Tanahashi's Dragon Screw!
I give, I give!
Who're you?
Plan A failed!
No other choice, then!
Uh oh! Now there's more Snow-Crab Masks!
This is really tough!
Which one of them is the real one?!
He figured it out already!
Another game of tag?!
Get back in the ring and fight, children!
Danji! Here's some water!
Forget water! I can't even see the cards!
You've gotta survive, Snow-Crab Mask!
Don't die on us!
You all right?
"I can keep going!"
"I'm gonna do this... pro-wrestling!"
What happened to the Vanguard part?!
The sight of him getting more and more cornered,
is frankly my favorite treat!
Hit him harder!
This can't be happening!
Make it stop!
Yu-yu! Throw in the towel!
Why isn't he throwing it?!
"What's wrong, tired already?"
What in the world is happening?!
Tanahashi's suddenly heated up!
Oraa!!
Yessssss!
Nooooo!
Orrraa!!
A Sling Blade!
This is Tanahashi at his finest!
Can he no longer stand up?! No, Snow-Crab Mask!
In the face of the Once in a Century Talent,
is this the farthest you can get
with the power of crab essence?!
"Now take this!"
Snow-Crab Mask does a Cross Chop!
His crab pincers strike at Tanahashi's throat!
Neither budges an inch!
It's a flesh against flesh, bone against bone,
will against will collision!
I'm burning up!
A Twelve Six!
Dropped down headfirst!
Whoa! Who could've foreseen this?!
It's the stance for Tanahashi's
greatest finishing move, High Fly Flow!
You did brilliantly.
Danji!
Snow-Crab Mask can do nothing more!
One! Two!
Lookit that!!
Incredibly, Snow-Crab Mask
has interrupted the High Fly Flow finish!
Snow Crab! Snow Crab!
Snow Crab!
Get him!
Snow Crab! Snow Crab!
One...
Two...
Three!
Tanahashi gets the three count!
Knew you'd be great.
You too.
People of Kaga, I love you!
Danji! Danji!
Bro!
I lost, big time.
And I looked uncool in front of you guys.
You weren't uncool at all!
Bro, you risked your life to advertise
the Neighborhood Pro-Wrestling Association!
Yeah...
Now some life has been breathed
into this town's pro-wrestling.
That's right.
The CardFight Pro-Wrestling Association
that you built with your family is alive again.
Good luck with your future endeavors.
Uh, I never built such an association.
Well, of course not.
This town has no pro-wrestling association.
No Neighborhood Pro-Wrestling Association?
No Card Pro-Wrestling Association?
Neither exist. It was all made up.
Made up?
Then, why did you have me--
Mr. Tanahashi! You were incredible!
S-Sure.
Zakusa! Once in a while, you're pretty capable!
Have a good time?
Only the best ever!
Thank goodness.
I set up this fight for your sake.
Because...
...today is...
...our anniversary, right?
Wait, what anni--
I wanted to give you a present.
Did you like it?
You must want a reward if you went this far...
Well, then!
I'll be giving you your reward.
In spades.
Wha?!
My, something like that could be nice, too!
Wha... wh-wha...
Wha?!
I didn't want anything like this!
Now suffer for every injury I took!
You're gonna pay!
I enjoyed it, though.
Hey! Quit dodging!
I missed!
So close!
How about here?!
Take this!
Check Out My Card!
I'm Tohya.
At last, it's my turn.
Now to make the most of it!
Today's when I introduce my Apex Ruler, Bastion!
Using its continuous ability, Bastion gives
all your grade 3 units +2000 power!
So if you went first against
an opponent's grade 2 of 10,000 power,
the +2000 power would let a grade 3
attack it with 15,000 power!
The bonus means that your single unit's attack
has a guard requirement of 10,000!
But even if you went second, a boost of 8000
would give your column 23,000 power,
so against an opponent's grade 3 of 13,000--
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Wonder Child