This is the most fun I've ever had.
Tonbo finished the hole at one under.
The winner will be determined
by the results
of the last group.
Tsubura. Hinoki. Ema.
I'll need to make it in two strokes,
but finishing in even three
will be difficult.
However…
Missing the par means
losing my spot at the playoffs.
I'll have to go through the grove
and land on the 18th fairway,
or bring it to the right side
of the fairway of the fifth hole.
If not that…
I'll have to hook it onto the green
just like Tonbo did.
I'll aim for the final hole.
Can it really turn that far?
I have to do this!
Go! Get there!
She's going for a two-on?
The wind blew it back.
This will make it hard to get par.
Tonbo used her secret weapon
at the final moment.
As for Tsubura,
she hit a shot completely different from
her secret weapon at the last moment.
Why couldn't you get
that great one pattern, Tsubura?
I'm hanging on by a thread.
If I can just finish in two strokes...
You'll need to take relief from here.
The nearest point of relief is…
There.
The green is blocked.
But from here, I can see the pin.
I'll go low through the trees,
and roll it to the green.
No…
I can't.
There's a bunker in front.
If I can't carry it to the green,
I can't land it next to the pin.
So this is the end?
If I go through there,
I can carry it to the pin!
I can't let the ball hop
like it usually does.
I'll have to hit it high,
starting with my swing.
To do that,
I'll have to put
all my weight on my left leg.
Seven-iron.
No, I'll take the eight-iron please.
What about relief?
No. I'm going to hit from here.
She's going to hit it off the asphalt.
She's not taking the relief?
I've got to loft it as high as possible.
This isn't enough. I need more!
It's only momentary.
I've put up with this pain for ten years.
Just a little more...
Just one more swing!
Make it through!
The ball dropped straight down.
Look at that.
That's not just technique.
She put her heart and soul into that shot.
Using the soul as your trump card.
This is why I love competitive golf!
She's got a chance for birdie.
This means…
Ema can still win.
That was amazing.
I was really moved!
Thank you very much.
If I can get it in…
I can catch up!
The head of Ema's putter snapped clean off!
It what?
What is this?
It's like a sign from the god of golf...
Why me?
Golf never goes as planned.
It never goes the way you want it to.
It tests you to your core.
I know it'd be better to give up.
Life would be so much easier.
But I just can't quit.
The last ten years were for this shot.
This makes it all worth it.
I hope I can make a shot like that again.
Though I'm not sure when that may be.
All I can do is keep playing.
I have to accept things the way they are
and keep swinging.
I've never hit a ball like that before.
She put so much into that shot.
Just one shot carries so much weight.
All of my shots seem to be weightless.
Wow! She's close!
It's Ema's. If she gets it in
she'll be tied with you.
Hinoki's up.
Never again.
She's a bit left of the pin.
Ride that left wind!
Go!
No! Stop!
It's still close enough to putt in.
Why are you so excited?
You'll lose if it goes in.
If Ema Kurisu gets the birdie putt,
she'll tie the top spot at one under.
If Tsubura Adaniya can
sink it in one putt,
she'll keep her top spot at one under.
If Hinoki Otoha can sink it in one putt,
she'll win at two under.
If she misses she'll be at one under.
A play-off against Tonbo Oi.
You mean these four
have their own play-off?
Tsubura's up.
The conditions are just right
for easily stopping the ball.
Is she going to chip it in?
No.
She’s making sure the ball won't bounce
off the pin and roll away.
She wants the ball to stop.
If the ball is spinning,
it would bounce right off
if it were to hit the pin.
If that's what she's thinking,
that means she's planning on
carrying the ball right to the pin.
That's right.
I swung too hard!
If she hadn't taken it out,
it really would have hit the pin.
She knew it would stop within two steps
on the first or second bounce.
She's relying on the putt now.
That was her play.
It's not only the approach.
She's thinking about how
to keep par with her next putt.
Even in this crucial moment,
she's able to think clearly.
Tsubura is a fearsome competitor, indeed.
It's the exact same distance and line.
We'll both finish the hole
at one under if we get it in.
The person who hits second
will have a big advantage.
If the first player makes the shot,
the second player's line will be exposed.
You can keep it out.
Unlike Tsubura,
she's clearly going for the chip-in.
If she wants to get it in the cup,
she'll have to use a wedge.
However, under pressure like this,
she'll want her putter as well.
If she takes her wedge,
it's a sign that she's well prepared
and is incredibly confident.
And there you have it.
I expect great things from her.
Hinoki practices hard.
She puts in more time than anyone else.
No matter how strict
her father's coaching may be,
she never gives up.
And when things go well…
I did it, Dad!
Hinoki's father has drilled golf into her.
But is that really all?
When I saw her smiling back then,
I knew a bright future awaited her.
I wanted to train her more myself.
Over there.
I've practiced an approach
from this distance thousands of times.
No, even more than that.
Now it all comes down to this shot.
Ema taught me so much.
As did Tsubura, and Tonbo too.
I want to be a golfer just like them.
I want to fight
for everything I've worked for.
It went in.
It's on the line.
She did it.
I did it.
I used everything I've learned.
Hinoki.
That was great.
You showed us how confident you are.
That was an incredible putt.
We'll have to see what happens next.
This could come down
to a cut-throat final shot.
I'm marking my ball.
I still have a chance to win.
I'll shoot first.
But…
I think I'm a hair farther back.
I see.
This is because
It was Ema's fault that
Tsubura missed her tee shot.
Now she's making up for it.
Which club will she use?
Her putter is broken, after all.
Her putter broke?
So what will Ema do?
She'll just have to use
one of her other clubs.
I'll use this one.
A wedge?
There are two cups.
She's on the same line I shot from.
I couldn't make it in at the very end.
It's the same line as me!
No! Go right!
Yes! It's turning!
More! More!
Go!
This puts Ema out of the match.
Ema.
I did my best.
The ball went off course
during Ema's wedge putt.
Can I trust this line?
Or should I find a new line completely?
If the ball had stayed on track,
she could have used that line.
But it may have made
things even tougher for her.
Thinking before a shot.
The most important part of golf.
But also the most difficult.
It's not as bad as it looks.
Just stay slightly inside Ema's line.
Tsubura!
Just slightly inside the line!
Did she hit it too hard?
Go!
She missed the comeback.
If she gets it in, it'll be
a playoff against Tonbo Oi.
Hinoki!
You can make that shot
with your eyes closed!
Mr. Otoha!
Yahoo!
Alright!
Now it's the playoffs Hinoki!
You've got this!
No. You're wrong.
What?
Hinoki.
Yesterday, on the fifth hole.
My ball moved!
But I didn't report it!
But I kept playing.
I continued on!
I…
I want to be like Tonbo, Ema, and Tsubura.
I want to play like them!
I should...
...be disqualified!
That means…
What?
-Igaiga? Your face is scary.
-You… you…
Scary? Or should I say weird?
-You…
You… You…
Tonbo!
You…
You won, Tonbo!
I wanted to say it!
Grandpa Gon! Grandpa Gon!
It's Tonbo!
Tonbo?
She won the tournament!
Is that so?
She really did it.
Tonbo.
Congratulations!
Thank you, Tsubura!
This hurts! It really hurts!
You're really a monster after all!
A monster?
You won't win the Japan Woman's Open!
Just you wait!
Got it?
I won't lose next time!
Tsubura.
The winner at the next one
will be the real number one!
What's the Japan Woman's Open?
It's the tournament that decides
the best amateur golfer.
Can you believe we lost to this girl?
Hey, what about Hinoki?
Oh, Hinoki?
She just went out that way.
I'm sorry, father.
I couldn't win.
I told you to win, not to cheat.
Igaiga...
When I was young,
I experienced terrible lows.
But I never stole from anyone.
What you've done is theft.
You stole a single golf stroke.
I…
I'm a thief.
However…
I'm the one who cornered and pressured you
to the point that you considered stealing.
Due to all that pressure,
I couldn't teach you anything important.
I weakened your spirit.
I'm sorry.
Father.
You might not be able
to play golf for a while.
You'll likely be suspended from competing.
What have I done?
By stealing one stroke,
I betrayed Tonbo and the other players.
I deserve the consequences.
I think you've learned your lesson.
I'm sure your heart was hurting
as you continued to play.
I'm sure you wanted to go back
as soon as the ball moved.
That's why you confessed
to everyone on the last hole.
That must have taken a lot of courage.
That's enough, Hinoki.
Please.
As a golfer,
what Hinoki did was truly dishonest.
Even so,
please don't keep her from
having a second chance.
Please continue to support her.
Please!
It is said that golf is a game for
ladies and gentlemen.
However, that may not be accurate.
Rather, it is the kind of game that
creates ladies and gentlemen.
This is the truth of the matter.
No one enters the course initially
as a dignified person.
I belive they become dignified only
by finishing a game.
Mr. Nakase…
Hinoki.
You're not going to quit, are you?
Tonbo.
I'm not quitting.
She's coming home.
I didn't expect to come home so soon.
It's a bit embarrassing.
You've got quite
the souvenir to bring back.
Everyone will be welcoming you.
Thank you, Igaiga.
What's gotten into you?
You know,
I'm glad I play golf.
I'm really, really
glad I play golf!
Your story is only just beginning.
You're going to get
bigger and stronger, Tonbo!
I love golf!
Hooray!