Natural Hot Spring
Beauty Bath
Please meet up with us in front of
the bathhouse at twelve o'clock!
But I wouldn't have minded camping out, too...
Didn't you say you'd have money
if you could get to an ATM?
I forgot that I'd bought the latest carton.
Festival!
There's a festival going on nearby.
Wow... wanna go to the festival?
You're in good spirits, Tohya.
I was joking!
Sublime Bath
Hey.
Isn't that...?
Sublime Bath
Dark Trickstar
Encounter
The recording from when you went to
the Ezo Fair was magnificent.
Your big brother... do you not... hate him?
I get it! You can stop!
What are you doing, expanding on the topic?
The reason I'm keeping you close at hand
is so that I can decide
how you will be dealt with.
I'm not saying to hide the truth your whole life.
If I deem it necessary, I could even create
an opportunity to reintroduce you as her brother.
And so...
...don't do anything uncalled for.
Say...
...are we taking a detour?
Why do you ask?
Because I heard the hotel we're staying at
is really close and on a straight road
from the shrine we just paid a visit to,
but this car has made several turns.
That, and because you're a magician, Danji.
I'm not sure I follow...
I mean, you know what
I'm thinking right now, don't you?
It's boring to go straight home after work?
Try again.
I wanna eat something sweet!
There, you got it!
I'm not doing anything uncalled for.
This is something necessary.
Right now, I am Danji Momoyama.
As Danji Momoyama,
I want things to go well with Mirei.
I'll decide when it's necessary to act on that.
Remember how they were sold out?
The guarana soda?
Yeah. I searched around,
but I couldn't find it anywhere.
Natural Hot Spring
Beauty Bath
But to make up for that, I found a yummy
limited parfait they sell here in Mino.
Natural Hot Spring
Beauty Bath
Hooray! I love parfaits!
Natural Hot Spring
Beauty Bath
We can't use the baths, though.
We'll just go in to eat.
Okay.
Sublime Bath
Danji?
Don't... don't worry.
They're my friends!
They're your friends?!
Then they must be good people!
And, uh... who is this young lady?
Oh, uh... she's my employer... so to speak.
A new job?
Well... something like that.
And wait, you guys...
Aren't you kinda dirty?
Well... stuff kinda happened,
and now we're penniless.
We can't even afford a bath.
Danji, let's pay for them!
After your bath, let's eat parfaits together!
Danji seems in good spirits.
Seems rough for Miss Minae,
though, not being able to see.
Where'd your good spirits go to?
Hey, I am in good spirits!
I'm getting the bath I wanted!
But...
...I feel like I've seen her somewhere...
Excited about the parfait?
Oh, yes!
Don't be so nervous!
I'm currently recruiting friends!
So let's be friendly!
Thanks for everything.
Even treating us to parfaits.
You really are a Big Bro.
I haven't been called that in a while.
Come on, man, you really saved us!
Even covering our travel expenses... thank you.
Now you can get back to Kaga, right?
No, we're not going back yet.
Huh? On that note,
why did you guys come out here?
We're headed for the headquarters of Daybreak.
On our way here, we've been
crushing Daybreak's team hunt.
Now the other teams are cooperating
with us, in order to stop Daybreak!
G-Great...
Drumroll, please!
Here's Mino's specialty,
Moo-Moo Hida Dairy Parfait!
Yay!
Let's eat!
Curse you, Haruka.
Why didn't you tell me
what was going on with Blackout?!
At any rate, I'd better make absolutely sure
that they don't find out they're mutual enemies!
This is really good!
Oh, say!
Do you both play Vanguard, too?
Yes!
Are you on a team or something?
Yes! Kaga's own--
Danji?
There's... a lovely garden over there!
Bathing in the morning is awesome!
I can't afford anything here...
Oh, I hear festival sounds again.
Some sort of explosion?
They're fireworks, right?
There's a festival in this area.
Oh, yeah. The one on the poster.
Festivals sound like a lot of fun.
Have you never been to one?
Right. I'd like to go, but...
You know, they can be dangerous, so...
They're not dangerous at all!
Shall we go with you?
As thanks for getting to use the bath...
though I don't think it can match that.
Sure! It's a promise!
Oh! But...
I'd better ask Haruka if it's okay to go...
Who's Haruka?
She's like the den mother for my team!
Miss Minae, you're also on a... team...?
Danji?
Anyone else hungry?!
It's a bit early, but maybe
I'll check out ahead of time?
What lovely weather...
I'll just try out the stone sauna...
Guess what?
I play Vanguard, too!
Oh, I see!
You're both impressive,
packing away a second parfait.
You two... really seem similar.
They make a cute pair, yeah?
N-No, don't be silly!
Hold on, you've got some on you.
So, something else!
Let's talk about something else!
Let's see... ask me a question!
Okay... Miss Minae, if you're also on a team--
Hey! Why do you both keep
breaking off in the middle of sentences?
Sorry... it's just...
SHHHH!
Then, I'll ask you a question!
Which team do you belong to?
It's called Blackout!
What's been with you, Danji?
You keep derailing the conversation!
You're both members of Blackout?
Yes!
Isn't Blackout full of bad people?!
What do you mean?
Ahh! I sure can't wait for the festival!
Blackout is a bad team that keeps
interfering with Daybreak's activities!
But, hasn't Daybreak been
burning a bunch of teams' banners?
Only because those banners belonged to bad teams!
But now, because Blackout instigated them,
the bad teams are all trying
to get in Daybreak's way!
Blackout is the boss of the bad teams!
"The boss"?
If anyone's the boss of bad teams, it's Daybreak!
Wow, the festival! The fireworks are amazing!
Daybreak is working towards an environment
where everybody can fight equally!
Whoa, these flutes! Such sweet flute sounds!
Daybreak is working towards an environment
where everybody can fight equally!
Ooh, there's a boom! Fireworks!
What's bad about that?!
You're mistaken about that!
The shrine's booming, too!
No, I am not mistaken!
Ooh, and take a look at--
Would you shut up?!
Hold it, calm down!
This isn't like you!
Remember what Blackout does at times like this?
That's it!
We'll settle this with a Cardfight!
Is here okay?
Yeah.
I'll be assisting her.
Just fight the way you usually do, Yu-yu.
All set up, right?
Yes.
Stand up, Vanguard!
I ride Rino.
He discards Cho Kuu Sha
from his hand, and rides Rino.
Rino? I see...
I ride Namorkahr.
With its skill, I add Swayanbuh
from my deck to my hand.
So that's how...
You identify them with stickers.
My Vanguard attacks.
No guard.
Damage check... Arcs.
Not only that, you memorize all the cards?
I ride Reiyu.
With Rino's skill, I call Trickstar.
Back left.
Miss Minae...
...did you used to have Trickstar in your--
What?
It's nothing!
Really, it's nothing.
So, what was that again?
Oh, it was noth--
I did used to have Trickstar in my deck.
I could hear what you meant.
Say, check this out!
Oh, wow!
Totally hilarious, yeah?!
What's with this girl?!
Was that a stratagem?
An attempt to bewilder me with laughter?
My turn is over.
I have to act nice.
They're Danji's friends,
so they couldn't be bad people.
They couldn't be...
Oh, um, sorry? Maybe you
should look for a different team.
Uh, say...
Are you all right?
Why do you ask? I'm just fine!
Thank goodness!
I ride Nirvana.
OverDress!
Yeah, when people are in conflict,
it really does work best to resolve it with cards.
Why?
Because this way, we can become better friends!
Since we're playing the same game.
What's with those stickers?
Aren't they against the rules?
And we can go to the festival together, too!
Do you really want to do that?
Yes, I do.
Why?
Sorry, I'm too busy.
We'll play there instead.
Let's stop for a moment.
I've finally seen... your defeat.
I ride Bavsargra.
I place Aadhitya as Right Deity Arms.
Its skill activates.
During this turn, I can Arm an
additional Order card.
Swayanbuh!
Bavsargra's skill!
I retire all my opponent's front row rear-guards!
And it gets an extra critical!
Wha?!
Kick them away!
I call!
Bavsargra attacks your Vanguard!
I guard!
Halibadra attacks.
No guard!
Halibadra attacks!
My turn is over.
Persona Ride!
With Nirvana's skill, I call
Trickstar from the Drop Zone!
OverDress!
And now, another overDress!
Exspecta!
Clinch it this turn!
I'll tell you about the conclusion I saw.
On this turn, not a single one
of your attacks will get through to me.
And next turn,
I'll defeat you with a single attack.
I won't let that happen!
Nirvana attacks!
With Swayanbuh's skill,
Bavsargra gets +10,000 power.
I guard.
Twin drive!
Critical trigger!
Exspecta attacks!
Perfect guard.
Toresa attacks!
I guard.
My turn is over.
Say...
Will you be friends with me?
Of course!
I mean, that's the reason
I'm having a Cardfight with you!
Liar.
I place Prithivih as Right Deity Arms!
Mow them down!
Vairina's alone again!
I used to have that same deck.
But I switched to this.
Have you seen this card before?
Trickstar?
It's Trickmoon.
DressBoost! +20,000 power!
Now I'll show you real power.
Next turn, I'll defeat you with a single attack.
Bavsargra attacks!
Nirvana!
With Prithivih's skill, it gets +10,000 power!
For 48,000 total!
Burn them to ash.
Hey... about Yu-yu's deck...
Did you need to say such things about it?
Let's go.
You don't need to come.
It's just past twelve o'clock already.
Game Over, Danji!
Can't you see our queen is furious?
If you're gonna be one of us,
you really need to do better!
Masanori?!
Now, let us return to Daybreak...
...Miss Mirei Minae.
Daybreak...
Mirei... Minae...
"Hello-break, Daybreak!
I am your leader: Mirei!"
Bro...
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
I am your leader: Mirei!
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'll introduce
my deck's shadow leader, Trickmoon!
A Piece of Soul
You see, Trickmoon can use a skill
that only helps Bavsargra: DressBoost!
When boosted this way, Bavsargra gains
+10,000 power for each card it has armed!
Trickmoon is the partner
supporting me from the shadows!
Huh? You say it's similar to some other card?
No, that can't be right.
My Trickmoon is much more powerful!
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Your Name
Reminiscence