Tonbo.
I...
I moved my ball!
I know you did!
All you need to do is take a penalty
stroke and put the ball back where it was!
Good luck!
That's not it.
You don't get it, Tonbo.
You moved your ball?
You mean before your last shot?
You moved your ball during your swing
but hit it anyway. Was that it?
Yes.
In that case, you don't have to put it
back where you found it.
Just take the penalty stroke
and play it where it is.
A penalty stroke?
That'll put you at four-on.
I... I lied again.
But that will mean the mistake I didn't
pay for yesterday will be paid for today.
I'm just being selfish again. But...
I do feel a bit better now.
You're going to have to take things
seriously from here on out!
Take things seriously?
You're in the middle of a heated
competition! Don't you want to win?
You've been searching for others' balls.
and taking super risky shots
that could cost you the whole game!
It doesn't seem like
you're trying to win at all!
The chance is dangling
right in front of you!
You need to give this 100%!
100%?
That's right! You need to change it up!
Change it up?
What does
giving 100% even mean?
This girl was six strokes behind
but has somehow tied up for the top spot.
Even with the wind and conditions
being as awful as they are.
You want me to change it up?
No.
I was wrong.
You don't need to change your game.
Play the way you always do.
I want to see more of it.
I think the answer as to why
I keep failing the pro test
lies in your golf game, Tonbo.
In my game?
Yeah.
It's not all about winning.
It's...
It's like you're playing
for something else!
I don't understand a word you're saying.
Anyway, there's still five holes left!
What I mean is it'd be a waste
if you didn't at least try to win!
Got it!
Is beating people really that important?
I just want to get better at golf!
That's it! That's all that really matters!
She's challenging herself
to get better at golf.
That's the only thing
that needs paying attention to.
I got a double bogey.
This is the first time her score
has changed in the second half.
I just can't let my score fall first.
I'm fully determined.
Finally. We're tied for the top.
The direction of the wind
is finally fixed in place.
It's a tailwind. This is it.
I'll be able to play
to my fullest on this hole.
The last par 5 of the day.
This hole will be the key to victory.
Ema's high balls have
an incredible amount of backspin.
On a windy day like today,
that’s become her worst enemy.
With the wind like this, a tailwind will
get rid of the small turns the ball makes.
It will push the ball forward.
This is it. This is my chance.
This is my only chance!
She finally did it!
I've got to do it!
Now!
There's 260 yards
to the center of the bunker.
Even with this tailwind...
Amazing.
-Nice.
-Thanks.
A creek?
Ema's not the only one depending
on making this hole the key to victory.
I get the feeling that whoever
gets a birdie on this whole
is going to be the winner.
To get the birdie with today's
pin position, the ball will
the ball will need to stop
as soon as it lands.
That won't be easy with this tailwind.
Rather than approaching
the green from close by,
a long shot will be easier to spin.
In regards to where
that long shot should be taken from,
I'll have to be wary of the bunker
that lies 100 yards from the hole.
If it goes in the bunker on my
second shot, I won't get the birdie.
I've got to find a route that prevents me
from going into the bunker.
If I plan to stop before the bunker,
it’ll be 140 yards.
I'll have to hit the ball 220 yards twice.
I can hit the ball around
200 yards with my creek.
Even with a tailwind,
it won't reach the bunker.
It's like the bunker isn't even there.
I can hit this shot free of pressure.
This is the best plan to get the birdie.
If the ball goes where I want it to,
my third shot will be
from around 110 yards.
It'll be easy for me to land the ball
near the pin. More than it will for Ema.
I'll keep fighting till the end.
My current score and position
are the real me.
I have to see how far I can really go
Tilting the tee like that will create
resistance, causing the ball to spin more.
She'll be able to utilize the wind.
Hinoki hasn't given up just yet.
I can't believe it stopped here.
It might as well have gone in the bunker.
What are you talking about?
If you had done that,
the tree might have gotten in the way.
From here you won't hit the tree,
but you'll have to hit the ball
from inside the bunker.
You'll have to stand on your tippy toes.
Even with the tailwind,
your sand wedge won't be enough.
You'll have to use the nine iron.
I'll use... this one!
Your six iron?!
Th-- What?!
I'll have to use the nine and hit it thin!
I see. So she can hit it
farther with a short iron.
If she stands on her toes, it'll be easier
to tilt the club face to the left.
I usually like to carry
one large club like this,
but I never thought to carry two or three.
Oh no. I thought it'd hook a bit but it
went totally straight.
What are you talking about?
That was a sick shot!
Sick?
It means amazing!
She used the creek again.
She's trying to stop the ball
in front of the bunker.
I see. So her third shot
will be a full swing.
Tsubura is the only one in this game
who truly understands the course.
Only 50 more yards.
Alright.
Amazing.
240 yards to the edge of the green.
Even with the tailwind,
to get it there in two shots...
Even if she gets it there,
she won't be able to get it over the
bunker to the pin with a spoon.
She'll have to avoid the bunker
and aim for the fairway.
If she doesn't, it'll roll too far
when it hits the green.
If it doesn't go far enough,
she'll have to hit it over the bunker.
Either way, it won't be easy
to get the birdie.
Tsubura.
Your course management is incredible.
But I'll also say this.
All you do is avoid
the dangers of the course.
A direct line to the pin?
The strain is too much.
My left ankle can't take much more.
If she hits putting that much
weight on her right leg,
the club will hit the ground!
My spoon has a wide sole.
I won't hit the ground
no matter how high up I hit it from.
It doesn't matter how high it goes.
I've just got to hit it the best I can.
That's all I have left to do.
What matters is direction. I need to
drop it within two yards of the pin.
The reference shot is a push draw.
A push draw is hitting
outside your target line.
On top of that, I'll swing the club
even wider than usual.
The more the shaft aims towards the
direction you want the ball to go,
the easier it is to create
an inside-out flight path.
This is the perfect set up!
She did it!
But it's too far left!
Come back!
Oh no. If it drops in there...
She hit it from there? She got a two-on?!
Ema!
That was great!
You're this close!
Yeah!
Tsubura.
Golf is a game of chance for you,
isn't it?
Shots that have a low success rate
have a zero percent chance
if you don't try.
But if you try, anything is possible.
You win by going on the offense.
Not with logic and reasoning.
You have to fight
at the crucial moment to win.
That's what I learned
playing golf in America.
I went to take a look.
You've got 116 yards to the pin.
Thank you.
It looked like 120,
but it didn't go quite far enough.
Somewhere between a
pitching wedge and nine-iron.
I can avoid the bunker with a nine-iron.
Hitting with the ball softly with a large
club will make it lose head speed.
If that happens, the impact energy will be
reduced, as well as the backspin.
It's only five or six yards.
Because my calculations were off,
my plan to hit a full shot on my third
stroke has been foiled.
I'll have to hit it gently.
If I can make impact without a single
blade of grass getting in the way,
even with a 9-iron...
With an eight-iron or below,
I've honed the accuracy of my short irons
so that I can aim dead on the pin.
Incredible. So this is
what it means to carry the ball.
Hit it as far as possible
with a driver from the tee,
and get the ball close to the green
with a wood on the second shot.
That's how most golfers
would play on a par five.
Hinoki's shots, approach
and putts certainly aren't ordinary,
but honestly, it doesn't scare me.
The higher the ball goes up,
the more the wind affects the spin.
We're on the same line.
Ema will see my line.
This should guarantee an eagle for her.
I have to get this.
If I miss,
Ema will have a two stroke lead.
That's not good for the final four holes.
I'm starting to lose my touch
from being nervous.
It's downhill. I have to
be careful with my speed.
Just like I thought!
She forgot about the wind.
Don't mind if I do.
I saw the line.
This is it. I can finally take the lead.
She hit it too hard.
The person who wins this hole wins it all.
Ema and I both knew that.
But I was aiming for the birdie.
Ema was aiming for an eagle!
Ema?
They're on the last three or four holes.
Now the real fun begins.
We could see a chemical reaction.
A chemical reaction?
This is Tonbo's first-ever competition.
On the last day, she may have been
able to have fun on the first fourteen,
But after that,
caught up in a heated battle,
this could be her first real game of golf.
Oh no.
"Real golf?"
The heart sways between
wanting and not wanting.
In competitive golf, that is.
I'm excited to see what she decides.
She went in the right side
woods on eleven,
and the right side bunker on fourteen.
Of the five courses she
used her driver in the second half,
she didn't land on the fairway
for three of them.
Could it be...?
That I was missing something?
Is it farther in here?
Ema got right next to the pin on her
second shot on hole fourteen.
She probably got an eagle.
That puts her at three under.
I see.
So I'm three strokes behind.
Don't sound so relaxed.
If you make a mistake on this hole,
you'll be down by four.
Down by four with three holes left.
You won't be able to win.
In other words, don't hit a bogey
if you still want to win.
If I still want to win...
Don't act like you don't know it!
You know it's true.
You're feeling pressure!
You're just pretending you don't realize
it!
You want to win right?
Don't you imagine what that's like?
Tonbo.
You're from an island
called Tokara, right?
Yes.
Think about how happy
everyone would be if you won.
You want to make them happy.
You don't want to let them down.
That's only normal.
Don't act like you don't get it!
Acting like I don't get it...
Ignoring the pressure is
the worst thing you can do under pressure.
I know it's hard acknowledging
that you're scared.
I know it's not cool.
I know I'm talking down to you, but it's
why I failed the pro test four times.
Tonbo! You need to acknowledge that
pressure and face it head on!
Only those who can do that
make it to the top.
That's golf!
Acknowledge the pressure.
Face it head on.
A divot mark...
As long as the club
doesn't go into the back edge,
there's enough space
to hit the ball, but...
What kind of divot mark is this?
It's probably from someone
on the eighteenth hole
trying to get the ball
back onto the fairway.
What a terrible shot!
The turf is all messed up!
I've got an open shot to the green.
Yeah.
It's not far away, either.
Around ninety, I bet.
But...
With this divot mark
you can't aim it to the green.
No matter what angle you use to hit,
the ground will get between
the ball and club.
Getting it over the bunker won't be easy,
either.
I can hit it the same
direction as the divot.
But at this rate...
my score will go down.
I won't be able to win.
Huh?
What is this? I want to win.
Everyone on the island
will be so happy if I win.
I want to make them happy. I want to win.
Golf is a game of pressure.
The reason being,
You "want" to get par.
"Want" to get on the green.
"Want" to hit it. There are many wants.
You "don't want" to hit it out of bounds.
You "don't want" three putts.
You "don't want" to duff.
You have to focus on the "wants" and
"don't wants" to hit the ball.
In other words, the things
you get from success,
and the things you lose from failure.
The bigger each of those things become,
the more nervous people get.
That's what we call pressure.
I get it now.
I'm nervous.
I'm under pressure.
That's the only way.
Don't hit it too hard.
Stop it before the bunker.
This isn't the only way. However...
However, this is my best chance.
What's wrong?
I don't care about chance.
By acknowledging the pressure I'm under,
I'm ready to face it head on.
Don't hit it that way!
I may fail.
This is a scary shot.
This is the first time
I've ever felt this.
I get it now.
So this is real golf.
Don't swing it that hard!
Come on. Crab ball!
An intentional shank?!
Please! Get there!
No way.
Alright!
We're almost at the last hole.
That's right. Just be yourself.
I will! Watch me, Igaiga!
On the next episode of Tonbo.
Tonbo, Hole Out
Don't take your eyes off
for even a second.
Your face is so scary I can't concentrate!
Tonbo!