Here it comes!
Whoa!
It's coming from this way now!
This wind is out of control!
Looks like the group ahead finished up!
The wind here is different
than on the green.
It's blowing the complete
opposite direction now.
It's not just
changing directions either.
With today's pin position,
even if you miss the pin
to the to the left,
an uphill approach is left.
Getting par should be easy.
Even if I give advice on where to
aim, it won't be easy with this wind.
Not even Tonbo will be able to use
this wind to her advantage.
It's hard to play the wind when you
can't read its direction.
The only judgement we can make
is choosing which club to use.
No...
Tonbo has been holding that club
for a while now.
She knew which one
she wanted to use from the start.
Does that mean she's able to read the
wind even as it changes this much?
The wind is playing.
It's just like golfing on the island.
The three iron.
150 yards to the pin.
Is she reading it as a head wind?
I never wore a hat when I
played on the island.
My hair was always
blowing like this.
Igaiga is here too!
The ground is hard.
This is so much fun!
What kind of a swing was that?
She's rolling it?
She's avoiding the wind altogether!
Did I just...?
A hole-in-one?
Guess not.
The ball ended up
in the best spot possible.
I never would have
thought to do that.
Even if thought of it,
I wouldn't do it!
It feels like I can't call that cool...
Can I even call it real golf?
Wait... who am I to judge?
Who am I to decide what real golf is?
Nice par.
Thank you.
Tonbo has par.
Her total is still an even par.
She made it through
this difficult hole with ease.
It seems like it's blowing
mainly to the right.
Seven iron please.
I'll take a bet on that.
No. The wind is blowing to the left.
It changed to a head wind.
This will be the end for all of us.
Tonbo will take the lead!
No.
If I persevere, I can get ahead
of Ema and Hinoki.
I can take the lead!
To make that happen...
A spoon?
That's...
She's doing it Tonbo's way.
She aimed for the same spot.
I can't afford to hold back.
I'm going to win this!
She hits her wedge and putter with
her right hand. And she's good.
I'm up.
She hits hard,
but perhaps her previous play style
used delicate techniques.
They can't afford to
let their guard down for a second.
I think I'm holding up well.
Even so, the seventh hole
was the turning point.
We were all tied until then.
It looks like the
second group is done.
Yeah.
I wonder how Tonbo's first half went?
Only a few players so far
finished the first half
with a score in the thirties.
And the ones that did
did it before this wind picked up.
Everyone else was in the forties.
Even if she drops
five or six strokes,
she's still hitting average.
Thanks.
Igaiga is watching.
She's hitting her third stroke
from the fairway.
We're right behind the pin.
Should we move?
How do you think
she'll hit it from there?
She has about a
thirty-five yard approach.
She doesn't have to
do anything special.
She needs to focus on distance,
but that won't be easy
with this wind.
Even though it's a head wind?
If she hits too hard and it
goes beyond the pin,
her fourth stroke
will be a downhill putt.
That will put the
wind behind the ball,
pushing the ball along strongly.
If it doesn't go in the cup,
the wind will carry it right over.
I see.
She's got to land it below the cup.
Even if it isn't perfect,
she'll have to leave an uphill putt.
That's her approach.
Igaiga is by my side. Alright.
Oh, Tonbo.
Alright! Right on target!
I knew it.
You knew it?
She often did that on the island.
By hitting a full lob
against the wind,
the ball falls down
and stops dead in its tracks.
Tonbo gets a kick out of that one.
I was trying to scare Igaiga.
Why didn't you just roll it?
No one in their right mind
would lob it here!
Alright! My first birdie!
Did Tonbo chip it in?
A birdie?
She's tied with Ema and I.
Your first birdie, huh?
It is quite windy.
How many bogies did you get?
None.
You're one under?
Yeah!
So nobody achieved
a green in regulation.
Even for the last group,
no one is playing
very well in this wind.
She opened the face up.
Is she going to lob it?
No. Only Tonbo would
take a risk like that.
That's enough! Stop!
I'm going to mark it!
That was a fine approach.
Indeed.
This is a critical moment.
If my score drops below Tsubura's
I have no chance of winning.
If I can keep my game up until
Tsubura's own score drops
I'll be able to apply pressure
and find my momentum!
I can't lose my nerve!
Everything has been going well so far.
I need to finish the first half
with my two-stroke lead.
It's a shank!
This is it.
Things are turning in my favor.
This will be
a double-bogey for Tsubura.
I'm enjoying my opponent's mistakes.
I'm hoping for trouble.
But why?
Why can't I stay positive?
Why can't I focus on
just being the best I can be?
Hinoki.
No practice swing?
I don't like this version of myself.
I'm know I'm going to pay for being mean.
I knew it, this is my punishment!
Or... maybe it isn't.
They said I'm the only one
to finish the first half under par!
So it seems.
Aren't you happy, Igaiga?
Why are you acting like that?
Believing this is the half way point
of the game is too leisurely!
In professional golf, it's not
halfway over until the tenth!
The final three holes require as much
or even more energy
than the previous fifteen.
Jeez.
I thought Igaiga
would be proud of me.
But I guess not.
You never know.
Tonbo finished the first half
under par!
She's only one stroke
behind the leader!
She might actually have a chance!
I've got to tell everyone!
Wait.
Bunpei doesn't have a phone.
Who can I send a message to?
I know!
Yes?
This is Toshima Village City Hall.
H-hello, the name's Igarashi.
I work at the
Hinoshima Development Center.
They call me "Igaiga" on the island.
Right...
Attention. This is the
Toshima Village Disaster Center.
We have an emergency
broadcast from a man named Igaiga.
Igaiga?
However, I have absolutely
no idea what he's talking about.
While quite out of the ordinary,
he told me it's very important.
I will now share with you exactly
what he told me to say:
Tonbo has closed the gap
to just one stroke
behind the leader at the end
of the front nine on the final day!
Or... something.
Bunpei! Did you hear
the announcement?
Can't you call me "honey" or
something like that?
Isn't it great?
Aww, Yoko!
I repeat:
Tonbo has closed the gap
to just one stroke
behind the leader at the end
of the front nine on the final day!
And so concludes our broadcast.
Yes!
Hinoki!
Where's Hinoki!
Excuse me, sir!
You can't come in
the clubhouse dressed like that!
Hinoki!
Where are you?
If I tell him I hit forty...
You've held your top position
despite this powerful wind.
You have no reason
to be looking so down!
You played wonderfuly.
Superintendant Nakase...
Just leave it to me.
Hinoki!
Where are you, Hinoki?
Mr. Otoha.
Please leave here at once.
If you continue to cause trouble,
I will have to resort
to drastic measures.
Drastic?
I may not look it, but I have
a strong sense of justice.
This is my golf course!
If you don't listen to what I say,
you'll pay the price!
Hinoki has moved onto
the second half in the top position.
She has?
Very well.
If only that were the truth.
Even if I'm able to win,
I can't win by only one stroke.
Even if I had taken a one stroke
penalty back then, I could have won.
That's why I have to get two strokes
ahead. I have to win by two strokes!
I don't see Tonbo on the fairway.
Did you find it?
Here it is!
She's not out of bounds,
but even if she gets on the fairway,
she'll use her third stroke
to get on the green
She'll have to make it in one putt.
This could hurt her score.
No matter where you hit it,
you'll have to aim low
to avoid the branches.
The widest spot is over here,
but there's a bunker.
The right side of the woods is a
depression set back from the fairway.
Getting on the fairway will be tough.
She could get a bogey or worse.
Don't worry about getting par.
Just make sure
you don't get a double bogey.
Where are you aiming?
That's way too far to the right!
Even farther than the green!
There's no way.
Are you trying to hit it through
that little opening?
There's no way!
Any farther and
it'll go out of bounds!
It went though!
Turn, turn, turn!
It turned!
It's on the green!
It rolled!
It disappeared!
You'll need a provisional ball.
Oops.
I'm hitting a provisional ball!
Let's get it right this time!
If you hurt yourself
any more than this...
A provisional ball.
Next will be her fourth stroke.
One to the fairway,
then on the green in five.
Two putts could give
her a double bogey.
If that happens,
the all-powerful Tonbo will be
dropped from the competition.
The bunker is a safe spot.
There's still 180 yards. That should
be no problem for y--
You're aiming for the green again?
And you're aiming up this time?
Again?
Is she insane?
I can't hope for others' failure.
Tonbo. That's enough!
It's getting narrower.
And wider again.
The next time it sways...
Now!
Go! Robin ball!
Alright! Right by the pin!
No way!
She can finish with a bogey?
I found my first ball!
And it's in a good spot, too!
I'll finish first!
After all that commotion.
She got a par after all.
I think that's it.
It stopped too soon.
There's still a long putt left.
It's totally stuck.
If it came down, I'd be able to
hit is as my second stroke.
I'll try shaking the tree.
Wait.
If the ball that falls down
really is yours,
you'll get a penalty stroke
for moving the ball.
You'll have to put it back, too.
That's...
If you're going to do it,
if it is your ball, you'll have to
declare it as unplayable first.
And if I do that?
Without going closer to the pin,
you can drop it straight down
and within two club lengths
of where it was,
or drop it alone the extended line
from the spot to the cup.
You can take your
third short from there.
That way I'll be able to
aim for the green.
That's much better
than the other options.
If it is my ball,
then I'm calling it unplayable!
Come on! Get down here!
Why won't it come down? If it doesn't
come down I won't be able to win!
Is your ball stuck, Hinoki?
Tonbo!
I have to make sure
it really is my ball first!
Then let's take a look!
Tonbo.
Was it a Callaway?
That's the one! It's mine!
I'll drop it down.
Tonbo!
Are you okay, Tonbo?
Here!
Tonbo! What are you doing?
You've still got a putt left!
Okay!
Do your best, everyone!
She came all the way
here to find your ball?
Tonbo is always like that.
Even when we were
practicing on the course,
she ran all over
looking for lost balls.
And look at me.
I've even messed with the score just to
win ahead of Tonbo.
Is this really who
you want to be, Hinoki?
You're too out of breath to putt!
Did Tonbo miss the par putt?
Her first bogey?
It's my fault.
She came to find my ball.
She did it for me. I...
I...
Tonbo!
Tonbo.
I...
I moved my ball!
Emma.
Have you ever felt pressured before?
I'm always suffering from it during matches.
I'm really feeling it right now.
What's wrong?
On the next episode of Tonbo!
First Time Under Pressure
I've got pressure in my tummy
from all that breakfast!
That's called eating too much.