Here you go!
It's delicious!
What is this?
I've never had anything like it!
You won't find a shop like this
on Hinoshima Island.
It's so good!
The meat just melts in your mouth!
You're very kind.
I've never seen a customer look so happy.
Have some more meat, on the house.
She couldn't stop crying on the ferry.
It's great to see her finally smiling.
The city at night looks like
it's been flooded with light.
There are more people downtown
than the island's entire population.
And the transportation...
It must all be so fresh
and exciting for Tonbo.
You came to Kagoshima to get
a cavity filled once, right?
Back then,
I stood behind Grandpa Gon
and barely noticed my surroundings.
This is the bullet train? It's so long!
This is Kumamoto Station.
Thank you for riding the bullet train.
Watch your feet as you exit the train.
Mr. Udo runs a driving range, right?
That's right.
He let me use it a lot
when I was a pro golfer.
What are they like?
Well, how should I put it?
The mother has a dirty mouth,
but is strong-willed.
The father is a passionate man
who raised his kids to be pro golfers.
They're a lively bunch. You'll see.
Even at this hour, it's still so bright!
So this is where I'll be practicing.
Let's go.
There you are.
Sorry we're late.
Is that her, then?
I'm Tonbo Oi.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
So those are the eyes of someone
raised only looking at the horizon?
Not bad.
Where is your carry bag, dear?
This is everything.
-What? Only four clubs?
-Huh?
That's right.
I bet you're eager to play.
Everyone on the island
would be sleeping by now,
but people here are practicing golf!
Are they training to be pros?
I wonder?
Mr. Igarashi!
It's been a while!
Hey, Hajime.
He's their son.
He's the lesson pro here.
So you're Tonbo?
Nice to meet ya.
It's a pleasure to meet you, too.
What a shot!
Let's see what you've got.
A driver?
Igarashi was so eager to have you here.
You must have some skill.
But, I can't be sure
until I see it with my own eyes.
If you don't have the skills,
we'll have to forget about taking you in.
Mr. Udo, wait just a second!
Okay!
It's huge! And long!
It looks like real grass!
But it feels totally different!
Tonbo has never hit a driver before.
A baseball grip?
When she first used
an eight-iron at Kuta's place,
she picked up on its characteristics
with one practice swing.
Thank you very much.
It's automatic? Amazing!
Where should I hit the ball?
What direction should I aim?
Well,
how about aiming
right between those two steel towers?
And what kind of ball?
What kind?
From here to there? Or more like this?
Well, how about a draw?
Okay!
When asked to demonstrate a shot,
most people would aim for the tee.
I've never been asked about
a draw or a fade before.
Having mastered the game
on the course instead of a driving range,
Tonbo only knows
how to take shots based on direction.
What kind of stance is that?
Does she have it confused with a fade?
No.
With the ball slightly inside,
left shoulder raised a bit
and hands leading the setup,
her upper body is ready to hit a draw.
She moved her left hand
to the closed position.
Incredible looping.
Continue.
Those are some nice sounding shots!
But she's slicing it every time.
Are you sure about this?
Taking care of a kid like this.
All of Tonbo's clubs are old.
Even among the latest drivers,
this one stands out for its length
and large head.
Due to the enormous volume
at the end of the shaft,
there's a significant force
when trying to open the face.
The effect only intensifies
when you swing.
I sliced it again.
Masterfully designed to minimize spin,
This club ensures that even if you miss,
the ball won't turn too much.
For a player like Tonbo
who intentionally curves the ball,
this is a challenging club.
I never knew drivers
were so difficult to use.
She sounds like
she's never hit a driver before.
This is her first time at a driving range
and first time using a driver.
Really?
That's enough.
I'll have you try again tomorrow.
Okay.
This will be your bedroom.
It's getting late.
Why don't you get some sleep?
Thank you very much.
Really? So,
when will you return to the island?
The next ferry to Tokara
is the day after tomorrow.
Hajime.
What was your impression of the girl?
Of Tonbo?
It's true my father loves golf,
but he doesn't know
a thing about swinging.
He raised his kids to be pro
with passion more than theory.
Mr. Igarashi.
Did you make her practice
hitting low balls from a high tee?
I'm curious.
Tonbo's swing has a tendency
to either have horizontal head motion,
or somewhat of a down swing.
Her swing doesn't have a scooping motion.
Hajime.
I'm relieved you're here.
Take care of Tonbo.
Tonbo must be so disappointed.
What is this?
The mattress is so thick! This is so fun!
This is delicious!
It all looks incredible!
So this is what a pancake looks like?
Very good.
Those who smile and savor delicious food,
and those who eat most will thrive.
It's so good!
Our driving range
is open to junior players.
There's a group of youngsters
around the same age as you.
I'll be taking them
to a nearby course this afternoon.
They let us play nine holes
after the usual players
are done for the day.
A course?
I hear you've never
been on a real course before.
Mr. Igarashi told me.
Wanna come with us?
Yes, please!
There are already so many people here.
Who could have done this?
There's no way
it was the men in this house.
That's pretty impressive!
Alternating between draws and fades.
How about this one?
Think you could give it a try?
Is that a driver?
Try a draw first, would you?
When I try to hit it like my three iron,
I slice it every time.
To hit a draw with this club,
I'll have to make contact like this,
and release like this.
Well done!
So she can hit a draw if she tries?
So I really do have to have to aim
for a strong hook to get it just right.
It's so different from all my clubs.
It feels so weird!
No good.
When the head is easy to rotate,
you can move it during your swing
and make better contact with the ball.
The perfect driver for someone like Tonbo
who uses the face to direct the ball.
Over here, everyone!
Meet your new friend.
From Tokara--
I'm Tonbo Oi!
It's a pleasure to meet y--
Try this one!
More drivers? Why?
That's what the boss taught us.
The boss?
Mr. Udo, of course!
It's normal to start with a wedge
and work your way up to longer clubs,
but the boss always asks,
"What's the first club you always use?"
"Your driver!"
That's why he starts
our practice with drivers.
"To be a good golfer,
you've got to change the way you think."
Not bad, right? Sounds like him.
This one, too.
Thank you.
Kids are brutally honest
when it comes to skill.
Always judging who's better or worse,
and openly dismissing
anyone they consider inferior.
Alright!
But she isn't fazed at all.
That's the stance. Alright!
The sakura have already fallen in Tokara,
but here in Kumamoto
they're in full bloom!
Where's your carry bag?
This is all my stuff right here.
For real?
How do you plan on playing the course?
Hinoki!
Hinoki.
Don't forget what I told you
about keeping your hands near your body.
I don't want you
getting more than one over today.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
Adaniya Tsubura will be
starting high school this spring.
We can't let a freshman
take the Kyuushuu Junior title.
Yes, sir.
Tsubura sure is famous!
Hello, Hinoki!
Hello.
Your outfit is so cute, Hinoki!
Thank you.
I've never seen you before.
Yes, right.
I'm Hinoki Otoha.
A sophomore in high school.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Tonbo Oi.
Last year,
Hinoki won the Kyuushuu Junior Open!
She's the best junior player
in the whole prefecture.
Okay! Let's go!
Let's go greet the caddy master.
START ROOM
Alright. Be sure to fix your divots.
Yes, sir!
S-sir!
Hey, you.
Where's your cap?
I don't have one.
She doesn't have one?
Wearing a hat is proper manners.
I didn't know that.
I've never played golf
with a hat on before.
I have an extra one.
You can keep it.
You don't have to do that.
It's fine.
I have plenty of them.
Thank you so much.
So that's how you wear it!
What a beautiful green!
Look at her!
What's wrong?
Maybe I should give you my visor instead.
Thanks.
Alright! Let's start!
Wow!
It's huge! And green!
And beautiful!
Alright!
Let's start in order!
This isn't good.
The wind carried the ball away.
It's really blowing out there.
A gentle breeze.
I don't want you
getting more than one over today.
Nice shot!
Way to go, Hinoki!
Rather than trying to battle the wind,
she hit it gently!
Okay, Tonbo!
It's your course debut!
Okay!
Her course debut?
She's never played a course before?
Everyone has to start somewhere.
Poi!
What's she doing?
Isn't she going to tee up?
She's using a three iron?
There's no way she can hit it like that!
There it is.
She's pushing the ball
into the ground? Why?
Hitting a three iron will be hard enough.
And now she's pushing the ball down?
The left side is out of bounds.
But her stance is totally pointed left!
She's going to slice it
if she hits like that.
No...
Her shoulder line is closed.
She's aiming for the right edge
of the fairway. Or even the rough.
She's pointed at that sakura tree.
Both shoulders parallel to the horizon.
If I can hit it out to that tree,
I'll be protected from the wind.
Here I go!
It's so low!
The swallow maneuver!
Keep rolling! Keep rolling!
What?
It doesn't roll
like on the island course.
How'd she make it roll like that?
That's why she dug
the ball into the ground.
What?
By positioning the ball lower,
grass gets between the club
and ball on impact.
This helps reduce some of the backspin.
Is she really able to calculate that?
I thought she was going to
top that shot for sure.
A top shot
wouldn't make a divot, obviously.
How did she hit her three iron
farther than my drive?
My ball is behind hers, too.
The wind is getting stronger.
It's like the cherry winds!
The cherry winds?
On this island, there's an east wind
that blows during sakura season.
We call it the "cherry wind"!
No matter how hard it blows,
it always feels so nice and smooth.
I just love it!
First Tokara and now Kumamoto.
I get to experience it twice this year!
How did you know these were east winds?
It's your first time here.
How could you know the direction?
Everyone knows that!
The direction the sun comes up,
even shadows on the ground!
Anyone can do it?
I have heard that golfers who are good
with directions can also read the wind.
It's an acorn.
The ball might move if you pick it up.
There's an acorn
right where my club will land.
There's no telling
where the ball will go.
There's a headwind.
It'll make the ball turn.
I know what to do!
A five wood?
I've never seen one before.
Just how old is that thing?
If I hit it like this,
the acorn will get in the way.
I should position the ball towards
the toe of the club face,
and just slightly cover it.
Alright.
Where is she aiming?
What does she plan on doing?
Here we go, Tsubura!
She's aiming for the tree?
Make it over!
It went over!
Alright!
Keep on rolling!
Alright! This is too fun!
What kind of golf is this?
What the?
How did she do that?
Igaiga, what's a "parting gift?"
It's a present we give someone
to see them off.
See them off? I see.
Do your best, Tonbo.
On the next episode of Tonbo!
"Igaiga's Parting Gift".
Igaiga!
Don't say a thing, Tonbo.
It's hard for me, too.
I want my parting gift now!
Tonbo!