TONBO!
EPISODE 26: TONBO'S CHALLENGE
THE HEROINES OF KYUSHU
When she was little, Tonbo Oi moved to
Hinoshima in the Tokara Islands.
With her late father's beloved three-iron,
she began her journey with golf.
Her natural talent for golf flourished,
Tonbo went to high school in Kumamoto.
There, she achieved an incredible feat,
winning the Kyushu Women's Championship.
Now, she's returned to Hinoshima,
celebrated as a champion.
Hey, Igaiga. What's with the creepy face?
You're muttering away to yourself!
Ah! N-Nothing!
How's the sunset on Hinoshima
feel after all this time?
It's amazing, just like I remembered.
Hinoshima sure is a great place!
But I bet your time off the island
was pretty exciting.
Of course! It was
a whirlwind of excitement!
What stood out the most to me…
What was it?
The ramen we had in Kagoshima!
What?! Ramen?!
Here you go!
What is this? I've never
had anything like it!
Seriously, you never lose your appetite,
no matter where you are.
I was so nervous
on the way to Mr. Udo's house.
Didn't you doze off hard
on the bullet train?
I was blown away by how beautiful
the driving range he runs is.
And at night, it's so bright!
Mr. Udo and his wife
are also very cheerful.
Yes, the customers love his wife, Yaya.
Let's see what you've got.
A driver?
I was bewildered when he suddenly
asked me to use a driver.
Yeah, that really put me on edge.
Okay!
Using a driver is really difficult…
Oh, and speaking of Mr. and Mrs. Udo…
Yeah?
-The breakfast they served was so good!
-What?!
Is breakfast the first thing that comes
to mind when you think of them?
No-Not at all!
And their son, Hajime, is a golf coach.
Mr. Igarashi told me. Wanna come with us?
Yes, please!
Over here, everyone!
Meet your new friend. From Tokara--
I'm Tonbo Oi! It's a pleasure to meet y--
Try this one!
I'd never been around so many
people my age, so I was nervous.
And also,
Hinoki and I are only a year apart,
but she seems so grown-up.
That's the first friend
you made in Kumamoto, right?
I've never seen you before.
-Yes, right.
-I'm Hinoki Otoha.
A sophomore in high school.
Nice to meet you.
It's huge! And green! And beautiful!
Okay, Tonbo! It's your course debut!
Okay!
It's so low!
It was the first time you played
on a real course. How was it?
It's different from our island.
There are no strong sea winds,
and the ball rolls differently.
Just like playing on Mr. Kuta's
island course, it was so much fun!
Gaining new experiences
and trying new things.
-Just like Fukuta said.
-Yeah.
Alright! This is too fun!
A driver?
That's when you gave me a new club.
Ah… That's right.
What? Is there a problem?
It's 15,309 yen!
I was so happy with your parting gift!
I felt so embarrassed…
Y-Yeah…
-Um. That's pretty cheap.
-It's a used club, too.
Don't slice it there!
It'll go off the cliff!
C'mon! I hope I chose the right driver!
The swallow maneuver!
Alright!
I did it!
It went through!
Go! Flying fish ball!
Everyone was blown away
by your playing style.
I just played like I usually did, though.
It's your "usual" playing style
that blows me away as well.
Alright!
I didn't think we'd end up
at the same school.
I'm relieved!
I was nervous about
going to school on my own.
Why are you crying?
It's because you've grown
into a high school student…
Exchanging contact info with your senior…
You said something similar
at my graduation ceremony.
Igaiga, your nose is running!
A thirty-eight?
I said no more than one over!
That's when you suddenly
snapped at her father.
Yeah, I just lost my temper
for a second there.
And what makes you think
it was just a little breeze?
You were indoors weren't you?
How could you know?
In a scary face competition,
you'd win for sure.
Come on…
-A competition?
-Yes.
The Kyushu Women's Open is next month.
They're holding it at Chuo Country Club!
What are you going to do, Tonbo?
What do you mean?
Dad!
I was shocked I would be
participating in a tournament!
No way.
That's why Tonbo
left her island in the first place!
Hajime put in so much effort to help you.
I can't thank the Udo family enough.
I'm putting Tonbo
in the Kyushu Women's Open!
And wasn't there someone else
from the Udo family who helped you?
Someone else?
Who's there? Stay away from me!
Calm down, Tonbo!
So sorry to scare you.
This used to be my bedroom, actually.
Nikome Udo, a tour pro.
She returns home feeling down in the dumps
every time she fails to qualify.
I know that feeling all too well…
She gave me golf shoes
and she told me something very important
for being able to continue playing golf.
Do you want to be a pro someday, Tonbo?
-I'm not sure.
-I understand.
You've never even been
in a competition before.
That's okay.
First, you have to fall in love with golf.
That comes first.
Fall in love with golf.
When you really love something,
you can't help but do your best.
Good night.
Hinoki gave me a golfbag.
Hajime gave me a six-iron.
And someone from the country club
gave me a nine-iron.
Together with your three-iron,
that's seven clubs in total.
-That's called a half set.
-I know that!
A half set…
That's so cool. I feel like a pro!
I crossed paths with someone on
day one of the Kyushu Women's Open!
Tonbo!
It really is you!
Tsubura!
You're really here!
I'm going to high school in Kumamoto.
You're so brave. I'm so happy!
Igaiga. Grandpa Gon. Setsu. Yoko.
Bunpei. Hidaka.
My first tournament has started.
I wish I'd been there!
Don't worry. I hit the ball
all the way to the island.
Alright!
N-Nice eagle.
An eagle? That's one hell of a debut!
I wish I could have seen it!
I shouldn't have gone back to the island!
Hidaka and Bunpei would have been upset!
Mrs. Shima, from our group, was
playing for the third time already.
She's such a nice person.
I'm sorry. Am I causing trouble?
Ms. Matsuda, who was also in our group,
was off her game, and I was scared of her.
But then, Mrs. Shima said…
But you know,
you can't recover from
your mistakes all at once.
There's a whole 18 holes
to set things straight.
If you're at the end of the game
and there's nothing left to do,
you still have your
whole life ahead of you.
If you can improve
your lifetime stroke average
even by one point, that's
something to be proud of!
My lifetime average?
What wise words…
Thanks to her words,
someone who I thought was scary,
suddenly became much more easygoing.
Wow! Number one! Incredible!
-I wish I could have seen it…
-Enough already!
Mrs. Shima…
-What a shame…
-Yes.
But she told me something very important.
Yes. It was good that you met her.
That's how much I love golf.
I'm so glad I got to play
with you, Mrs. Shima.
I'd love to play with you again someday.
Thank you, Tonbo.
It sure is crowded.
On the second day, I met someone new.
Ema Kurisu, a former
World Junior Champion.
A lefty?
She suffered a major left leg injury
and started playing
left-handed to overcome it.
I played a round with her,
Tsubura, and Hinoki.
Once again, I'll be your caddy, Hata.
I look forward to playing with you.
Thank you.
Ema's determination really inspired me.
It reminded me of when Tsubura shared
her dreams back on Hinoshima.
Her passion for golf…
I can learn from that myself.
Everyone's got this
amazing dedication to the game.
In America, all sorts of scary creatures
live in the lakes on golf courses.
You mean, alligators?
I lost my ability to swing and
make shots as beautiful as yours.
However, it hasn't been all bad.
I'm happy to be able to play at all.
I'm grateful that I'm able to play golf.
I think that might be
my greatest strength.
On the second day, I scored 77,
10 strokes worse than my opening round…
That's when…
Tonbo!
What are you doing here?
You came to get me?
You're doing great.
You started crying then.
Were you that happy to see me?
No! Nothing like that. I…
I was just happy to see you
after all that time.
I missed the island.
-I was just hopesick!
-You surely mean "homesick"?
Remember that tool you used
to dispatch octopi and fish?
At first, I didn't understand your advice.
-But it worked!
-I know, right?!
Were you surprised when you heard
I was in first place on day one?
Actually, it didn't surprise
me all that much.
Oh?
I was happy more than anything.
And not only me.
Everyone on the island was smiling.
Everyone on the island is rooting for you.
It's like you've become
the pride of the whole island.
They're happy you're one of them.
Don't worry about your score!
Play your way! Show us
that special Tonbo style!
Okay!
Go! Flying fish ball!
What? That stance!
She avoided the sand!
What?
I knew that would work! This is so fun!
Igaiga is over there. Alright.
Alright! Right on target! Oh?
Alright! My first birdie!
If you make a mistake on this hole,
you'll be down by four.
Down by four with three holes left.
You won't be able to win.
In other words, don't hit a bogey
if you still want to win.
If I still want to win…
I was waiting for something
to spark inside of you.
Yeah. I could feel it
from the 15th hole onward.
What is this?
No. I want to win.
Everyone on the island
will be so happy if I win.
I want to make them happy. I want to win.
I get it now.
I'm nervous.
I'm under pressure.
I don't care about chance.
By acknowledging the pressure I'm under,
I'm ready to face it head on.
I may fail.
This is a scary shot.
This is the first time
I've ever felt this.
So this is real golf.
Come on. Crab ball!
Please! Get there!
No way.
Alright!
This was the hole where I first sensed
the pressure you warned me about.
And I felt that up to the final hole.
Tonbo…
But you know, whenever
I would overthink things,
I could hear you cheering me on.
Here I go.
Just like Igaiga told me.
You're not aiming for the fairway at all!
It's just like I told her.
The score doesn't matter.
Give it your all! Win this thing!
Thanks to you, I finally realized
the true meaning of golf.
So close!
Why didn't it go in?!
You jinxed it, Igaiga.
That was fun!
The last group was Tsubura,
Hinoki, Ema, and me.
Go through!
By the third day,
the strain on her leg had gotten worse.
I did it!
But Ema was holding back
the pain and fell down at the end.
That kind of mental resolve
is rare among players.
Still, competitions can be ruthless…
Yahoo!
Now it's the playoffs, Hinoki!
No. You're wrong.
What?
Hinoki.
Yesterday, on the fifth hole.
I made my ball move!
But I didn't report it!
But I kept playing. I continued on!
I…
…forfeit the game!
That must have been
such a difficult situation for Hinoki.
A foul is a foul, though.
It took a lot of guts to confess that.
She has my respect.
Same.
You talked to Hinoki with kind words
and Hajime encouraged her as well.
I was so happy for that.
Hinoki.
You're not going to quit, are you?
Tonbo.
I'm not quitting.
You know, Igaiga…
Since I left the island, I've
grown to love golf even more.
It's not about setting goals
or aiming for something.
Just loving the game is enough for me.
That's what I've realized.
I see.
And that means I'm going
to keep loving golf more and more!
Alright!
Let's eat Grandpa Gon's fish and
Setsu's cooking till we're stuffed!
Not training?
Typically Tonbo, huh?
Okay! Time for a bath and then dinner!
Alright!