Grandpa Gon's boat shot?
You did what?
During a round?
Yes. I did.
Nice!
Now that's what I like to hear!
That's the Tonbo I know.
I can just imagine their
faces when they saw that!
It's not that funny!
Tonbo hasn't changed at all. But...
Tonbo.
I want to see you take a shot.
Okay. Let's go.
Don't let your guard down just yet.
It's still only day two.
If you're not in first place
at the end it'll all be for nothing!
Hinoki.
She's still practicing.
Oh. You're starting now?
You're just grasping at straws.
Hinoki is six strokes ahead of you.
You're out of luck, I'm afraid.
Let's go home.
Right.
See you tomorrow!
Tonbo. I'm sorry. I have to win. I must.
Forgive me.
So you've added a six
and nine iron to your bag?
Who gave them to her?
My dad gave her the six iron,
and she got the nine iron
from Mr. Nakase at the country club.
Three, six, nine.
A wedge.
I'd say that counts
as a full set for Tonbo!
This will be a great setup for her.
Here I go. Starting with a swallow ball!
Osprey ball!
A thin slice!
Hajime.
You haven't trained her at all.
Why?
I wasn't able to.
I worry that if she adjusts even one thing
she'll end up having to adjust
every aspect of her game
I fear that would
throw Tonbo's game off entirely.
I want her to keep playing
with a free spirit.
Hajime.
I'm glad I put her in your care.
However,
since coming to Kumamoto, Tonbo
has been hitting from the mat every day.
That's starting to show in her swing.
Practice mats
become worn down in the center,
causing the left edge
to be slightly elevated.
Placing the ball there
creates a slight
uphill lie for the left foot.
That creates a small space
between the ground and the ball.
This is causing Tonbo's swing to relax.
Due to the slope of the mat, the right eye
is about half a ball's width lower
and the bridge of her nose
tilts to the right.
Tonbo.
Hit here.
Okay.
She's aligned her eyes
with the tilt of the turf.
She instinctively
adjusts her setup to match the lie.
This is one of Tonbo's many skills.
What changed? What did he change?
The trajectory got a bit lower.
Place the ball
wherever you like this time.
Do you have a hat?
Yeah, I have one.
Hinoki gave it to me.
Make sure both ends
of the bill are parallel.
Just make sure
the right end isn't lower.
It's okay if the left side is lower.
Got it.
Alright. Go!
The sound changed.
Igarashi has been watching her for solong.
He knows just what to adjust.
Tonbo.
Try hitting barefoot.
It tickles.
I knew it.
She's lifting her left big toe.
The toe she used to keep her grip
on the wet floor of the fishing boat.
Tonbo.
Remember that tool you used
to dispatch octopi and fish?
Yeah.
Imagine you're using that tool to pin
your toes to the ground when you hit.
That sounds painful!
It's just pretend!
We're not actually using it.
You mean I should stay still?
Right.
In a golf swing,
you must move some parts of your body
and keep others perfectly still.
The toes of your left foot mustn't move.
Right.
Got it.
Just like this.
The sound changed again.
That's it.
Even when you hit a fade,
don't forget to keep track of your toes.
You've got to focus on your feet,
not just your hips.
Right!
What is it?
Nothing.
I just thought,
you should be the one giving her lessons.
I just made a few minor adjustments.
If she puts too much strain
on her body to control her swing,
she'll be feeling it tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
You should lower the net down tonight.
The wind might start
blowing in the morning.
Ready to call it a night?
Yeah.
The weather report didn't mention that.
They mentioned rain.
Not the wind.
Igaiga.
He's becoming more like Grandpa Gon!
Stay here tonight.
No, I couldn't.
That's far too generous of you.
Because of all those foolish things you did
when you were playing for us,
my husband's reputation
was dragged through the mud.
Well, it's no matter.
Water under the bridge.
I couldn't.
You're taking care of Tonbo, too
I couldn't possibly ask of anything more.
I couldn't possibly ask you
to take care of me, too.
-I couldn't.
-You're already changing in pajamas!
How's Grandpa Gon doing?
Is he still sticking to only three drinks?
I can't speak on his drinking, but he's
doing just fine.
It's almost flying fish season, too.
The busiest time of the year.
I won't be able to help him fillet the
fish this year.
Tonbo.
About tomorrow,
strong winds will dry out the green.
-That's why--
-How's Setsu-ba?
I wish I could help her at the inn.
Making dinner by herself must be tough.
She's persevering like she always does.
What about Mom and Dad's grave?
It's lined with flowers every day.
I visit from time to time.
I see. Thank you.
Tonbo looked so happy.
Mr. Igarashi is like
a father to her, after all.
Really? Wataru is still playing golf?
Bunpei must be getting nervous!
Bunpei is doing just fine, too.
Bunpei and Yoko,
are they getting along?
I wonder if he still thinks of her
while he eats an ice cream after visiting
the hot springs?
Huh? Igaiga?
Thank you.
Thank you for coming.
Nikome!
Nana! Momoko!
We're in the same group this week!
I'm looking forward to it.
I am too!
By the way,
how's that girl doing?
She was in first place on the first day,
but fell off on the second.
I think she's in
fourth place with an even par.
She's only got seven, after all.
Seven?
Seven of what?
Seven clubs!
Huh? What?
It's the final day.
Hinoki Otoha is at six
under.
Tsubura Adaniya and Ema Kurisu
are both at five under.
They're the only three under par.
Tonbo Oi is in fourth place,
five strokes behind with an even par.
It seems like one of the
top three will likely take the win.
Although Tonbo Oi and
her half set of clubs
taking the victory at the very end
would have made for a better story.
It really is windy today!
Shut up!
Your weather report was way off.
You really are like Grandpa Gon!
I'm off!
Tombo is acting different today.
I know what it must be.
What is it?
Nothing.
Excuse me, could I get today's pin sheet?
They saved the most
difficult holes for the last day.
There are a lot of pins
placed near bunkers.
Emma is hitting the ball quite high.
Proof that her spin is incredible. She can
make the ball stop better than anyone.
She'll have the best chance
with today's pin positions.
I've finally got a chance to win.
I have to make it happen.
I've been waiting ten years for this.
I feel confident.
I'm only nervous...
...about one thing.
Were you surprised when you heard
I was in first place on day one?
Actually, it didn't surprise
me all that much.
Whatever.
I was happy more than anything.
Very happy.
And not only me.
Everyone on the island was smiling.
Everyone on the island is rooting for you.
It's like
you've become the pride
of the whole island.
You really are an island girl, Tonbo.
Everyone was happy. I made them smile.
I'm doing this for them.
Alright.
You must get three strokes under today.
If you can get your score
to nine under, you can't lose.
You'll make the playoffs.
Got it? Three strokes.
My goal is sixty-nine.
I'll try to get two strokes
under in the first half.
How unfortunate.
I won't be able to play with you today.
Today we're playing in groups of three.
You're with Tsubura's
last group today, right, Hata?
Who's the caddy for my group?
Me!
Shall I polish your balls?
No thanks.
This is Mr. Nishi, caddy-in-training.
He failed the pro test four times.
You don't need to mention that.
I'm Tonbo Oi.
Nice to meet you!
Y-yeah.
You too.
I heard the rumors. She really only has
seven clubs. Can she play like that?
Why do I have to caddy for this kid?
Why did Mr. Nakase tell me to do this?
What's with that face?
Sorry, Igaiga.
You really are like Grandpa Gon.
Ms. Kasahara, you'll mark for Ms. Okawa.
Ms. Oi, you'll mark for Ms. Kasahara.
Okawa, you'll mark for Ms. Oi, please.
Can I get ahead
three strokes in this wind?
There's another thing
to be nervous about.
My strokes have a lot of spin and are weak
to wind. That's the only way I can hit.
I'm used to playing in the wind. I don't
mind it. But I'm not the only one.
There's someone else
I need to watch out for.
The forest has turned completely white.
White?
The color of the leaves
when they're blown by the wind.
When reading the wind,
golfers must pay attention to the trees.
Pros look at the color of the leaves.
When it's blowing this hard,
even Bunpei can tell
where it's coming from.
That's because he's
really good at reading the wind!
Who's Bunpei?
The king of goro golf.
Goro golf?
Maybe I'll try goro golf today, too.
So that's how they do it!
That's so cool!
The wind carried it all the
way into the left forest.
I've got to tie it a bit tighter.
Hey! You're next!
The hole starts with a grove on the right.
I'll probably have to aim
for the adjacent hole,
but aiming that far right
is scary.
Even with a flat fairway, landing the ball
in the right place will be tough.
The band will break
if you pull too hard!
You'll need a hairpin, too.
Alright!
It's not alright! You have to hit!
Sorry, I'm going to use this one.
A five wood?
Tonbo!
Don't worry about your score!
Get out there and win this thing!
Play your way!
Show us that special Tonbo style!
Okay!
Teeing up high in wind like this?
Where is she aiming?
Tonbo's going for a swallow ball.
But why is she using a five wood?
Her driver is designed
to produce as little spin as possible.
Not only backspin, but
creating side spin is difficult as well.
It's hard to turn the ball.
Because a five wood is usually
hit from the ground,
it's designed to create backspin
to send the ball up high.
It's easy to turn the ball.
She's not aiming for a swallow ball.
She's looking to improve her score.
What? The wind isn't carrying it!
Go! Flying fish ball!
Alright!
The ball has a fierce cut spin sending it
straight through the wind, unharmed.
Oh no! My visor is gone!
What should I do?
The visor Hinoki gave me! Where'd it go?
Her concentration is incredible.
Even in this wind, she's able to
send the ball any direction she wants.
She's like a fish in water.
Hey! We have to get going!
I'll find it for you later!
Okay.
She's amazing.
How is she able to turn the ball?
Her swing is different
every shot she takes!
This one won't be easy.
Sandy lies with thin grass.
There's even a bunker
between the ball and the pin.
What?
That stance!
She avoided the sand!
What?
I knew that would work! This is so fun!
You knew it?
You mean you had confidence in that shot?
Aren't you scared of anything?
Scared?
That's a terrifying shot!
What if you went in the bunker?
What?
I just thought it'd be cool if I could get
it over the bunker!
Cool?
I avoided hitting a chunk shot
with my stance!
What? But how?
I'm not sure.
That's where Tonbo hit.
Even in this strong wind,
she's aiming her swings
towards the seventh hole on the left.
I'm sure she hit that cut ball
to battle the wind,
but I don't plan on fighting the wind.
I'm going to use it to my advantage.
That's how I deal with wind.
I just have to get the ball
on the wide left area of the pin.
It won't make it!
Sorry!
Hey Tsubura! How's it going?
What does it look like? My ball is way
over here!
How about you, Tonbo?
My score hasn't changed yet.
Adaniya got a double bogey.
I'm down three strokes.
Tsubura and Ema are down two.
We're all tied at three under.
I thought only the three of us had a
chance to win. But Tonbo is on par.
She's entered the running
to win this thing!
The final day of the
competition has begun!
Huh? What's wrong, Tonbo?
Well, you see...
On the next episode of Tonbo!
Hinoki's Troubles
Yaya asked me to choose between
western or Chinese food for dinner!
You haven't changed at all.