You think Mirei isn't happy?
Me... happy?
That'll never happen.
What'll never happen?
Daybreak vs. Blackout, Nagoya Showdown!
You don't care about this, do you?
Battle 2: Haruka vs. Megumi is finally over!
You could just turn off your phone.
Megumi has broken through Haruka,
the first gatekeeper standing in their way!
As a result, Blackout has broken
through the castle gate!
Despite having lost one fighter,
they reach the castle's second level!
Who will be the next gatekeeper awaiting them?!
Is that picture book really all that interesting?
The opposing Blackout also has
plenty of strong members remaining!
Is that picture book really all that interesting?
I loved it when I was little.
The opposing Blackout also has
plenty of strong members remaining!
Are you ready, you blackguards?!
Now you can focus on the book.
If it's that interesting...
...then try reading it.
"Long ago..."
"...there were..."
"...two types of lions in the world:"
"Maned lions, and maneless lions."
Just go.
"The maneless lions lived in the Moon Kingdom,
a splendid and wealthy country."
"The maned lions lived in the Sun Kingdom,
a small and poor country."
"The two countries were always fighting."
Oh! Look who's here!
I'll do it.
I'm back at my best today. Are ya sure?
Wait, please!
Yu-yu?!
Huh, so I get to start by defeating you?
Talk about a shabby hors d'oeuvre!
Yu-yu, don't take that twerp seriously.
Isn't Daybreak supposed to be
a team that prizes following rules?!
Mind your manners!
That'd mean not getting to talk at all!
Masanori told me our conversation
wouldn't be included in the broadcast,
and that I can go ahead and play however I like!
That jerk... doesn't that mean anything goes?!
So hey... shall we have some fun?
Now, the third fight is starting!
From Daybreak, "Little Monster,
Overflowing Malice," Shinobu Kajita!
And from the opponent Blackout,
Yu-yu Kondo comes in with fists flying!
Stand up, Vanguard!
Awakening of Chakrabarthi
Flight
"Each kingdom had its own king."
Awakening of Chakrabarthi
Flight
"Arthur, the most cheerful of Sun Kingdom,
and Leon, the quietest of Moon Kingdom."
Awakening of Chakrabarthi
Flight
"Arthur, the most cheerful of Sun Kingdom,
and Leon, the quietest of Moon Kingdom."
Second to go is Yu-yu,
who swiftly calls a rear-guard and attacks!
Now, what will Shinobu's next turn bring?!
I ride!
With my minions' skill, I take Greedon
from my ride deck, reveal it,
and draw one card.
Both of these kids have cute faces,
but act like terrible hooligans!
Both of us? You really don't get it!
Damage check!
Snerk! A wasted trigger!
My turn's over!
Go on!
I ride Reiyu.
I call Trickstar!
Whoa, what a dignified face!
You've just nonchalantly butted in,
only to lose on purpose!
And I hear Blackout has
just gotten a new banner, too!
If you lose, it'll get burned up again, right?
I absolutely...
...must not lose!
Now all the rear-guards are deployed!
The first to get them in formation is Yu-yu!
Are you sure you wanna do that?
I've seen your deck before.
I'll crush you in the early game
with one big offensive!
I attack!
I guard!
My turn is over.
A swift bombardment!
Yu-yu's current attack vigor is incredible!
Yeah, it's not bad.
Hey, what's the rush?
I know that you're strong.
Ooh, you got that right!
Check me out. I'm way too strong!
Time to live up to your expectations.
I ride Avaricious Demonic Dragon, Greedon!
Call in the minions!
Greedon attacks!
No guard.
Whoa, you're so cool!
All righty, twin drive.
Draw trigger.
Munch, munch, crunch, crunch!
Hogging the attacks and all trigger effects.
That's greed: the power to seize everything!
With Greedon's skill, the minions
enter the Soul, and it restands.
My Greedon is always, always
the strongest of the strongest!
Plus, with the minions' skill,
it gets an extra drive! Rawr!
Ha ha! Now you're scared!
Gobbling up its rear-guards to restand,
and it even gets five total drive checks?!
What a greedy Vanguard!
That twerp's as hideous as ever.
Say...
Do you remember?
During the earlier fights...
...Shinobu never made
a single attack with a rear-guard.
But Greedon restands by putting
four rear-guards into the soul.
Yes, which means that after starting with
five rear-guards, there's still one remaining.
And yet, Greedon makes all the attacks.
That's Shinobu's unbending fighting style.
Greedon attacks once more!
No guard!
Aww, yeah! That's the stuff!
I love this sensation!
Triple drive!
Somehow, it's like... the hunger's
more insatiable than usual today!
Double critical!
Sowwy, I'm just so strong and cute!
Damage check.
Oopsie! Now there's no way out for you!
My turn... is over!
Yu-yu has been abruptly driven to 5 damage!
If I lose, it's all over.
I have to win!
Your Name
Dang... that was a heck of an ending.
Though both lions had been good friends,
after they grew up and fought,
one of them wound up dead?
It's because both of them were kings.
To protect their kingdoms,
they threw away their friendship.
Unless you fight and win,
you can't protect your country.
Nobody's going to stick with
a king who can't win, are they?
That's true.
That's why you have to win
in order to achieve your goal.
Even at the cost of ending up alone.
I ride Chakrabarthi Divine Dragon, Nirvana!
I must clinch the win now!
Vairina overDress!
You like doing that, don't you?
Oh, shut up!
Oooh, so scary!
Nirvana attacks!
Okay! No guard!
What the? Aren't you gonna draw?
Huh? What is it?! Don't tell me you're nervous!
Twin drive!
Calm down.
Focus.
Feel it.
I must draw one now...
...or else lose!
Critical trigger!
Now a card to turn the game around!
Second check!
Dear oh dear!
Were you perhaps expecting something dramatic,
like an Over Trigger or a double critical?
I told you to shut up!
Get through!
I guard.
My turn is over.
Yu-yu's ferocity is unflagging!
However, Shinobu pulls through with 5 damage!
I couldn't finish it.
At this rate...
Whew, so close!
Too bad for you that you couldn't end it there!
After such provocation...
...I refuse to lose!
Provocation?
You think I'm talking like this to provoke you?
I do it because it's fun!
Just like how you guys chat
during your fights at your gathering spot.
If that's how you have fun,
then this is how I have fun!
And besides, it's not like
I need to get you all shaken up.
What's the point of that strategy?
I mean, you're weak!
I just love that look on your face!
Shut up!
Okay, then! It's about time I licked my chops!
Persona Ride!
Now my Greedon won't lose until it hits 7 damage!
Now, this is strength!
Forget winning and losing.
I even get to decide who lives and who dies!
There it is! A skill that increases life force!
Now the amount of damage Yu-yu
must drive through has gone up by 1!
I call! And then...
Greedon attacks!
With the skill of the minions
in the Soul, its power is 48,000!
I... guard!
And intercept!
You're scared, aren't ya?
Of losing.
I am not scared!
"I am not scared!"
This is bad.
There are two attacks remaining.
Yeah... he doesn't have enough cards.
However...
I always chow down in the tastiest,
most awesome situation ever.
Greedon's skill activates: the minions
enter the Soul, and it restands!
This is how I Cardfight!
There's no limit to my greed.
Greedon demands it!
Your defeat!
Your terror!
Just to mercilessly, and relentlessly,
prey upon the minions before it!
That is the proof of absolute strength!
Once again, I'm the happiest and strongest ever!
Way too scary, ain't it?
Well, yeah! It does have a whole 78,000 power!
Time for you to die!
Greedon attacks!
I...
...guard!
A perfect guard?
How dare you struggle?!
Ooh, but! Wait for it! Triple drive time!
Ta-da! Heal trigger!
Now my win's clinched, yeah?
My turn's over!
What an unbelievable Greedon fixation!
A complete affront to one's self-respect, huh?
It's Yu-yu's turn!
He still needs to deal 3 damage to Shinobu,
but how will he fight in this situation?!
I need to deal 3 more damage to win.
I have one card in hand, and no front rear-guards.
Is this... how it ends?
Why?
You still haven't given up?
But I'm sure I'll lose.
And I'm afraid... of losing.
You were always by my side, guiding my emotions.
That's right.
I want to see them.
Both Danji...
...and her...
What?
Just what are you doing at this point?
I draw!
I ride Chakrabarthi True Dragon, Mahar Nirvana!
He's riding a grade 4!
It's suddenly unclear
how this match is going to end!
Mahar Nirvana's skill activates!
I call Trickstar from the Drop Zone!
Furthermore, if my opponent has 4 damage
or less, their Vanguard takes 1 damage!
Wha?! Hey!
Dealing damage without an attack?!
Can you really do that?!
No no no no no!
You can't, you can't, you can't!
How can you do that?!
I'm scared.
But... it's my turn!
Vairina Valiente overDress!
Mahar Nirvana attacks!
Here's a perfect guard!
Triple drive!
Eek! Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it!
First check.
No no no no no no no!
Second check!
Oh, God! Please, God!
Third check!
Wha?! Wha wha whaaaa?!
Rino gets +10,000 power and an extra critical!
A critical trigger!
Now it's over if either
rear-guard's attack goes through!
Huh? What the?
Now it's over if either
rear-guard's attack goes through!
Huh? What the?
This is weird, this is weird!
What damage do I lose at again?
What the? What the wha the huh?!
Rino attacks!
Dang it!
I guard!
I guard! I guard!
Twist the inferno, and burn red...
Fierce flame quivering, changing to wings...
Furious fire flourishing, let us take flight...
In a blaze of crimson, transform into embers!
Valiente attacks!
No guard!
With Valiente's skill,
because its attack hit, it restands!
No, you can't do that!
No! Oh no!
Oh no oh oh no oh no!
One more attack!
The winner: Yu-yu Kondo!
He did it!
Your Name
Well, while it's true that he won...
...it's kind of a lonely story, isn't it?
Those two lions had made
the effort to become good friends.
Couldn't they have whined, "I don't want
to fight my friend!" and stopped the fighting?
They wouldn't be able to do that, right?
Because they're kings.
Because a king... is special.
Just as I'd expect from Daybreak's king.
Your attitude is on a whole different level.
Well, after reading this book, I understand.
So it's because you're special
that you're eager to be alone?
What are you implying?
Enough. I hate you. Call my brother over.
Oh, dear. Now you hate me?
Call my brother's phone!
You were watching the match, right?
Yeah.
Go ahead, look down on me.
After all, I'm not like you.
Go on.
It seems I'm useless now.
That's not--
Been a while!
You look as cool as ever.
Now, who's up?
Did we lose again, I wonder?
Still, we'll be fine.
Because... I've grown strong!
Like a king.
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
I'm Yu-yu!
This time, I'll introduce Nirvana's new form:
Chakrabarthi True Dragon, Mahar Nirvana!
For its first skill,
if you have a unit in overDress,
your front row units all get +10,000 power!
And for its second skill, when you call
a grade 0 from the Drop Zone,
if your opponent has 4 damage
or less, you give them 1 damage!
I call it the... "Special Move: Trickstar Cannon!"
Next Episode
Aurora Fierce Princess
Right and Wrong