Alright. On the first hole
I can gauge my condition
while avoiding using up
too much energy.
It looks like an approach shot.
No, more like a super long putt.
Tsubura is always on point!
It looks like it's 253 yards to the edge.
A spoon?
So she's going to try for two shots.
You need to be responsible
for making your own dreams come true.
Hinoki is fired up from what
I told her before we started.
I can sense the momentum
in her practice swings.
She's going to use her
full power from the start.
A 253 yard shot would come up just short.
She can't hit it that far.
If that's the case,
she'll aim to drop on the fairway
and hope that the ball rolls onto the
green. That's what she's planning.
Go. Get there.
So close!
Just a little farther left
and it would have been perfect.
What have I done? It won't be easy
getting out of that bunker.
She used some energy for this one,
and she'll use even more
for the next shot, too.
Amazing. They're already about 210 yards
away from the green edge.
For her first and second shots,
She chose simple shots
that would allow her to preserve energy.
No-pressure shots that would
take her 240 yards in two turns.
-Is my ball ahead?
-No.
Mine went just a bit farther.
I won't make the eagle. But I still have a
a chance to make the birdie.
Knowing that I'm guaranteed par at worst,
I'm going to get that birdie.
Is it my turn yet?
I'm so excited!
I've made it this far.
I can send the ball to the green.
I'll have to aim near the pin to make the
eagle. But I have to avoid the bunker.
To get the birdie,
she'll aim for the center
left of the pin.
She'll take it in two strokes.
She might even get it in one.
She could also get an eagle.
That's how I'd do it.
This is getting tense.
She's so cool!
Nice one! Amazing!
Most players don't celebrate
when their opponent makes a good shot.
Alright. I'm up.
How should I do this?
I have so many options.
Hey, do you mind?
There's no telling what
Tonbo might do next.
Watching her golf is just like
playing with a Jack-in-the-box!
I'll use Tsubura for this one!
This club. I named it Tsubura!
That's the club I gave her, you see.
She's aiming to the left.
I can't tell what she's trying
to do with that stance.
It could go either right or left.
How will she hit it? Where will it go?
It's a ladybug!
I didn't mean to do that.
What was she thinking?
Do you plan on hitting it from there?
You can try again, you know.
I know,
I just thought I might hit it!
I can't believe it.
The way she plays golf
reminds me of a little child.
26, 27, 28
It rolled a little farther than expected.
72 yards to the edge and 79 to the pin.
I'll use this and aim right for the pin.
This girl is clever.
She's been aiming for this
third shot position since her tee shot.
There's nothing standing
between her and the pin.
She was able to set herself up
for this position perfectly.
And also,
I can sense how that her shoulder
movements are on point.
Stop jumping around like a bunny!
You're distracting me!
I was trying to see where my ball is!
Sorry!
Jeez. You're funny, Tonbo.
Just around 80 yards.
She could land it right at the pin.
But if she's thinking
about her fourth shot,
She'll aim for the area that leaves a
straight putt on the final stretch.
A gimme.
A gimme dead in the center!
Alright! Way to go, Tsubura!
Take the birdie!
Where's my ball?
She was able to line up a birdie
while preserving her mental stamina.
There it is!
If she hopes to line up with the pin
she'll aim for the green edge.
That doesn't leave
much room between the bunker.
If she comes up short,
it'll go in the bunker.
If it goes in, she'll get a bogey.
She knows better than to
aim for the green edge.
She's going for it.
She'll lob the ball right to the edge.
Tonbo isn't thinking
about her score at all.
She only has the excitement of the shot.
Okay.
She squared up the club face?
Lining the ball to the right?
The ball's lost its power.
Very interesting.
Oh no! A sprinkler? I didn't notice it
hidden behind the grass!
The ball landed right
where I was aiming, too!
She really was aiming there?
I can't believe she
aimed for such a tricky spot!
No professional player would ever risk
doing something like that.
It's too risky.
Tonbo's greatest strength
is her fearlessness.
It's also
her greatest weakness.
She doesn't think about her mistakes.
Her shot was perfect,
but it ended up a failure.
This will be a bogey for Tonbo.
Hinoki still has a chance for a birdie.
If she wants to guarantee a birdie,
she'll have to land the ball
right on the inside of the green.
She doesn't want to come up short.
The thought of not making it on the green
will definitely affect her shot.
She'll try to hit it past the pin.
It's on the green,
A downhill slice line.
They're probably thinking
this putt won't be easy to make.
You have to enter the bunker
from the lowest point!
You can't just jump in!
Sorry!
She sure gets yelled at a lot.
She won't be making anymore shots that
would risk getting in the bunker.
She's reached her limit already.
Her fingers are almost touching the shaft!
That hand rate...
That stance is ...!
I knew it!
The shot she showed me on Hinoshima!
It's close.
Oh no. The ball stopped.
The bunkers on Hinoshima
have steeper slopes.
She was good at steep slopes near the pin.
She also had a following wind.
She tried the same thing here
and the ball stopped.
Nice touch!
Nice birdie!
It breaks more at the end than I thought.
I see. Hinoki didn't overshoot.
She was trying to hit it that far.
Last one.
If she overshoots it will land
in line with my first putt.
That's what she was aiming for.
Now's my chance.
Nice birdie!
I thought she was a goodie two shoes who
did whatever her dad says. Why?
Isn't she a clever one.
She seems to have experience in competing.
That's a birdie! Amazing!
Everyone is so good! What a group!
Okay. It's my turn!
Alright, nice!
It's been an hour. They'll be on the fifth
hole soon. That's close to here.
Where are you going, Mr. Otoha?
I'm going to see how Hinoki's doing.
You can't do that.
No one is allowed on the course
besides the players.
Nice shot!
A birdie on one, two and four.
I have to keep my honor.
Perhaps I got a little too heated up.
She's already at three under.
You've got a beautiful swing.
Yeah! Hinoki's swing is so cool!
Whoa! Perfectly straight again!
A beautiful swing makes a beautiful shot.
That's the kind of golfer I wanted to be.
That's the path that I travelled.
Keep going!
Nice shot!
Ema is currently at four under.
After getting one bogey, she got a double
bogey on the third hole
Her score has dropped by three,
putting her at two under.
Ema?
What's wrong?
It happens whenever I hear a big splash.
In America, all sorts of
scary creatures live in the swamps.
So that's probably why
I react that way.
You mean, alligators?
After I won the World Junior Open...
...it took me ten years.
We moved to Japan for my father's job,
but I was finally able to compete again.
But why?
Why did you do all that just for golf?
Why?
I don't get it.
After an injury like that, after being so
scared. Even walking must have been hard.
There was someone on the island
who had scars just like Ema's.
He was attacked by a shark while fishing.
But even so,
he's still fishing today.
Why? Isn't he scared?
I'm sure he is, but he
loves fishing too much.
The love overcomes the fear.
Same for me.
If something were to take
golf away from me,
I'd do the same.
I'd do my best to be able to play again.
I lost my ability to swing and
make shots as beautiful as yours.
However,
it hasn't been all bad.
I'm happy to be able to play at all.
I'm grateful that I'm able to play golf.
I think that might be
my greatest strength.
Everyone's playing golf
because they like it.
Do I feel the same way?
I...
I told Hinoki she's got to
take the top ranking today.
But sir...
I've got to get out and
encourage her to get there.
Mr. Otoha.
Why do you do it?
Why are you so determined to
make Hinoki number one?
When I was young,
I would go around peeking
underneath vending machines
trying to find spare change
that people had dropped.
I got down on my hands and knees
and looked for hours.
People who claim that
money isn't everything
clearly have never known
what it's like to be poor.
It's a miserable problem.
That's why I made a promise.
A promise to be rich.
A promise to take first place
and the prize money.
People like to talk big.
Winning isn't everything, they say.
They're wrong.
Only those who aim for first place
can take the ultimate prize.
Everyone wants to be a winner.
But when they know they can't do it,
they claim it's the effort that counted.
But that's not how I see it.
It's the results that matter.
Those who show results
are the ones who receive praise.
It turned too much.
In the world of golf, there are players
who lack good sportsmanship,
yet they still gain fans, status,
and great wealth through their victory.
Did you find it?
Yes.
I'm so glad! Next is Tonbo.
On the other hand,
there are golfers who adhere to etiquette
and have a good attitude, yet never win.
There are countless golfers like that.
I have to get first place.
Don't you agree, Hajime?
Your path to the pros was
closed off when you got cold feet.
Since then you haven't been able
to make any progress.
Mr. Otoha.
Even so,
even at my lowest,
I never stole from anyone.
That's something I'm proud of.
Looks good.
She made it.
I have to get first place.
If I don't get first... my father will...
Have you found your ball, Tonbo?
Here it is!
The ball moved!
Tsubura, what am I supposed to do again?
If it's your fault the ball moved,
you lose a stroke and
move it back to where it was.
Got it.
I'll put it back.
Nice birdie.
-Nice birdie.
What's your score?
Four under.
I'm tied for first.
I've got to take first place.
The ball moved again!
Tsubura!
If it's your fault the ball moved,
you lose one stroke and put it back.
That's right.
Why? Why is she so calm?
Why can't I be like that?
Alright.
What was that?
The Grandpa Gon Boat Shot!
Alright!
Her score is in shambles, but I've never
seen a more incredible golfer.
The waves were crazy out there.
What a ride.
Tonbo! Mr. Igarashi is coming now.
Coming here?
Where is he now?
He's in Kagoshima.
He said he couldn't get a hold of you.
My battery died.
I forgot to charge it.
If he's in Kagoshima now,
he should be about two hours.
But why is he coming here?
He heard you took the top on the first day
and wanted to see you.
I see. Two more hours.
Oh? I thought she'd be happier.
Igaiga is coming!
I should have tried harder today.
I hit a 77.
Ten strokes off yesterday's score.
He would have been so happy
if I had made the top again today.
But... that means he'll
be there tomorrow too.
If I do my best tomorrow I can make him
happy! Alright! I've got this!
Someone's excited.
She's got a good reason.
Tonbo!
What are you doing here?
You came to get me?
You're doing great.
Why am I crying?
Tonbo.
Thanks for coming, Igaiga.
Don't sound so distant.
I know things haven't been easy for you.
Igaiga.
On the next episode of Tonbo!
"The Tossing and Turning Winds"
You're making me so proud!
Igaiga?
Your face is scary.
I'm crying, okay?