While the night is brief,
it comes around again soon enough.
That's how we've been able to endure.
No matter how badly our days may go,
as long as we have the night...
...as long as we have Vanguard...
...we can fight through it all.
As long as we have our friends
from Team Blackout....
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
This place was our hangout spot.
We didn't know much about each other's
life situations, and we wouldn't pry.
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
We didn't know much about each other's
life situations, and we wouldn't pry.
That was all for the best.
What connected us was Vanguard. A card game.
In this place, everything
was decided using Vanguard.
And with the cards between us,
we'd have conversations.
Until that day, the day this place got wrecked.
I read book after book.
The nights were long without everyone around,
and reading was the only thing I could do.
Here where we live,
the city of Kanazawa in the land of Kaga,
we have a capture-the-flag game called Hatagenpei:
a battle between the Genji and the Heishi.
In this area, the famous warrior Saito Sanemori
staked his life on a hopeless battle.
I'm neither Genji nor Heishi,
much less a military commander.
The pity of it
Trapped underneath a HELMET
A grasshopper chirps
I'm neither Genji nor Heishi,
much less a military commander.
Even if I failed to protect the Blackout banner,
losing the battle wouldn't cost me my life.
The pity of it
Trapped underneath a HELMET
A grasshopper chirps
Even if I failed to protect the Blackout banner,
losing the battle wouldn't cost me my life.
And yet...
...why does it hurt like I'm dying?
No matter how I try to empty my mind,
the painful feelings keep getting in.
Does Tohya not understand that?
I mean, Tohya's the one
who destroyed the merry-go-round.
And now he's the one fixing it.
The nights are long without everyone around.
And worse, they come around again soon enough.
The nights are long
when you're by yourself. Too long...
How many days has Tohya been here, all alone?
Exspecta vs Bastion
Reboot
Welcome to Wonder Hill
Let's Have Lots of Fun
The pity of it
Trapped underneath a HELMET
A grasshopper chirps
A new... banner?
The pity of it
Trapped underneath a HELMET
A grasshopper chirps
Uh, say--
You don't need to help me.
I caused all of this.
I'm atoning for it.
I can manage this by myself.
Long time no see!
Tomari!
It's weird running into anyone here
at this time of day.
Oh my?
Now, that takes me back!
Look, it's the banner that Takami made.
That was Blackout's banner?
Yes, long ago.
To think that Danji still has it!
A lot happened back then, too.
I'm sorry.
It seems that only the light bulbs were broken.
I'll be sure to replace them.
Ah, youth...
You're not angry, Tomari?
Nah, Blackout has lots of naughty kids.
And Danji was one too, long ago.
Yamamoto and Ishida
have also settled down, but...
Have you talked with Tohya?
No, not yet.
I see...
Then, you haven't heard the thing
about him and his university?
He said he quit in order to play cards seriously.
He told me, "I went that far, to come here."
Yu-yu, are you angry with Tohya?
Well...
But weren't you offering to help fix it?
That was...
...because Tohya was also worn out.
And he seemed to be suffering. That's all.
So you're the type who'd forgive a girl
who cheats on you if she cries, huh?
What are you talking about?
I'm just saying, be careful!
Okay!
Those were my words of sisterly advice for you!
Work to Do Every Day
#1: Feed Melonbread
#2: Take out trash
#3 Clean bath
Number one.
Feed Melonbread.
Trash and Recycling Schedule
Number two.
Take out the trash.
Number three.
Clean the bath.
Done!
Hello! Odd Jobs by Danji!
Watching the house?
Danji will be away from home for a good while,
so he's letting me stay here in the meantime.
I see you're taking over his gig work, too.
Well... I do have to pay for
the repairs, and the electricity.
Uh, say...
I could help--
You don't need to help.
Wha?!
Why not?!
I caused a lot of trouble for Danji.
I have to take care of all this myself,
for it to count as atonement.
Tomari was telling me...
...that you're trying to take care
of everything all by yourself.
But that's impossible, she said.
That's why I'm--
Hello! Odd Jobs by Danji!
I've seen Danji do this job before.
Once I'm done, I'll help you out, okay?
No, as soon as I'm done,
I'll be right over to help you out!
I wasn't even able to climb a tree earlier,
but I'm not gonna lose this time!
Can you carry even one of these?
Should be a piece of cake for me, though.
It's going to work out... this time!
Are you sure?
You're weak!
Do something!
Awww, c'mon!
Could it be that the work
Danji does is horribly tough?
Awww, c'mon!
Will those two be okay?
Substituting for Danji is...
a bit too much... for ordinary people...
Why are you back again today?
Because I can't leave you to do it all yourself!
Go away!
You're the one who'd impede any progress.
But you failed at everything yourself!
Shut up!
No, you're right.
So please, go away.
It's embarrassing.
Tohya, you're somewhat... ordinary, aren't you?
You struck me as someone more perfect, and scary.
What about it?
I'm just a bit relieved.
Since I'm embarrassed myself.
Doing nothing but failing,
unable to get anything right...
And so!
Shall we do our best together a little longer?
Speak of the devil...
Sorry about the sudden request!
Have you memorized your dance moves?
You're on in five minutes,
so we'll be counting on you.
Later!
I can't do my best at this...
But not doing it isn't an option, right?
Ugh...
Kiddie Showtime
Yay, I can't wait!
What's it gonna be?!
Wha?!
Amazing!
What is this?!
Tohya, are you all right?
I failed yet again...
Hey, what were you doing out there?!
We're terribly sorry...
No, that's not what I meant!
It was awesome!
I'll be calling on you again!
Here it is! A Big Kani-Kani Parfait!
"Kani"? Crab?
This is what Danji orders
on his way home from work!
Danji says, "It'd be no exaggeration
to call this my reason for working!"
I wasn't able to do anything.
You were able to dance, weren't you?
Only thanks to you.
I couldn't do anything without you there.
Well, same for me.
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Y'know, we really ought
to reinforce the scaffolding...
I'm only here because Yu-yu asked me to come.
I'm not here for you.
Hey, what's he talking about?
I'm sorry.
I just thought fixing this place
was too much for the two of us.
Yamamoto's really good at hammering!
He taught me how to do it
when we built the barricades.
And Ishida's stronger than he looks!
Stuff that we can't carry, he can, easily!
Fine, I get it.
With that, it's mostly in working order.
I get the feeling it's even
more splendid than before.
Yeah, but... what about the electricity?
Yeah, Danji's not here anymore.
I paid the electric bill.
I used the money I earned working with Yu-yu.
It should be back on tonight.
Thank you.
Uh, say... we've got some time
before tonight, right?
There's a place I'd like to go visit...
Card Shop Stray Cat
High Prices for Used    Battle Space Available!!
I haven't been here in ages.
There's a pack I want to get.
Tohya, please look around in here while you wait.
Tohya!
Come here!
Take a look at these!
Anything in the new cards grabbing you?
How about you?
For me, when playing Keter,
I'd have to go with Lagrele, yeah?
You think so?
But Lagrele is high-cost and difficult to use,
and its strength depends a lot on luck.
No, no, that's what's great about it!
It's fun because it depends on luck, yeah?
Are you sure?
Good point!
A fight with everything
riding on luck can be a great time!
Sounds right up your alley.
What d'you mean?!
Exactly what I said!
Uh, say...
I robbed you all of your place to play Vanguard.
I really am very sorry about that.
Well, it's all fixed now, right?
And you're getting our electricity back.
It's back on!
Hey, everybody!
Tomari!
Great, the lights are back on!
Blackout is finally reactivated!
I couldn't get it entirely back
to how it was before, though.
Well, that's a given.
Nothing that's been broken
will go back to the way it was.
That's what "scrap and rebuild" is all about.
Rebuild it to be even stronger than before.
By which I mean...
Go up there and give us a real fight, you guys!
Got your new card?
Of course I'm using it.
Bring it on.
All set?
Stand up, Vanguard!
Yay! It's a fight to launch Blackout
into a brand new restart!
They each have one win
and one loss against the other!
No matter who wins,
this'll be Taking-the-Lead Fever!
Tomari's more exuberant than usual tonight.
Is she?
But I kinda get why.
Because I'm also happy
to be able to fight like this!
Yeah, I agree.
Okay! We'll dispense with the details!
While we fight, I'm gonna give you full leeway!
Of course!
But that means...
...overDress!
It's also fine for me to
beat you to a pulp, right, Tohya?
So you're able to say that, now.
I attack!
What's this?
Are you guys youth-ing it up?!
Don't go leaving me behind, here!
Tomari's not commentating at all.
Yeah, she's totally heckling.
I ride Bastion!
It's too soon for you to fight the way Danji does.
Can you stop me?
You were wrong to assume
you'd clinch this perfectly.
Since you'll mess up soon enough, Tohya.
Wha?! You were talking about something
besides cards there, weren't you?!
Maybe, maybe not?
I swear, you really have gotten saucy.
Attack! Attack! A series of attacks!
With the effect, Alden's power rises,
inflicting a fierce sword blow on Yu-yu!
OverDress!
And now, another overDress!
Here's where Yu-yu's new card shows up!
It's Vairina's final evolution!
After this, who knows
how the fight will proceed?!
Now you're talking.
Great! That's the way!
Get him! Yu-yu!
Hang in there!
Get him!
First, I'll have Nirvana attack.
Tohya?
Oh, sorry. No guard.
Tohya's not guarding at this point?!
If there's a critical, it's all over!
Just what strategy is he following this time?!
Uh... I'm not...
Doesn't matter.
I'll end it now.
Twin drive!
Front trigger...
One more!
Front trigger!
Critical denied!
No way! Was the "no guard"
because he foresaw this?!
Actually, If I'd done an incomplete guard,
I wouldn't have been able to block on this turn.
That was an accident, though.
It'll be full someday.
That entire audience space!
Yeah, definitely.
Exspecta attacks your Vanguard!
With its skill, it has two criticals,
and its power is 73,000!
Perfect guard!
Reiyu attacks!
I guard with two Gurgants!
Wha?! Wha the huh?! He held it off completely!
Amazing! So he saw that development coming?!
So he staked it on a critical not appearing?!
Fights can be like this, yeah?
They sure can!
Persona Ride!
I call Lagrele!
This time Tohya calls in a new card!
The Knight's Squad's newest recruit
has joined the fray!
Alden attacks!
No guard!
Bastion attacks!
Yu-yu guards!
With the skill, his total shield is 40,000!
Not even a double trigger will get through now!
Check!
And yet, he drew a double trigger!
Now even Tohya's all go-go-go, shove-shove!
Will he be able to clinch a win
with his last attack?!
No, not with this...
Lagrele attacks!
I activate its skill to gain a drive check!
In exchange, I must discard my entire hand
after this battle ends.
I'm staking it all on this turn!
Fighting with your back to the wall, are you?
You've got a perfect guard, don't you?
Yep!
Perfect guard!
Yu-yu actually had one!
Now even if Tohya draws a trigger,
his attack won't go through!
It's not over yet! Check!
No trigger.
Check...
A grade 3!
With Bastion's skill, I restand Alden!
H-He had that trick available?!
Tohya can attack once more with Alden!
Grand Heavenly Sword!
Now, just try stopping it!
I'm going at full strength!
I'll rise to your challenge!
Exspecta!
Why are you smiling?
I... don't know if I was able
to forgive you seriously, Tohya.
But still, I'm somehow having fun!
What is this violent throbbing in my heart?
What is this radiance in my chest?
I think I might understand...
...what Danji was talking about.
What's going on here?!
Am I breaking into a grin?!
Here I go!
Let's clinch this, Exspecta!
This is everything I am right now!
Incredible! No guard, at 4 damage?!
For real, just how far ahead
had you read the game?!
That was a mistake.
For real?!
You've got great luck, man!
But really, that fight was red-hot!
Yeah!
If only your luck was as great as his, huh?
That was uncalled for!
A Piece of Soul
Check Out My Card!
I'm Tohya.
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'll introduce
Heavenly Shock of Distinction, Lagrele.
A Piece of Soul
So, when this card attacks a Vanguard, you can
rest your units to give it drive checks.
However, there's a penalty based on how many
other rear-guards you rest when it attacks.
Now, here's the trick to mastering this card!
If you rest four units, you don't discard any of
your hand, but you get fewer attacks that round.
If you rest two units, you don't lose attacks,
but your total number in hand is reduced by one.
And if you don't rest even one unit,
you discard five cards from your hand, but--
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Maiden Mannerism
Reconciliation