Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
It's all soggy.
Welcome to Wonder Hill!
Let's Have Lots of Fun!
Runny Porridge
Welcome to Wonder Hill!
Let's Have Lots of Fun!
I finally get a vacation, and now this!
This is no different from work!
You're the only one who can fix the clock, Bro!
I swear...
I wanna finish up and mingle, but...
...why did the cog suddenly get out of whack?
Stand up...
...Vanguard!
It's no good.
Brush not helping out today?
I cannot see the light of Eos.
"Eos"?
I... lost...
I won, but... wait a minute.
Are you sure you're all right?
I thought he seemed off.
Whew! Now I can finally have fun!
Danji! Yu-yu is...!
What's wrong?!
Yu-yu!
Are you... all right?!
Oh, Danji...
I'm fine.
I'm the picture of health!
See?
Yu-yu!!
Wh-What is it?!
Yu-yu! Yu-yu!
Speak to me! Yu-yu!
Bro, what's the matter?
Yu-yu is... Yu-yu is...!
Oh dear, he seems to have a fever.
He has a fever?!
Pardon me a moment.
His throat isn't swollen.
His throat isn't swollen?!
Danji! Quiet down a little!
Um...
I just feel a little crummy.
Sleep will take care of it.
For now, take him to the doctor!
It's a cold, isn't it?!
Yu-yu! I'll teach you how a man cures a cold!
First: to bring down your fever.
Next: to give you nourishment!
Then: to wrap a leek around your neck!
Well?! All better now, right?!
He's gotten worse!
Jeez, looks like I'd better take him in
and nurse him back to health at my house!
Absolutely not!
Your house is too dangerous!
A man needs quiet to fight off a cold!
You're clearly the more dangerous one!
I'll care for him with full attention to detail!
I'll report you for unlawful confinement!
Uh, no, I will...!
Leave him to me!
I'll do it!
No, I will!
No, me!
No! Me!
No, m--
No, me!
Take him to the doctor first!
Oh, right.
Hospital
Examination Room
Is he all right?
They said it's nothing serious.
A fever brought on by abrupt stress.
I see.
Abrupt stress, huh...
The hospital beds are full,
but it's mild enough for him
to recover fine at home.
You've got work, right, Tomari?
Yes. I'd better get going.
In that case, I'll drive Yu-yu home.
I need to tell Akiko and the rest about what--
Hello?
What souvenir would you like?
Akiko, are you three on a trip?
What the? Danji?
Yes, we're at a hot spring!
We invited Yu-yu, but he said, "No thanks,
I'll be spending time with Danji and the gang."
Could this be what they call growing up?
It makes a big sister feel lonely!
Um, Yu-yu's running a fever.
What?! Yu-yu has a fever?!
Oh, no!
But we can't go home now, surely?
What a pickle.
Oh, dear! Whatever shall we do?
D-Don't worry!
I'll manage something!
What'll you do?
I'll take him to my place.
Goodness, are you fine with this
leading to a criminal case?
Don't poke fun at me!
I already told them
I'll manage something for this guy.
- Apples, leeks -> for sore throat
- Jelly sports drink if no appetite
- Don't let him get worked up, etc.
That Tomari...
- Apples, leeks -> for sore throat
- Jelly sports drink if no appetite
- Don't let him get worked up, etc.
I mean, I already knew what he needs.
Yogurt / Whole Milk
Cooling Strips (contains 5)
Would he need these?
Yogurt / Whole Milk
Classical Music for a Good Night's Sleep
Maybe this, too?
This, for sure.
It's been a while since
I've taken care of a sick person.
Kaku-E
I oughta catch a cold, too...
Thanks for holding down the fort, Megumi.
What's that?
Oh, I just guessed he'd sleep better
with this guy next to him.
But he's not a baby...
You're up?
Danji?
Ow, hot!
Where are we?
My place.
It seems there's nobody at your house,
so you'll stay here until tomorrow morning.
Oh, I see.
Sorry to cause you all this trouble.
It's fine. You're still feverish, right?
Um, I think it's over?
Is it now?
My hand's hot, so I can't really tell.
Anyway, you must be hungry.
Let's eat.
Ta-da!
Danji Momoyama's Japanese man food!
Is that... homemade?
Yep!
I even pickled the plum myself!
This is great for a cold!
Here.
It's so tasty that you're crying!
What the? Doesn't suit your taste?
Hang on a minute!
That's right.
Everyone says they're sour.
Oh, just talking to myself.
Eat this, then sleep some more.
I'm not sleepy anymore.
A sick person's gotta sleep.
Even with such a slight build,
you bared your fangs at Tohya,
and overexerted yourself.
This really is the place, huh?
Unmistakably.
Just let us in, it'll be fine!
Hey, why did you all show up?
Heya!
You're all here!
Goodness, this feels like a man's castle!
Indeed, no place to sit.
Mind if I toss these aside?
Quit it! What did you come here for?
To pay our dear Yu-yu a get-well visit, why else?
My, you're already up and better?
I'm just fine!
My fever's gone down.
Shall I set out cushions?
You shouldn't be treating this place
like it's your own home!
I mean... sorry to barge in...
So this is Bro's house...
You're here to see Yu-yu, right?
Leave your get-well gifts and scram!
But, Danji, they took the trouble to come here.
As kind-hearted as ever!
Here's my get-well gift for you!
Ta-da!
What's that?
A li'l doctor's kit!
You're just joking around!
Breaking a sweat is great for your health!
I told you, he caught a cold!
I'd like you to wear this next time.
Isn't that your hobby?!
Here you go.
Oh, sorry! I already have that playing!
Hurry up and get well!
Right!
Everyone! Thank you very much!
See? Yu-yu's happy!
Well, I'll let it go this time.
Get well soon!
We're waiting for you!
Go on, get going!
Take care!
Okay, it's time for bed again.
Come on! I really am all bet--
This will decide if you're better or not.
See? All better!
Okay, okay!
You got quite a lot of stuff.
You could put together a full deck with these.
This one's strong... and this one!
You really are loved.
I've been wanting this one!
This one, too! And this!
He was tough, huh?
But you won.
Aren't you happy?
You tried so hard, you got a fever.
Since you won, there shouldn't be
anything lingering from the fight.
Something does linger.
The one who lost...
...is hurting because of it.
Don't worry about that guy. He's strong.
Even so, I still don't...
like seeing anyone suffer.
Well, if you're all better,
wanna join me in a fight?
Okay! Now it's your turn.
The water's boiling now.
Got a question?
Danji, what kind of music do you listen to?
Mature music, of course.
Jazz!
Just kidding.
That was harsh!
It's a punishment for lying.
Your bath will be ready soon.
You can use the bath first.
I'm fine going later.
What'll I do?
That was revenge.
I'll give you time to think.
I'll fold laundry in the meantime.
Oh! I'll help out, too!
How many days' worth is this?
About a week.
Okay, it's your turn!
Oh! I totally forgot to think on it!
I won!
I lost!
Was that fun?
I do...
...really love Vanguard.
Yeah.
That's enough, for now.
One more fight! Okay?!
Nope! Bath time!
Danji! Gimme a break!
You worry too much!
I wanna worry while I still can.
Okay!
This next one, then bath.
Sure!
Stand up!
Vanguard!
It's back.
That great look in your eyes.
Welcome to Wonder Hill!
Let's Have Lots of Fun!
Thank you, Danji.
I ache all over.
Good morning!
Oh, Danji...
G-Good morning!
Whoa!
Oh, sorry, I used your kitchen without asking.
You fried up these eggs, Yu-yu?!
Have one, if you like.
Yummy!
You've got yolk on your lip.
Holy moley, that gave my stomach a thrill.
Did I leave the door unlocked?!
It's one of a thief's tricks: lock-picking.
Secure your home.
A cop shouldn't commit crimes!
How are you feeling, Yu-yu?
I'm all better!
That's wonderful!
Danji seems to have nursed you back to health.
Well, it was a piece of cake!
Breakfast cake?
Basically, yeah.
Shall we go out to eat?
What'd you like?
Ramen...
In the morning?!
All right!
For that, I know a great local place!
Wait!
This is just Hachiban Ramen!
I see you've got your appetite back!
I won't lose to you, Danji!
Them's fighting words.
Here is your order.
I didn't order all this.
I ordered it!
Eat up, it's to celebrate your recovery!
Then, here's a present from me, too!
And some free bamboo shoots from me.
Thanks for the food!
Great! I'll have another bowl!
Oh, I'll have another, too!
Huh?! Then, I'll have large seconds!
Me, too!
And thirds! Keep 'em coming!
And you, Zakky?
Oh, I'd better keep up!
I'll have extra-large seconds.
Extra-large?!
Oh, I'd better keep up!
Check Out My Card!
I'm Danji!
This time, I'm introducing my deck's
ace in the hole: "Diabolos Boys, Eden"!
To indicate just how amazing this one is:
It's like Mt. Fuji in a New Year's dream!
Like a strawberry on shortcake!
Like a piece of octopus
in a batch of fried anchovies!
Huh?! That's not enough explanation?
All right, fine.
Basically, it's a cool and tough unit
that hits the enemy line like a hurricane!
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Like a Fish and Water