She did it.
That was perfect.
Everyone on the island.
This is for you!
That's a huge draw.
Nice shot!
No way.
This hole is 514 yards.
At this rate...
She'll hit the green in two strokes.
I've got to be careful.
Tonbo brought her A-game today.
This is it. My very first competition!
She's playing in the Open again this year?
Looks like.
She's the oldest golfer
in the competition.
I did it Shin. I made it
to the Open again this year.
Let's do it together, Michiko!
You know I don't have the time, dear.
I'm happy as long
as you can enjoy yourself.
I promise I'll work
even harder than before.
That's nice of you to say.
I want you to understand how fun it is.
How great the game of golf is.
Shin...
Oh no.
Sorry! I'm coming!
There's no need to hurry.
Oh, come on.
She's still way behind us.
She's going to throw off my rhythm.
Here I go!
Unlike a pro tour,
this is as far as you and I can go.
I hit it!
She's happy just to make contact.
Give me a break.
Come on!
It's just cause she threw off my game!
Wow. You're about 30 yards
from the wild cherry trees.
There's probably another
230 yards to the green.
You should use a fairway wood.
Thank you.
A five wood?
She might be able to get
two on with a spoon.
The pin is on the inside,
left of the green.
It's probably closer to 260 yards away.
Igaiga.
That last tee shot got my heart racing.
I've never felt that playing golf before.
Use this when you
want to hit the ball far.
Alright!
Swallow ball!
Again?
I didn't think
such a low ball could go that far!
No way.
How does she make it roll like that?
Igaiga would never let me down.
Alright!
N-Nice eagle.
Seriously?
Phew. I'll take the double bogey.
Now she's happy about
a double bogey on par five?
That was the first time
I've ever seen an eagle up close!
I wasn't sure it was even possible!
That was incredible!
I even surprised myself!
She said this was her
first competition, right?
And she gets an eagle on the first hole?
Beginner's luck.
This looks a lot like
hole one on the island.
On the island, the ocean is on the left.
I'll hit it just like I always do.
Aiming for the trees?
But that's out of bounds!
It's headed right for the trees!
Over the out of bounds area.
A slice?
Is she hitting
hooks and slices on purpose?
Best parting gift ever!
Parting gift?
Yeah.
It's 1,309 yen!
A parting gift from Igaiga!
Igaiga?
She's trying to calm her nerves.
Ugh, I smell an amateur.
I'm going to hit a provisional ball!
It's safe!
Thank goodness.
It's right on the fairway.
I thought I prepared for this.
Nice!
It's 140 yards from the edge of the green.
The pin is near the front.
About five yards in.
So, 145 yards in total.
The pin is just at the top of a sloping
hump between the two bunkers.
In front of that, a big slide.
One hundred forty-five.
A seven or eight iron
would be a good choice.
She doesn't have either of those.
What will she do?
My only choice is to
hit it lightly with my six iron.
A three iron?
Isn't that way too big?
To the slide.
Oh, looks like it's maybe a little short.
It wasn't too big after all.
She somehow adjusted the distance by
hitting a low shot to land on the slope.
She's using a putter
thirty yards from the green?
The pin is just ahead.
I'll have to hit it softly with my wedge.
But my hands...
They're still shaking.
I'll have to use a putter
and hope for the best.
Nice!
Thank you.
Alright!
Nice bogey.
Now she's complimenting herself.
How about you, Matsuda?
I got a bogey, too.
I'll have to do my best
with the lie that I've got.
There's still a group ahead of us.
I'm at five over now.
I'm down a point from my last bogey!
If she's so happy about all those bogeys,
what's she doing
at the Open in the first place?
She shouldn't even be
participating at this level.
What's the point?
I'm at three over myself.
I can't believe I'm doing so poorly!
I just can't play under these conditions.
Maybe I should just give up.
I'm sorry.
Am I causing trouble?
No.
You've really put that one to use.
It's a keepsake.
It's my father's club.
I see.
A keepsake
from your father?
My clubs were also a present
from my husband. His last present.
The last?
Yes? This is Shima.
Your order has been delivered.
It's a birthday present for you.
You sure do have a great husband!
Let's do it together, Michiko!
I want you to understand how fun it is.
How great the game of golf is!
I should have played
with him when I had the chance.
Why didn't I listen to him?
Don't go in there!
Oh no, my present!
It's covered in dust!
I couldn't bear
to touch it for over a year.
But I finally built up the courage to
visit my husband's favorite driving range.
His golf buddies offered me
all kinds of good advice.
Do you finally see how fun golf is?
I loved it right away.
Golf doesn't always go
the way you think it will.
It's like getting
dumped by a significant other.
What kind of comparison is that?
It'd be easier to just give up.
But if you keep at it, they'll eventually
look back at you with a smile.
Those are the moments that keep you going.
I think I understand
what he meant by that.
The pin is just to the right.
About 148 yards.
A three iron again?
That club is way too much!
I hit it just a little too low.
I'm sure Tonbo is able to love her score.
No matter what it may be.
That's the result
of making every shot count.
Each shot is precious.
That's what you said, Shin.
The old lady is ahead of me
in the hitting order!
This is bad.
Right to the pin!
So close!
That was a close one.
I think Tonbo hit it
with the face more open.
Hers sounded much better than that.
Nice one!
Nice birdie!
I can't believe I fell asleep in the car!
Tonbo will be almost halfway done by now!
Oh no!
Hey, excuse me.
Yes?
Tonbo, the girl with the half set.
How did she do?
She was last to hit each time.
What?
She couldn't do it after all!
No. That might be the case for tee shots,
but perhaps she meant
Tonbo was last to hit her second shot.
Which one is it, Tonbo. Tell me!
Tonbo! How was it?
I was watching Hinoki the whole time!
She nailed it on the ninth hole!
That's great, but what about you?
I chipped in on the ninth hole!
Sorry, I need to use the toilet!
I hear she got an eagle on the first.
With an eagle chip-in on the ninth,
that alone puts her at three under.
Right.
No matter how she hit on the other
seven holes, that's still a great score.
A tee shot at the very end?
Didn't you get a chip-in
on the ninth, Tonbo?
It was a chip-in bogey!
So what was your score then?
Looks like you're having fun.
Yeah.
I got forty-one on the first nine.
I was able to get
back to the score I wanted.
The score you wanted?
This is actually my third time
in this competition.
I've always aimed for eighty-two,
and the cutoff score for the finals
is always around that number.
Your goal is eighty-two?
Say you squeeze your way into the finals.
What do you plan to do then?
You'll never join the high ranks,
and there are no participation prizes.
So what are you doing here?
It's meaningless.
Meaningless?
I guess for young people like you who
dream of winning competitions like this,
it seems silly for someone like me
to be in this competition.
But not all pros
see their dreams come true.
In fact, I think more people give up
before their dreams come true.
Do you think that's meaningless, too?
Is it meaningless to try
playing golf in the first place?
Your goal shouldn't be to become
the self you see in your dreams.
You need to learn
what it takes to be that person.
It depends on
if you can be proud of the effort or not.
It's not about whether you can fly or not.
It's about having what it takes to try.
That's what I believe.
That's how I like to play golf.
But I...
I don't want to lose to them.
The tee is five steps ahead, and the pin
is ten steps in from the green.
It's 147 yards.
She can't rely on that nine iron forever.
She'll have to use the six iron.
What is this? It doesn't feel right.
Igaiga.
Outside of the island,
people may ridicule the way you play.
Even so, you need to be true to yourself.
Play the way you want to play,
just the way you are.
You won't lose. I guarantee it.
Believe me.
A nine iron?
How does she make it roll so far?
She'll get the birdie for sure.
Her fifth one today!
I believe you, Igaiga. Of course I do.
She hit the six iron again, but this time
the ball came to a complete stop!
If she makes it,
it'll be her sixth birdie!
I can't take it anymore!
I could never do that to my father's club.
Me too.
I could never allow myself
to get that angry during a game.
I know someone who loves golf and wanted
to keep playing more than anyone.
Just knowing that
makes me happy to play.
Get over!
Alright!
Nice one!
Thank you.
If I can get the par in two putts,
I'll still have a chance
to make the finals!
I'm glad I got to play with Ms. Shima.
Looks like three putts after all.
I can't believe she's cheering
after an awful shot like that.
There it is again.
This doesn't feel right. But why?
It's just like before.
What's with this girl?
Did you see how weird her swing is?
She's just having beginner's luck.
No. They didn't say anything.
I'm just imagining things.
Oh no.
It's them. Its people that are scary.
I'll go first then.
What do you want?
N-Nothing!
I don't think you're playing
to your full potential today, are you?
Now that you're frustrated,
it may be too late to make a come back.
That's probably why your game is off.
But you know,
there's no use in trying to cover up
all your mistakes at once.
There's a whole 18 holes
to set things straight.
If you're at the end of the game
and there's nothing left to do,
you still have your
whole life ahead of you.
If you can improve
your lifetime stroke average
even by one point,
that's something to be proud of!
My lifetime average?
When you get to be my age,
you make a lot of mistakes.
And not only in golf.
I've made mistakes that fill
my heart with deep regret.
But at the end of the day,
you can't turn back the clock.
We have our whole lives
to recover from our mistakes.
Each of us lies in our own unique rough.
And we can't always change that!
All we can do
is try our best until the very end.
My lifetime stroke average.
I'd never thought of it that way before.
I'm glad I left the island.
Staying on the island would have meant
laying in the rough forever.
If I hadn't taken a shot and left
the island, we never would have met.
If I make par, I'll be at eighty-three.
I might actually be able
to make the finals.
You can do this.
Get in the hole!
Nice par, Ms. Shima.
Thanks.
Will you look at that!
Wow!
You won the Japan Junior Cup.
Right, Tsubura?
I'm going to win the Kyushu Women's Open
and keep climbing to the top!
On the next episode of Tonbo! My Rival is the Title Holder!
I won once before too, you know!
The "Tonbo Farewell Cup" on Hinoshima!
I want to play in that one, too!
Deal!