Tonbo Oi?
Who's that?
I hear this is her first tournament.
Five under on her first tournament?
Apparently she did it with
only half a set of clubs, too!
Tonbo is having quite the debut today!
She did.
Better than we could have imagined.
How about Tsubura Adaniya? She should be
able to beat Tonbo's 67.
The new scores are up!
Tsubura is in second!
It looks like Tsubura Adaniya
is sitting at two under.
The out course group just finished.
The in course group will finish last.
If a player using only a half set
wins this tournament
it'll be big news.
Tsubura Adaniya is in second,
and Hinoki Otaha is in third.
They're all notable players.
I'm hitting!
Aw, no.
That's not a good place
to be on the last hole.
She's not going to be
happy about that one.
I hope you can make the finals!
Yeah.
I didn't make the last two years.
Before he died, my husband said
he wished to play in the finals.
That's why,
I want to do it for his sake.
Stop it!
Tsubura?
Everyone is so surprised!
Everyone's making a big commotion about
the new girl playing with a half set!
It's no surprise to me!
That's a lie, of course.
I can't believe she's at five under.
Having two new irons in my bag
made it much easier to play.
I think I just got lucky.
I've never gotten a score
like this before!
The last group has just returned.
The top positions will
probably stay the same.
The pairings tomorrow
will be based on current standings,
so we'll probably be
playing together tomorrow.
I get to play with you?
Wahoo!
The last group's scores are going up.
I'm in 99th place with current score.
They added another name above mine.
That puts me in one hundredth place
One hundredth place, again.
I'm in last place.
Is that her?
She hit an eight on the first hole.
Maybe I have a chance.
Sixty-nine?
Another player with a score
in the sixties at the very end!
A sixty-nine with a double par?
That puts her at seven under.
She played with a base of sixty-five?
Ms. Shima.
Have a line drawn above
your name like that
is like being told that
you're good for nothing.
It really hurts.
But...
It's like my husband said.
Golf never goes the way you want it to.
I'll do my best to prepare again
for next year.
That's how much I love golf.
I'm so glad I got to play
with you, Ms. Shima.
I'd love to play with you again some day.
Thank you, Tonbo.
This is Toshima Village
Disaster Management.
We have an announcement to make.
About the Kyushu Women's Open
that began today--
-It's a golf tournament, and--
-Hurry up and say the important stuff!
Right. A resident of this island and a
student at Tsuboi High school...
You're taking way too long!
Everyone! Tonbo is in first place at her
first ever tournament!
Hey! I wanted to say it!
I'm the one who heard it first, after all!
Everyone! This calls for a celebration!
Today was only the first day!
The tournament is three days long!
That doesn't change the need to celebrate!
Let's drink! Go Tonbo!
You didn't let me talk at all!
Because you took too long with your
babbling nonsense!
Hey.
You could at least
turn the microphone off.
Right! Of course, Yoko!
Tonbo is in first,
and Tsubura is in third.
Leaving the island and
competing against so many people...
I wonder how it feels for Tonbo?
Don't worry!
Tonbo's doing just fine, I'm sure.
That's right.
I'm sure she's hard at work
practicing for tomorrow.
Do you think it will dry by tomorrow?
Those are the only clothes
she has for the tournament.
What do you mean?
If they don't dry in time
I'll lend her mine!
Tonbo!
Which one do you like?
Leave the poor girl alone.
Seriously.
What'd you say?
Ema Kurisu.
Ema?
Now I remember!
What is it?
Ema Kurisu!
I knew I'd heard of her before.
Is she famous?
She's an incredibly talented title holder.
Has it already been ten years?
There's a girl who's been winning
world tournaments since she was twelve.
A Japanese-American girl.
I think her name was Ema Kurisu.
A world junior champion?
However, after that,
her name stopped coming up.
What has she been doing
for the last decade?
It sure is crowded.
There's a spot.
A shark bite?
I've seen a shark bite wound
on the island before.
Hers looks the same.
She's left-handed?
I had heard about her championships,
but never that she was a lefty.
But the wedge she was just using
was a right-handed club.
Wait, what?
Her 58 and putter are right handed,
but everything else is left handed?
What is that stance?
She's putting her weight
on her right foot.
That's called a one-axis swing.
Even so, that's an interesting way
to apply her weight.
Thank goodness!
Will my daughter ever be
able to play golf again?
Golf?
I'm still not positive
she'll ever walk again.
We have to start there first.
I can't hit it as far as I used to.
My left leg...
Dad.
I want to use lefty clubs.
If I use these
maybe I can play again.
Why are your 58 and putter right-handed?
I want to play the way I always have.
With small techniques, there shouldn't be
too much stress on my left ankle.
When I use bigger clubs
my left ankle can't hold the weight.
"No weight shifting is
required during back swing."
If I do this I'll be able to swing
without putting weight on my left leg!
More. More.
I've got to put more effort in.
Maybe then I can finally compete again.
It took ten long years,
but I'm finally competing again.
My efforts paid off.
You've played this course
hundreds of times!
more than anyone else here.
Hitting under par should be no issue.
I don't want you to get a stroke over 69.
You're getting first place today. Got it?
My father will never be satisfied.
Are you listening, Hinoki?
I'm not Hinoki.
Golf would be easy if you
could improve by being scolded.
You can't control your score.
If you don't understand that, you don't
have the right to be scolding others.
I don't like your attitude!
Tonbo!
Ouch.
She reminds me of how
I used to enjoy playing golf.
Tsubura!
I'll hit with you.
She doesn't have the attitude of
someone about to compete in a tournament.
Tonbo.
When we played golf
on the island it was for fun,
but this is different.
I want to make my dreams come true.
I'm going to win and get into the Japan
Women's Amateur Open.
The Japan Women's Amateur?
I'll win the Amateur Open,
and prove my true talent.
The Japan Junior and Japan Amateur Open.
With those two big titles,
I'll be able to make it to the pros.
After that, I'll enter a pro tournament
and win.
I'll win a pro tournament
while I'm still an amateur,
and join the pros myself.
What about you, Tonbo?
Me?
What kind of future do you want in golf?
Well, for me,
I left the island because
I wanted to learn more about golf.
But I didn't think I could do it.
You didn't?
You and all the other girls
have goals and dreams.
You are all aiming
to be the best golfers you can be.
I thought that without having goals or
dreams like you do,
maybe I shouldn't
be playing golf at all.
I thought maybe I wasn't serious enough.
But you know?
Yesterday I got to play
with a woman named Ms. Shima.
She made me realize I was wrong.
The club!
It's okay to play golf
just because you like it.
It's okay to push yourself to get better.
Just having the idea alone is
enough reason to put your all into golf.
Tonbo has evolved significantly since she
got here, in both technique and spirit.
Excuse me.
Thanks for talking to my father.
This is Hinoki Otoha. She's a grade above
me in high school.
I know who she is. She was last year's
Kyushu Junior Champion.
I'm not myself.
Every morning I try to be myself,
but I can never quite do it.
My father scolds me to be myself.
I've heard of that.
Your motto, right? Doing your best
so that tomorrow you'll be your true self.
It means you'll do better tomorrow, right?
Well...
I don't think that's right.
You don't?
"I'll be myself tomorrow."
You say that, thinking you'll do better.
But that means you'll never do your best.
You'll be saying that motto forever.
It's like people who say
"if I had only tried my best."
They say that forever
and never actually try.
They blame their inability on others.
Tsubura...
Only you can be responsible for becoming
who you want to be.
It's still early, but why
don't we get ready to start?
I've got to be my
true self starting today!
Will the 9:46 group please
report to the tee?
Once again, my name is Hata and
I'll be your caddy today.
I look forward to playing with you.
Thank you.
The Kyushu Junior Champion.
The Japan Junior Champion.
And the World Junior Champion.
A high-skilled group
fitting for today's order!
And among the greats, there's Tonbo.
Without any titles to her name,
there's no telling
how far her ability goes.
What are you looking at?
I can see a kobu spinning a web.
There won't be any wind today,
just like yesterday.
Kobu?
That's what we call spiders back on the
island.
They only spin webs on days
when the wind isn't too strong.
That's what Gon always says.
Gon?
Is that some kind of bug, too?
That's my grandpa!
He's not a bug!
No wind today, either.
The tee is higher than usual.
Her grip is higher than usual, too.
Her stance is wider, too.
Her distance from the ball, longer.
Her backswing is bigger.
She hit it as far as Tonbo did yesterday.
She's added a bit more to everything.
She usually hits the ball far
but I've never seen Hinoki swing
like that first thing in the morning.
Maybe I got through to her.
My third shot will be from the left side
of the fairway.
I want to hit my second shot from the
right side.
That means I'll
have to tee up from the left.
A tee shot like that will have
the other players running scared!
Please remain quiet.
I have 420 yards to the third shot.
I'll have to get there in two.
There's no need to be scared.
What kind of weak swing is that?
That's what you call a good shot.
Wow! I haven't seen
you do that in a while!
What was it called again?
Igaiga told me once.
That's it! The Great One Pattern!
Good position.
She is the World Junior Champion,
after all.
She gets it.
A one-axis swing
is characterized by aiming
the sternum away from the ball.
What a bounce!
Good shot.
Thanks.
The tee won't go in easily.
Is it from all the sunshine recently?
She raised the tee.
She's going for a big shot.
A hand-first stance with a driver?
Setting the ball in the middle?
That will loft it like a vertical wall.
She's going to use the
top half of the club face?
She dropped her stance!
Third one from the right!
Go! Sunshine Shot!
How does she make it roll like that?
The third line from the right.
The mowing lines of the fairway.
Mowing lines?
According to an old pro,
on a long hole, you should
aim for a bright spot on the fairway.
It's an old technique.
By a bright spot,
he meant areas of the fairway
that appear brighter in color.
These are the mowing lines.
Alright!
She's lined up with Ema Kurisu's ball!
I didn't think a low shot like that
would travel that far!
Amazing!
Tonbo took into account
the ground being dry and hard
and hit a shot she knew would roll far.
How was she able to calculate that?
I was actually aiming for the fifth one!
Igaiga! Everyone!
Today's a new day!
Tonbo.
I can't give you advice
like Mr. Igarashi does.
Thank you!
It's okay, Hajime!
You have something that Igaiga doesn't.
I do? Really?
On the next episode of Tonbo!
Jack-in-the-box Golf
Tonbo! What is it that I have?
Your face isn't scary!
Oh, come on!