Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Bro?
I'm gonna hook a big one!
Hey! What's wrong?!
Why that getup?
Like a Fish and Water
Why fishing?
It's because, uh...
I felt like fishing today?
Say, Bro.
Um...
Watch me!
I'm gonna land a whopper!
What's wrong?
Nothing's biting.
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
So, how'd it go?
Zilch. Today was the worst.
He already said he caught nothing.
Not what I meant!
Grr, I need food, food!
Wanna come, Megumi?
I...
...don't feel like eating.
Do you dislike the taste?
No. I'll have some.
It was back when Takami
had been chosen as the family heir.
He'd begun to spend
a lot more time apart from me,
and we'd been talking less.
While I didn't feel like I was lonely,
it was as if Takami had suddenly gone far away.
One such day...
Yes! I withstood it!
I'm gonna win again today, Takami!
Are you sure about that?
It's that guy again...
Persona Ride!
R-Really?!
Yes, really.
I attack!
Damage check!
I lost!
All right! I beat Danji!
Dang it!
He and Takami were always together...
at least, that was my initial impression.
Takami had never shown a face like that to me.
Young miss, your teacher is here.
I'm coming.
Young miss?
R-Right!
For a time, Bro didn't visit at all,
because Takami had grown busy.
And I spent my days just going
between home and school.
I'd realized that was
the sort of family we were,
and thought that I myself needed
to become a person suitable for that.
It was the deck my brother had stopped using...
I thought that those days
would never again return.
Just then...
I'm finished!
Yeah, it's nicely done.
You're that guy...
It was my reunion with Bro.
Later, I found out he'd come to trim the tree
in the garden, at my brother's request.
Thank you for your hard work.
Master Takami left a short while ago.
That's too bad.
It's been a while since we had a fight.
We'll be counting on you tomorrow.
Sure! If you'll excuse me...
I felt like calling out to him.
But I held back.
I mean, what would we even talk about?
It wasn't like he knew me at all.
Stop the car here.
If I let this chance slip away,
we may never meet again...
Those were my thoughts as I got out of the car.
Wonder Hill
It was the amusement park
I'd often visited when I was little.
After having not seen it in so long,
I was surprised at how rundown it was.
What does he do here?
Whoa!
People?
Cardfighting...
The winner: Danji Momoyama!
Who's there?!
Who's that?
You know her?
Oh! Aren't you... Megumi?
Look out!
Hey!
You all right?! Hey!
Um, uh...
Wait, what, hey...!
My bad!
I'm sorry!
Hey!
You know her?
Yeah... somewhat.
What'll you do about that?
Good question...
I reacted by running away.
I hadn't even thanked him.
Afterwards, fretting over his sunglasses,
I went and got a new pair for him.
But, when and how would I give them to him?
And I couldn't be sure if he'd even accept them.
"What am I doing?" I wondered to myself.
Megumi!
Oh, you're here! Come out a moment!
Um, I'm...
Sorry!
I broke your hair ornament!
I don't know if this will do, but...
You got one for me?
Figures that I'd get the style wrong...
That's not why.
Here.
Are these...?
I also felt bad about breaking your sunglasses.
Well?
This calls for an exchange.
Sure!
It's a busy time of year right now,
always warming up then cooling down.
Um...
This is...
You play Vanguard?!
No, this is...
Why didn't you say so?!
You're welcome any time you want a fight!
What's wrong?
I can't cardfight.
I've never had one before.
You've never had one?
Then how would you know you can't?
All right!
Come with me!
It's sure chilly once the sun goes down.
You all right?
Yes!
The wind against my cheeks felt refreshing.
Hold on tight!
Our team is Blackout.
Black...out?
Hey, everybody! This is Megumi!
She's my friend. Tell her hello.
It's nice to meet you again, Megumi.
Nice to meet you.
Hi there!
Nice to meet you!
Great to meet you!
Heya!
Wh-What's happened to you?!
I wanted to change my mood.
How do I look?
Looking good!
We're witnessing the birth of a new Megumi!
Happy birthday to--
He burst out singing!
That's what you do for a birth, right?
Are you kidding us?!
Hey, it's her birthday!
What else would I do?!
Thanks to them,
I felt like I had been reborn.
First period today features
a special lesson on traffic safety!
Special Lesson: Traffic Safety
First period today features
a special lesson on traffic safety!
A police officer is here to speak to you all,
Special Lesson: Traffic Safety
so please listen closely.
A police officer?
Well, come in!
Good morning, everyone.
I am Tomari Seto, from the Traffic Division.
Tomari?!
Yes, you there! If you would sit down, please!
R-Right!
Let's begin!
In order to avoid traffic accidents, you need:
safety confirmation,
and hazard anticipation!
You look both ways before crossing the street.
That is safety confirmation.
And for hazard anticipation,
you think about how a car or pedestrian
could suddenly come around a blind corner.
Considering possible incidents in advance
allows you to deal with them promptly.
"Hazard anticipation," huh...
However, there are times when
overthinking is what leads to danger.
Specifically, when it involves the guy you like!
Huh?
Um, Ms. Seto...
What'll I do if he comes around that corner?
Will he see me looking weird?
How's my hair? My makeup? Is my face puffy?
And while you're doing that:
Ka-pow!
You realize he's all you can think about!
What is this feeling? What should I do?
And you can't stop!
The brakes! Just! Won't! Work!
Screech!
Ms. Seto, could I have a word with you?
Why?! We were just starting to have fun!
Class, treat the rest of
first period as study hall!
Who was that person?
A comedian?
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
What was that about?!
Oh, wasn't it helpful?
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Hardly!
What's your problem?
Here I went out of my way
to give you a special lesson!
Special lesson?! For what purpose?!
Ah, so you wish to know?
What?
Then I'll tell you.
It's because you've been all gloomy, Meg.
Huh?!
This is a place for you
to forget your cares and have fun!
Yet you've been hanging around
with that sour look and acting gloomy!
I am not gloomy!
Are too!
Right, Yu-yu?
Zakusa, what do you think?
I'd like to attend her special lesson...
Besides, it's not something
for me to learn from you, Tomari.
You don't understand a thing about me.
Aww! Zakusa, Meg's being mean to me!
I'll console you, if it helps.
Goodness, is that a promise?
Grrr...
Shall I make tea?
Heya, you guys arguing?
Bro, would you shut up?!
That's true.
Here, the rule is for disputes
to be settled by cardfights.
Then, shall we?
Come and get me, Little Miss Gloomy!
I told you, I'm not gloomy!
What's wrong?
Uh, nothing.
Megumi and Tomari are having a Cardfight!
Who's your favorite?
Just what are they doing?
Tomari!
It's my first fight in ages! I'm getting chills!
You'll handle commentary in my place, 'kay?
I definitely won't lose.
Are you ready?
Bring it on!
Stand up, Vanguard!
O-Okay, Megumi and Tomari's cardfight begins!
I haven't personally seen these two
battle before, either!
Just what sort of fight
is about to unfold before us?!
I ride Kyanite Blue!
Its skill activates!
I add Galaxy Control Prison,
Galactolus to my hand,
and then put it into the Order Zone!
I'm gonna show you how an adult fights.
An "adult," huh?
Someone who's an adult on the outside,
but a child inside, is the nastiest of all.
That's right, even after becoming
an adult, they're still a child--
Wait, who's this about?!
You really need to ask?
Megumi calls unit after unit!
Then she attacks!
It's another intense assault from her today!
You're fighting like you always do.
With the plays you always use.
Aww, it's so boring.
What about it?!
I told you! Nothing's gonna change!
Not when you won't take
your big sister's advice, girl.
Time for a spanking.
I ride Risatt Pink!
Its skill activates!
I imprison one of my opponent's cards!
Th-There it is!
It's Tomari's Police Prison Combo!
Locking an opponent's card in prison
makes it unavailable to use!
Furthermore!
With Agra Luge's skill, I imprison Agleo!
With Chevalstud's skill, I imprison Dooger!
She's arresting the units on the board, too!
Unless Megumi pays the cost,
she won't be able to release
her imprisoned units!
Welcome to your cold jail cell.
Is it to your liking, young miss?
As always, you fight dirty.
This is an adult fight.
Could you not misrepresent
an old lady's pigheadedness as "adult"?
Beg pardon? I couldn't quite hear you, there!
Oh, are you losing your hearing, granny?
Ka-clang!
Aren't you afraid of drawing
the wrath of a police officer, Meg?
Oh, yeah, I'm so scared.
Say what?! I'm gonna kick your butt, girl!
I can't stand to hear any more of this!
Somebody please take over the commentary for me!
My turn!
I ride Magnolia!
Soul Blast!
Now, release Dooger to me!
Megumi pays the cost to free her friend!
I won't stand for being locked up.
Looks to me that you're bound up
by something else, though.
What do you mean?
You've been hesitant and gloomy for a while now.
What's got you so unhappy?
What? Nothing, really.
Are you unhappy about the kid who's barely joined
and yet steadily gaining in importance?
Or about the man who won't look your way,
no matter how much time passes?
Or about yourself,
for being troubled by such things?
That's not...
You'd best confess to everything, lovelorn maiden.
Pardon?
I ride Seraph Snow!
Further, I call two Agra Luge
and a Kyanite Blue!
This is bad.
Its skill activates!
Go to jail!
I'm disciplining this girl
who can't be honest with herself!
While I'm at it, I'll also teach you
how to behave toward your superiors.
Megumi's in trouble!
Everything besides her Vanguard
has been put into prison!
Seraph Snow attacks your Vanguard!
No guard!
Didn't you know?
The more units I have imprisoned,
the stronger my deck gets.
Triple drive!
Seraph Snow's powered-up ability
gives it a triple drive!
And as a result...
Double critical!
A double?!
Now she has two critical triggers!
Tomari is one attractive woman!
Well, that's because
I'm always on my best behavior.
Meanwhile, Megumi hasn't drawn
even one trigger, and has 5 damage!
With one card in hand,
and her Vanguard all alone on the board,
She's light on the red--
er, right on the ledge!
It's as you said, Tomari.
I wasn't honest with myself.
Oh, finally?
However... you had me all wrong!
None of those were the reason why!
No way... that card!
Persona Ride!
You had it all along?!
Don't you often say,
"Trouble can be opportunity"?
Counterblast.
Now, return to me!
Paying the cost, she releases
card after card from prison.
It's a tactic only made possible
by taking all those attacks!
My prison...
...has...
...been breached!
I'm back.
And on top of everything,
by Persona Riding on Magnolia,
all her units in the back row
gain the ability to attack!
In short, it's a surging wave
of six attacks in a row!
Not bad.
Same to you.
Now, take this!
Gonna struggle like an adult to the very end?
Suddenly I'm starving!
Me, too!
Wanna go?
Let's!
And they're gone.
Weren't those two arguing just a moment ago?
Yes. It's like nothing's been resolved.
Friendship born from
a serious exchange of blows!
Now that's manly!
Huh? But--
What a great fight!
Uh oh.
Danji, did you pay the electric bill?
Sorry.
Danji didn't pay the bill.
Well, it's fine.
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Now, get on!
It's my treat today!
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
Sure!
No telling my butler, okay?
Wonder Hill: Land of Dreams
All right!
Thank you, Tomari.
I can manage this much, even on my salary.
That's not what I meant.
I'm just glad I met all of you.
Meg...
Hachiban Ramen
Go on, eat up!
Sure!
But, if you eat at this hour,
you'll need to diet.
I'll be fine! I'm still young!
Wait, what's that supposed to mean?
I wound up stuffing myself...
Look over there!
Whatever you're fretting about or wanting to do,
you still get hungry, and morning still comes.
Yeah.
Megumi! Tomari!
Bro?! And everyone else?!
Happy birthday to you!
Yay!
You remembered!
Of course I did!
Warming of water hails the coming of spring...
A year does pass quickly.
Actually, I'd planned to catch
a great big fish to celebrate, though.
Well, it's all good!
Today will be my treat, too!
Eat as much as you like!
Yeah!
Tomari, let's have another bowl!
What, you can still eat?!
Let's have heart-warming karamen noodles.
And hang on, pay the electric bill first, Danji!
Okay, fine!
Yu-yu, hurry up and join us!
Yeah!
Check Out My Card!
Hey, listen!
A Piece of Soul
It's feeding time, all you card-loving
and card-possessed spirits out there!
A Piece of Soul
This time, I'm introducing my card,
Aurora Battle Princess, Seraph Snow!
A Piece of Soul
With one Counterblast, Seraph Snow can send
two opposing units directly to a cold jail cell!
You get to pop 'em in the slammer!
Furthermore, if you have at least three cards
in custody, it gets an extra drive!
Excellent! Fantastic! Woo!
To Be Continued
Next Episode
Overnight Statue